3

First Mission

Hinata was the first to arrive at training area nineteen. She'd left home earlier than strictly necessary, but she was happy to be out of the Hyuuga compound. She was slightly ashamed that she felt happier away from her ancestral home. She knew that her father would see that as a demeaning lack of pride in her heritage.

Shino arrived a few minutes later. The Aburame boy was quiet, merely nodding to her when she greeted him. At first Hinata wondered if he was angry with her for disagreeing with him at lunch yesterday. But as she watched him examine the base of one of the trees, she remembered how quiet he had been at the academy. Perhaps he just didn't have anything to say.

Kurenai arrived with another boy, and it took a moment for Hinata to recognize Naruto without the orange jumpsuit that had been his trademark over the last couple of years. He was frowning; making Hinata wondered what was wrong. Naruto was always smiling and joking, and for him to appear so grim…

As they approached, Kurenai-sensei put her hand on his shoulder and said something too quiet to hear. Naruto nodded and shook himself, like a dog with wet fur, and then he straightened up and let out a sigh. Naruto grinned at everyone and she felt her face begin to flush again.

"I'm glad to see you all got here early," Kurenai called out as they walked up. "Punctuality is important for what we do… or rather, being too late can be fatal."

Hinata felt her stomach tighten at the jonin's grim words, but tried not to let her fear show. Father would be mortified that any Hyuuga, let alone his own daughter, would show fear before others. Not that Hinata had done that well at abiding by her father's wishes.

Shino didn't visibly react to their sensei's words. Instead, he just continued to look at her through his ever-present dark glasses. Hinata envied his reserve.

Hinata did not know quite what to make of Naruto's new uniform. It was certainly more practical, but his orange jumpsuit had become such a part of him that it seemed strange to see him without it. The quiet way he approached with Kurenai-sensei was also at odds with his normal behavior. All of this made Hinata concerned for her teammate. She liked the Naruto that always smiled and tried again, and she didn't want to see that change.

As she became more upset, a sudden thought gave her pause. She liked the loud, brassy Naruto, but did he necessarily like it himself? He'd looked so dejected after the Genin exam, and her mind wandered back to other times that he'd been down. Were those truly the only times he'd been upset – or were they the only times he let it show?

Reading people was a high art among the Hyuugas, ever since one of her clan leader ancestors took his Byakugan to a new level. Hinaro-san was the first to read a person's intentions from the tension in their bodies and the way they moved. His eyes were said to be sufficiently acute as to detect variations in a shinobi's pulse rate by observing the vibrations in the skin over their carotid arteries. There is even a rumor that fear of this formidable skill was what led the Hatake family to begin wearing their traditional masks.

As with most of her family's arts, Hinata was not very adept with body reading. She could see the disappointment and resentment that festered in the eyes of the clan elders, but they didn't bother to conceal their feelings. Her cousin Neji, on the other hand, was said to be able to see things that the adults wished to keep unnoticed. From most people, Hinata could merely guess at their mental state.

However, she had also spent a long time studying Naruto. She was no expert on his mercurial moods, but as she watched him approach, she didn't get a sense of sadness or anger from him. He was just… reserved, in an odd way.

At the same time, he also seemed very focused. When Kurenai-sensei spoke, Naruto took in every word. Not even Iruka-sensei at his most outraged could command so much of Naruto's attention. Hinata found herself respecting the jonin even more now, though she wondered what she had said or done to Naruto to earn such respect.

Her curiosity became even stronger when the woman reached into the pouch at her waist and removed a pair of scrolls. She handed one to Shino and the other to Hinata. "These are some exercises I'd like you to perform on your own, outside of our team meetings. They are mostly speed and endurance-building exercises, though there are also activities that should build up your chakra capacity and control."

Hinata carefully placed the scroll in her weapons pouch. "Ano, sensei, uh… what will we be doing during team meetings?" Despite Kurenai-sensei's kindly demeanor, Hinata still found it embarrassingly difficult to speak out or ask questions.

"That's a good question, Hinata," Kurenai replied evenly. "I'd like this time to be spent working on things that would benefit from us all being together. For the speed and endurance training, I will leave it to each of you to make sure you are pushing yourselves as hard as you can. It won't just be you paying the penalty if you don't. But a team also needs to learn how to fight together. Sparring will let you test and improve your skills against one another, and it will also let you come to understand each others' fighting styles."

Kurenai smiled, perhaps a little grimly. "That knowledge will prove very useful when you fight together as a team. You will know how your teammates will react and be able to move with them smoothly to counter any threats. A well-trained shinobi team can move together like a well-oiled machine, and becomes much more effective than just the sum of its members. We call this extra bonus 'synergy'."

Hinata nodded slowly. She vaguely remembered something about that concept from lessons at the academy last year. Naruto frowned thoughtfully but didn't say anything.

With that, Kurenai put them to work. "We'll start with just taijutsu today. No other techniques for right now. Just hand to hand. Hinata, why don't you and Naruto start? Light contact only."

Hinata was a little nervous about sparring with Naruto first thing, but tried to control her reactions. Sensei was right, she needed to know her teammates as well as she knew herself.

Naruto moved a little stiffly at first, perhaps because of his new clothes. Hinata activated her Byakugan so she could see his Tenketsu points, but she didn't push any chakra out of her palms as she struck. This way she could tell if she struck true, which wasn't as often as she liked, but didn't disable her teammate.

Naruto jolted back on his heels when her palm slipped around his block and struck him flat on the chest. He smiled ruefully at her and shook his head. Her stomach gave an odd wobble as he dropped back into a ready stance. Naruto didn't seem to be upset that she'd scored on him. In fact, his look was almost… approving.

That thought made her falter and she almost missed a block. Naruto, of course, was pulling his punches at the last instant; neither of them was out to hurt the other. Nonetheless, his knuckles still jarred her shoulder.

Mortified at her slip, Hinata grabbed his sleeve, wrapping her fingers around his arm just above the wrist. She brought her other hand in low, aiming for the Tenketsu point right above the hara, between the navel and diaphragm.

Naruto twisted backwards to avoid the blow, but her hold on his arm limited his motion. Naruto purposefully fell backwards. Hinata let go of his arm so she could chamber a kick, but then realized that he had a handful of her jacket clenched in his fist now.

Her unpredictable teammate rolled onto his back, pulling his knees up to his chest, and Hinata was yanked forward off her feet. He let go of her shoulder as her stomach came to rest on his sandals. Hinata barely saw the pleased grin on his face before she was launched into the air.

Hinata found herself upside down, flying backwards through the air. She curled up to speed her rotation, and managed to get her feet under her before she landed, her back to Naruto.

"Good recoveries, both of you," Kurenai said, and with the Byakugan still active, Hinata could see her smiling without having to turn her head. She was embarrassed at her slip, and could see her father's disapproving glare in her mind, but no one here seemed to notice or care.

Nonetheless, Naruto seemed a bit more focused when they resumed their match. His attacks sped up and became more fluid, and Hinata had to fully focus her concentration to block him. Every time she blocked one of his punches or kicks, his grin became a little wider, and Hinata found herself smiling a little as well. He really should have participated in the after class sparring, she mused as she ducked under a looping roundhouse kick. She swept his supporting leg, but Naruto twisted sideways with the motion and landed in a hand stand. His waist twisted and the foot she'd swept came arcing towards her face. She leaned back to avoid it, and as it passed she struck the back of his calf with the heel of her hand.

This sent Naruto's lower body off-balance to the left. He should have fallen to the ground, but he'd anticipated this and flexed his elbows, throwing his upper body into the air even as his legs rotated to the ground. He ended up on his feet in a comically wide stance, but the rotation brought his upper half in close to Hinata and his left hand came up inside her guard. She tried to flinch back from the fist rising toward her jaw, but it was too late. She closed her eyes and felt her head jolt.

Instead of the expected pain of impact, her chin felt very warm. She opened her eyes, realizing that she'd dropped her Byakugan in her surprise. Naruto's hand was wrapped around the point of her chin, his fingers warm on her cheeks.

"Gotcha!" he said, chuckling happily. He withdrew his hand as she blinked at him. "I was moving too fast to be sure, so I opened my hand." He frowned. "It didn't hurt, did it?"

Hinata shook her head, not trusting her voice. She knew she was blushing, but also realized that her whole face was red from exertion, so it hopefully did not show. In fact, she was dripping with sweat and it was becoming difficult to keep her arms from trembling. Naruto's face was a little flushed, but that was it. She was a little disturbed that he wasn't even breathing very hard.

"Very good, both of you," Kurenai-sensei called out. "Adaptation, Improvisation. But your weaknesses are not your techniques. Experience will only improve you both."

Kurenai sparred with Shino next, to give them a breather. Predictably, her Sensei was noticeably faster and stronger than Shino. Hinata's attention, however, was focused more on the blond sitting on the grass next to her. He didn't even look like he'd been exercising now, and she wondered if he'd just been playing with her while they were sparring. I should have known I wasn't really that good, she mused reproachfully as she pressed her forefingers together.

She was jolted out of her thoughts by Naruto's elbow. "All those palm strikes were times you would have used chakra to shut me down?" he asked her.

Hinata nodded silently. Aside from Kurenai explaining the reasons why they trained together, it wasn't that like Jyuuken was that big a secret. Her family's famous techniques were described, in a general fashion, during the History lectures at the Konoha Ninja Academy.

Naruto rubbed at the back of his head. "Then I guess I got you twice and you would have demolished me at least a dozen. That's pretty good!"

Hinata turned and stared at the boy, but he didn't seem to be mocking her.

Kurenai smiled as she put Shino through the wringer. The boy was a little larger and physically stronger than his teammates, and for the most part he hadn't been challenged that much the day before. She had a feeling that the boy was actually a bit more talented than he let on. As reserved as the boy's father had been, she realized that she shouldn't be surprised that his son would treat the academy like an infiltration assignment.

In the back of her mind, Kurenai again wondered at how clueless the academy examiners seemed to be. If we are teaching children to be shinobi, she mused, then why should we expect straightforward tests of their abilities to be accurate? Some students would excel at those of course. The Uchiha boy, Sasuke, seemed to have something to prove, so he would of course push himself to become the top of his class.

But those might prove to be the exceptions.

She'd stayed after the meeting where the Genin were assigned and grilled Iruka for everything he could tell her about his charges. The chuunin was a little disconcerted by her attention, but gratified that she was actually interested in his observations, as well as the examination grades. In those, Shino was said to be merely average at taijutsu. He was more than capable of defeating someone without training, but was barely above the bottom third of his class at the academy.

But now, placed on the spot against a superior opponent, the boy was executing blocks and counters at a level of proficiency approaching that of a chuunin. "You've been holding out on us," she accused as she drove a spear-hand strike at his mid-section. He silently blocked with the edge of his wrist and sent a back-fist strike against her temple. Kurenai stepped into it and blocked with her forearm. She brought up an unnoticed knee and tapped Shino in the stomach.

He nodded, acknowledging her point, and stepped back into a ready stance again.

She sent a kick at his midsection, but when he went to block, she pulled her foot back, re-chambered the kick, and launched it again at his head. He ducked his head, but her heel clipped his shoulder on the way down. Shino drove two fingers into the hollow of her knee and she barely managed to pull her leg back before his nerve strike numbed it.

"You didn't learn that at the academy," she observed as he deflected a ridge-hand strike she aimed at his floating ribs. "Extra training with your family?" she asked as she blocked his counterstrike at her stomach.

Shino pushed back against her block and his feet slipped backwards a few inches on the grass. That evidently was his aim as that motion gave him enough room to bring his foot up and kick. She caught his ankle between her palms and gave his leg a sharp twist. He leapt upward and retracted his leg, pulling himself closer for a knife-hand strike at her face. The move was unexpected and well-timed, and she barely pulled her head back in time to avoid it. As it was, his fingertips ghosted across the skin of her forehead. She used her grip on his ankle to throw him back and he somersaulted backwards once before rolling onto his feet and rising into a low crouch.

"Very good, Shino," Kurenai said approvingly. "But if you wish to remain on this team, you will not hold back during our training sessions. I can understand your caution within the academy, but there should be no secrets between teammates." She saw Naruto give a guilty start out of the corner of her eye and knew he'd gotten the message as well.

Shino merely nodded at this, which she accepted with good grace. She'd get him talking. Eventually… Maybe.

After that, Naruto sparred with Shino, and had a noticeably harder time landing a hit than he did the day before. Kurenai also took the opportunity to work with Hinata on her blocking techniques. Kobaru-sensei had done the same for her, many years ago. There were ways to angle the arms and legs that increased one's leverage. These modified blocks were not taught at the Konoha Ninja Academy because they required superior speed and timing to execute properly. For an agile kunoichi who possessed less upper-body strength than her male counterparts, however, they were ideal.

Hinata took to the techniques avidly, and Kurenai could tell she was flattered to be getting any individual instruction at all. If she didn't already despise Hiashi, the Hyuuga girl's reactions would drive her to do so. When she explained why she was showing the girl the alternate techniques, Hinata just nodded thoughtfully. Kurenai was embarrassed to remember how she had given Kobaru a very hard time about his insinuation that she was weaker than Mattai or Nomaru.

After about half an hour of this, switching off sparring partners every few minutes, Kurenai found all of her genin to be somewhat worse for the wear. Naruto's new uniform was covered with dust and bits of grass from all the times he'd been knocked down. At the same time, he was also smiling broadly as he helped Hinata, who'd slipped to one knee after successfully blocking his last kick. The Hyuuga girl was red-faced and barely able to stand, and Shino's chest moved rapidly enough to inform his teacher that he was breathing hard.

"All right, that's a good start. We can walk to cool down and let our muscles relax. I can tell we definitely need to work on endurance training. Make sure you follow the exercises I gave you, and ask me if anything is unclear." With that, she led them out of the training area and through the outskirts of the village.

The villagers they passed had very different reactions to the genin placed in her charge. Hinata's eyes and unadorned forehead marked her as a member of one of Konoha's oldest and most powerful families. People who didn't know her gave her at least a respectful nod, and she returned those she noticed.

Shino's clothing and glasses marked him as an Aburame, and most people gave him a wide berth. A few glanced downward at their arms and legs, as if to make sure a bug hadn't crawled up onto them. Kurenai did have to wonder how commonplace it was for a member of Shino's clan to 'tag' the people around them with the scent-producing female kikai bugs. The one she'd worked with explained that it helped him differentiate his teammates to the 'allies' he'd stationed on guard duty. It also proved useful when a member of their team had been ambushed and wounded, and they needed to find him quickly. Of course, that didn't mean she was comfortable with the idea of someone ordering a bug to crawl onto her body and hide itself. She'd probably need to talk to Shino about that the next time she could speak to him alone.

While Shino seemed either uninterested or unperturbed by the villagers' reactions, the same could not be said of Naruto. Maybe it was his acceptance by Iruka; maybe it was her own agreement that his treatment was unjustified. In any event, as Naruto received his normal allotment of angry glares and muttered oaths, he began to glare back. Soon he was walking with his hands fisted at his sides, on legs stiff with anger and resentment.

Privately, Kurenai wondered if this wasn't a healthier attitude for him than his previous denial. At the same time, it wouldn't do for him to get into an altercation with random villagers. She resolved to let him work through his feelings on his own, but keep a close eye on him and offer advice if asked.

By the time they'd arrived at the Hokage's tower, everyone appeared to have recovered from the sparring. She led them up the stairs to the top floor, and told the chuunin on duty that they were "Team 8 reporting for assignment". At her words, she noticed Naruto straighten his posture with pride, and even Hinata stopped looking downward for a moment.

The Sandaime looked pleased to see them, and his eyes seemed to linger on Naruto's new clothes. His eyes then met hers, and she couldn't suppress a mild blush at the approval she saw in them.

"You're just in time, jonin Kurenai," the Hokage said. "We still have a few D-rank missions left." Kurenai inclined her head respectfully as the old man shuffled through a stack of papers on his desk. "There we are," he said, pulling one out. "I need you to report to Herbalist Yukitaza in the western district, near the river. He suffered a broken leg last week while working on his roof and needs some help."

Kurenai led her students down to the exit, trying not to laugh at the confusion on Naruto's face, and echoed somewhat on Hinata's. "As a new genin team," she began before they even had a chance to ask her, "you will be assigned D-rank missions until you have completed a good number of them." She specifically avoided saying how many, because she wanted to have the option of delaying their first C-rank mission until she was sure they were ready.

"D-rank missions," she continued, "are judged to be little or no threat, and should rarely, if ever, involve travel beyond the outer walls of Konoha. They are tasks that still need doing, will give you all an opportunity to practice working together, and will supply you with a little pocket money when you are done."

She paused on a street corner while they digested this. Naruto still looked a little rebellious, but resigned to his fate. She stepped up the pace a little as they made their way to the western quarter of the village. When she rang the bell at the door of the house described in the mission briefing, a voice called out for them to come around to the rear deck.

Herbalist Yukitaza proved to be a middle-aged unmarried man with a large cast on his left leg. He made a short double-take when he recognized Naruto, but didn't react in any other way.

Soon, Kurenai and Shino were working on the roof repairs, the Aburame boy having reluctantly mentioned helping his father perform a similar task last winter. Hinata and Naruto were put to work weeding the client's large garden plot, a task better suited to their smaller statures.

They'd been working for a few minutes when Kurenai was startled to realize that it was Naruto carrying the next load of wood up the ladder. She looked over at Shino, who just shrugged.

"Naruto," she said puzzled, "I thought you were going to help Hinata with the garden?"

Naruto grunted and laid the boards down on the shallow pitched roof. "There wasn't enough room," he said.

Kurenai frowned and looked out over the back yard. Hinata was working on the garden plot, along with about twenty Narutos.

Kurenai turned back to Naruto. "They can all work independently?" she asked. Bunshin were usually only capable of limited thought, following simple and straightforward commands.

Naruto shrugged. "Why shouldn't they?" he asked.

Kurenai wasn't quite sure how to answer that question. Naruto shook his head and turned to go back down the ladder. Unfortunately, he evidently forgot about the stack of boards he'd just put down, because he tripped over them and tumbled off the roof.

Kurenai lunged forward, hoping to catch the boy, but it was too late. She reached the edge of the roof just as Naruto hit the ground… and disappeared in a puff of smoke. She stopped, staring at the vapors that rapidly dissipated. I was talking to one of his Bunshin and didn't even realize it, she mused. What the hell is that boy? She looked out at the garden, where Hinata had just grabbed Naruto's arm to prevent him from pulling up a plant that wasn't a weed. He scratched at the back of his head, embarrassed, not even noticing how Hinata pulled her hands back from his arm like they were burned. Nor did he notice her blush, for all that it was brighter than his own. He's Uzumaki Naruto, Kurenai reminded herself ruefully, and he breaks the rules without even realizing it.

Naruto and Hinata finished the garden in less than twenty minutes, with a clone starting at both ends of each row and Hinata using her Byakugan to supervise. With her ability to look in all directions at once, she could see if he missed anything or was about to pull something that wasn't a weed. The latter happened a little more often than Naruto would have liked, but Hinata didn't tease him about it. In fact, she seemed to worry that she wasn't doing her fair share of the work.

Naruto wasn't any expert on girls, or kunoichi, by any stretch of the imagination. But he suspected that most of his female classmates would have been glad of an excuse to not get their hands dirty, rather than worrying that they weren't doing enough. He tried to tell Hinata that he appreciated her attitude, but when the words came out of his mouth it sounded more like "I like how you're like a boy, instead of a girl" and she became very upset and then confused when he tried to explain.

"I mean, you're not like Sakura or Ino," he said quickly.

Hinata ducked her head down and looked even sadder. "I- I know," she said hesitantly.

"But that's a good thing," Naruto said quickly. Did she like Sakura and Ino? He wondered. I don't remember ever seeing them talk, but they are all girls – they're like some secret society.

"I-it is?" she asked. Her forefingers were pressed together so hard that the skin had turned white.

"I – I mean, they are nice and all… I'm not saying they are ugly or anything," Naruto added quickly. If they were all friends and it got back to those two that he said they were ugly, genin or not, he was a dead shinobi.

Hinata frowned, perplexed. "A-ano… I…" she swallowed. "Naruto-kun, I don't understand what you mean."

"I'm just saying… well… I'm glad you're on my team," Naruto said firmly. There. No one could interpret anything bad out of that, right?

Hinata stiffened like she'd been slapped, then quickly turned away.

Naruto's mouth dropped open. He started to step around her to ask what he'd said when she pointed at one of his clones.

"S-stop. He's about to pull a good plant," she said in a choked voice.

Naruto whirled toward the offending clone. "You heard her," he barked.

"Take it easy, baka," the clone said. "You're acting like she's your girlfriend or something."

An instant later the clone disappeared as Naruto's fist transited through the space its head once occupied. "S-sorry," he apologized. "Sometimes they get a little mouthy when they know their time is almost up."

"We a-appear to be almost done, Naruto," Hinata said in a quiet voice, still not facing him. "I will go inside and help Yukitaza-san with the kitchen."

Naruto glared at the remaining Bunshin as Hinata silently walked toward the house. All of them stayed bent over, peering carefully at the ground as they finished the weeding.

After finishing outside, Naruto went indoors to help with the cleaning. Hinata was silent as he passed through the kitchen, very intently focused on dicing up some vegetables Herbalist Yukitaza had delivered earlier that day. After locating the cleaning supplies, Naruto created another set of clones and put them to work tidying up. Fortunately, this was something he knew quite well how to do, having had to clean up his own apartment for years. He finished as Kurenai and Shino came down from the roof. Naruto sent his clones out to put away the tools and the ladders.

Hinata was still busy in the kitchen, so Naruto and Shino were sent to make some deliveries to their client's customers. Kurenai-sensei decided she would help Hinata finish. She gave Naruto a piercing look as she announced this, and he felt the back of his neck grow hot.

As he ran down the street with a small bundle of herbs, Naruto tried to figure out what he'd done wrong. It wasn't like he'd asked the stupid Bunshin to mouth off. Maybe Hinata thought it was saying something Naruto was thinking, and that was why she'd been offended. It sort of made sense in a way. Sakura always hit him soon after he'd asked her out. Naruto realized that his attempts to be friendly with her seemed to always make her angry at him. Maybe it was something about him, maybe it was some aura given off by that bastard fox. Perhaps it was a side-effect of the seal used to imprison his unwanted tenant. Maybe a seal strong enough to repel a demon would also repel any girls he came in contact with as well.

He scowled as he knocked on the door of his bundle's destination. An old woman opened it and Naruto handed her the package before she had a chance to realize who he was. "This is from Herbalist Yukitaza. He broke his leg and can't make his own deliveries today." With that, he spun and was halfway back to the street before the woman had a chance to speak.

Naruto stuffed his hands into his jacket pockets as he made his way back to the Herbalist's newly cleaned and repaired house. It was bad enough how people hated him for something that happened the day he was born, but now he was pissing off everyone else – even when he was trying to be nice.

When he returned to the house, Hinata and Kurenai had finished up in the kitchen. With the deliveries made, the last tasks for their 'mission' were completed. The Herbalist thanked them for their help, and even looked Naruto in the eye, which impressed him a little.

"Not quite an hour and a half," Kurenai said after they made their goodbyes. "That was very quick. Good use of your Bunshin, Naruto, and coordinating with Hinata to make sure there were no problems. I'm very pleased with your teamwork, both of you."

Naruto felt the knot of resentment in his middle loosen a bit. Hinata's reaction, however, caught his eye. She looked down, pushing her fingers together as her cheeks turned red. When she noticed him staring, she turned completely away. He frowned and let out a sigh. Evidently she was still mad at him or something.

As they made their way back toward the center of the village, Kurenai peered up at the afternoon sun. "At this point, I doubt the Hokage has any missions left to give out. Let's get together a little earlier tomorrow. If we work as fast as we did today, we can probably clear two missions a day. I'll see you all at the training ground at ten, all right?"

Everyone nodded, and then Kurenai pulled some slips of paper from her pouch. "A friend of mine gave these to me, but I have something I need to do tonight, so I thought you three could use them." She handed one to each of her genin.

It was a coupon for Ichiraku, good for a large bowl at half price. Naruto's stomach rumbled, but the way things were going he thought he'd rather eat alone.

"Thank you, Sensei," he said, though he imagined his voice sounded a little subdued. His team-mates echoed his thanks, though he noticed Shino looking at him a little oddly.

Naruto also felt his sensei's eyes boring into him. "Well, you'd better get going before the dinner rush starts," she said. "You probably shouldn't stay out too late. Oh, before you go, Naruto, I needed to talk to you about your taijutsu training. You can catch up with the others."

Naruto let out a quiet sigh as Shino and Hinata headed off to Ichiraku's.

"Okay Naruto," Kurenai said. "I need you to let Gai know tomorrow morning that I'll be working with you all on genjutsu recognition week after next. He can send Tenten and Lee over to training area nineteen at noon, so they can participate. Got that?"

Naruto nodded and repeated back the relevant details.

"Good," Kurenai said, nodding her approval. "Now, would you like to explain why you are less than enthusiastic about sharing a meal with your team-mates?"

Naruto rubbed at the back of his neck. "I seem to have annoyed them at some point today."

"Shino seems to be acting normally towards you," Kurenai observed.

Naruto stayed silent.

"So it's Hinata," she surmised. "Did this happen after you paid her some complement?"

Naruto's mouth stayed shut, but his head betrayed him by giving a quick nod.

"I see," Kurenai said. She gazed down at him for several moments. "It probably isn't my place to say anything," she finally spoke, "but I've noticed that she doesn't always know what to do when someone says something positive about her. I wouldn't take it too personally, Naruto."

"Why is that?" he asked, genuinely puzzled.

Kurenai shook her head. "Why don't you ask her yourself?"

Naruto opened his mouth, and then closed it. It was obvious to him that Kurenai-sensei knew more than she was saying, but she wanted him to find out for himself. "Why are you making such a mystery out of things?"

Kurenai looked down at him and gave a faint smile. "I know things about you that you would probably prefer that I keep to myself. Please extend your team-mates the same courtesy."

Naruto's stomach lurched when the meaning of her words sunk in. "G-gomen," he said quickly.

Kurenai sighed and shook her head. "No need to apologize, Naruto. You are still learning how a team works, and what a sensei does for their students. Just keep in mind that I'm probably helping other people in similar ways to how I help you." She cocked her head, frowning, as the afternoon light glistened on her mane of black hair. "Naruto, this is usually hard for someone your age to really understand, but keep in mind that not everything that happens around you is about you."

Naruto frowned and scratched the side of his head as his mind raced. "So, what you're saying is that she didn't act that way because she's mad at me?"

"I'm saying that might be the case," Kurenai replied cryptically, "or more likely it's a combination of things, and who you are played only a contributing role in the outcome."

Naruto nodded slowly. "I think I understand, a little. I don't understand why this has to be so complicated though."

"People have been asking that question for a long time," Kurenai replied in a serious voice.

Naruto let out a sigh. "It's not going to get any easier, is it?"

"Probably not," Kurenai said with a slight smile. "But few worthwhile things are easy, are they?"

"I guess not. Thanks for explaining some of this," Naruto said, straightening. His stomach decided to lighten the mood by letting out a low rumble.

"That's partly my job, you know," his sensei said with a sad smile. "Real life examples of looking 'underneath the underneath' seem to work the best. But… you'd better get going before they eat all the ramen."

Naruto knew she was just teasing him, but his pulse still sped up at the thought. After a quick bow, he began racing off across the rooftops to catch up with his team. He heard the quiet laughter that followed him, but, recognizing the voice, he just smiled himself.

He caught sight of Shino and Hinata blocks before they reached the ramen stand. He landed lightly on the pavement behind them, but still they both turned as one to look at him. Well, we are supposed to be a reconnaissance team, he mused. "I, er, had to talk to sensei about my extra training," he said. It was technically true, and much less embarrassing to admit.

"Ano, what does your scroll say?" Hinata asked. "We've been comparing ours, and Kurenai-san has put a lot of detail into the plans."

"She didn't give me a scroll," Naruto said with a slight smile, "she arranged for me to work with another jonin in the morning. Some guy by the name of Maito Gai."

Shino looked at him, and Naruto swore the skin above his glasses began to draw together, like he was frowning. "I've heard of him, he's a renowned taijutsu specialist."

Naruto bit his tongue before it could start bragging. If Kurenai-sensei was correct, these were not the people around which he needed to put up a false front. In a heretofore rare flash of insight, he realized that Shino might interpret Naruto's morning training with another jonin as a sign of favoritism. "I hope so," he said with a theatrical sigh. "She said my taijutsu was such a mess that she didn't think she could fix it without help."

Hinata just stared at him as Naruto gave a sheepish shrug. Shino's brow, however, smoothed out and he gave a thoughtful nod. "Then it's good that you are both taking this so seriously."

Naruto shrugged. "How am I going to beat you down if I don't?" he asked innocently, then began to whistle tonelessly as he walked past his teammates. "We'd better get there before the noodles get cold," he said.

He turned back to see Shino and Hinata exchange a wordless glance before they began walking again.

The old man who ran Ichiraku always seemed pleased to see his best customer. "Hey Naruto, who are your friends?" he asked. Until recently, he and his daughter were the only people Naruto knew who were likely to even notice if he dropped dead in his apartment. At least, until the smell bothered the neighbors, he reminded himself.

Still, if anyone deserved a smile, the gracious man about to serve the noodles surely did. Shino and Hinata had silently walked up on either side of him, so he put a hand on each of their shoulders as he answered. "These are my team-mates, Ichiraku-san!"

"Well, why haven't you brought them here before?" the old man asked.

"Well, we just became Team 8 yesterday, and we had a practice, and…" Naruto explained until he noticed the man was smiling and waving his hand from side to side.

"Naruto, I was just joking with you. Seriously now, aren't you going to introduce your friends?"

"Gomen," Naruto said quickly. "This is Aburame Shino and Hyuuga Hinata."

"I'm pleased to meet you both!" he replied. "Have a seat and I'll get you some menus, take all the time you want to decide – we have a lot of flavors to choose from."

Naruto, of course, already knew what he wanted. He used Kurenai's coupon to order a large bowl of pork ramen at half price, and after checking his wallet ordered another bowl of miso-flavored ramen. Shino ordered a bowl of beef ramen, while Hinata eventually settled on miso ramen.

Everyone was quiet after the noodles arrived. Their labors seemed to have given them an appetite, because their mouths were kept too busy for conversation for a good while.

Surprisingly enough, it was Shino who finally broke the silence. "Our sensei was impressed by your Bunshin," he said without preamble.

Naruto frowned. "What do you mean?"

"The one that carried the wood up to the roof," the bug-user replied cryptically. "I don't think she expected to be able to hold a conversation with one."

"Why not?" Naruto asked. "If it's a copy of me, shouldn't it be able to talk?"

"Most Bunshin jutsus don't even produce solid copies," Shino explained. "And while there are some that do produce copies of the user that can touch things, those copies are usually not very self-aware. At first, we thought it was you talking to us."

Naruto stuck his lower lip out. "So you're saying I'm so dumb that you couldn't tell the difference between me and a mindless clone?" He thought he heard a sharp inhalation coming from the stool on the other side of him, where Hinata was sitting.

Shino looked at him for a long moment. "Your attempt at self-deprecating humor is noted, but not necessary. The thrust of my remarks was that your clones are unusually self-aware, a reflection of the degree of skill and energy used in their creation."

"Oh," was all Naruto could say to that. "Er, thanks, Shino."

The Aburame boy nodded gravely. Naruto finished his pork ramen and started on the miso-flavored bowl. He wondered why Kurenai-sensei hadn't said anything to him about the Bunshin. He concluded that she probably didn't want him to get a swelled head and start acting like an Uchiha. But that didn't explain why Shino decided to bring it up on his own. Then he remembered the boy's disparaging remark yesterday after his botched attempt at Kage Bunshin no Jutsu. Naruto supposed he might have felt the need to make up for his previous comment, even though Naruto had mostly forgotten it a day later. While the boy's reserve and exceptionally quiet and precise manner were a little unusual to deal with, that same precision and rectitude would also make him a very reliable team-mate. Oddly enough, Naruto found himself warming a bit toward the silent shinobi.

Of course, such an introspective mood was not meant to last. Naruto's train of thought was neatly derailed when he felt a spike of killing intent coming from the street behind him. He twisted on his stool to see what was happening.

Looking somewhat bruised and dirty, Kiba, Sakura, and Sasuke were walking up the street. Sakura was chattering happily about some test involving bells and Naruto felt his stomach quiver happily for an instant. Then he remembered her words on the park bench and the warm feeling died. The killing glare, of course, was coming from Sasuke. Naruto wondered if the famed Uchiha genius even figured out why Naruto had taken his place. Probably not, he concluded, for a genius, he doesn't have much imagination.

Naruto returned his rival's glare and bared his teeth. He knew his slightly enlarged canines sometimes made adults a little nervous, but he didn't fully appreciate why this was so until a couple of days ago.

The whole thing might have ended with an exchange of glares if Kiba hadn't asked Sasuke a question. When he didn't get an answer, the Inuzuka boy looked over at his team-mate and flinched at the facial expression he saw. Kiba frowned, evidently searching for the source of Sasuke's ire. Finally he seemed to notice Naruto, seated at the counter of Ichiraku Ramen, twisted around in his seat to return Sasuke's stare.

Kiba gritted his teeth and his spiky hair seemed to puff up as he stalked over toward Naruto. "Do you have a problem with my team-mate?" he asked in a voice that was little more than a growl.

Naruto didn't answer, but instead kept his eyes locked onto Sasuke's face. He did notice that the Uchiha boy's upper lip was curled, perhaps in annoyance at Kiba's interference.

"What is your problem?" Kiba asked again, a little louder this time.

"Mind your own business," Naruto said, glaring back at Sasuke. Sakura had also stopped, and looked back and forth between the two of them.

"Kiba," Shino said reasonably as he stood up, "Naruto and Sasuke have never really gotten along. We should probably just stay out of it."

The dog-user frowned at the bug-user. "Who are you to tell me what to do, Aburame? We just spent all day on Kakashi-sensei's stupid bell test, and we're the first team he's ever passed!"

Kiba threw out his chest with that last statement, and Shino's eyebrows became visible over his glasses. "Our teacher did not make us perform any additional tests beyond a basic skills assessment, so she must be confident in our abilities. Instead, we completed our first mission today."

Kiba snorted. "So? Just because you got an easy sensei… I got a look at her when she picked you up. She just decided to go easy on you."

Shino stiffened as Naruto stood up from his seat. Naruto swore he heard a low buzzing coming from somewhere nearby. Sasuke scowled at Kiba's back, but he approached the ramen stand along with Sakura.

Fortunately, the Haruno girl stepped forward and grabbed Kiba's elbow. "Don't you dare insult their teacher just because she's a woman! Would you want your sister to hear you say that? Or your mother?"

Kiba winced, seemingly in spite of himself, and Naruto had to stifle a snicker. He was a little surprised when Hinata spoke up as well.

"A-ano," she said, "Shinobi are not allowed to fight in public. I, er, don't want to see any of us get in trouble so soon after graduating."

Shino's brow furrowed, but he gave a short nod and sat back down. Naruto grudgingly followed.

"Right Hinata!" Sakura agreed with the girl. "Leave it to the women," she sneered at Kiba as she emphasized the word, "to keep their heads in a crisis." She smiled at the Hyuuga girl. "It's not worth any of us getting in trouble, just because Naruto-baka is too stupid to leave Sasuke alone."

That last insult, so gratuitously added, was the last straw for Naruto. Sakura was playing the peacemaker here, but she still made time to insult him. Her precious Sasuke was glaring at him, while he was just trying to eat his ramen.

Well, to hell with it, and to hell with them.

He got up from his stool so abruptly that it fell over. He pushed past Kiba so brusquely that the larger boy took a half-step backwards. Kiba reached out for Naruto's shoulder, but the smaller boy used the heel of his hand to knock Kiba's hand loose before he even had a chance to get a grip. Akamaru let out a low growl as the Inuzuka boy leaned against the wall of the restaurant.

Hinata felt her jaw drop, along with her stomach, as her team-mate angrily marched away. She felt almost worn away by all the emotional reversals she'd been through that day. First Naruto's stumbling comments in the garden had mortified her, as if he was saying she made him think she was a boy.

When he tried to explain what he meant, it only got worse. He seemed to be saying that she wasn't pretty or nice like the other two girls in their graduating class… but that wasn't right, or else he wouldn't seem so confused. Then he finally said that he was glad she was on his team.

Hinata couldn't remember anyone ever expressing happiness at her presence, not since her mother was alive. His simple, heartfelt statement almost made her faint. As it was, she had to turn away because her face was blushing as red as a tomato. She'd had difficulty talking to him after that, and it wasn't until Kurenai-sensei came to help her in the kitchen that she began to organize her thoughts.

Kurenai was nothing, if not observant, and she soon had Hinata explaining the whole situation. The older woman chuckled a little when the genin repeated Naruto's words. She advised Hinata in a more serious voice that any future compliments she received from the Uzumaki boy were likely to be just as heartfelt and incoherent. It was funny how her sensei seemed so sure that would happen, but Hinata knew better.

She really didn't want anyone to get in trouble for fighting, especially Naruto. She suspected that he would receive more of the blame than he deserved if there was an altercation. Hinata did not miss the looks the villagers gave him as they walked together. She knew Naruto was often laughed at by the other students at the Konoha Ninja Academy. But she hadn't realized how the villagers in the street reacted to him. It seemed almost, familiar, in a way. It took a while before Hinata realized that she'd seen that degree of distaste before – in the faces of the Hyuuga clan elders when they talked of her failures.

Still, Naruto passed through it without comment, merely returning the more virulent glares. Hinata didn't know whether to be impressed by his fortitude in the face of such dislike, or to be heartbroken that the boy didn't seem to regard it as anything unusual. Nonetheless, she feared that a public brawl would make people hate him even worse, especially since it would have involved genin from several prominent families.

Between her and Sakura, they'd managed to remind the others of the rules, and at least partially defuse the tensions between the two teams. She was grateful to the pink-haired kunoichi, and started to shyly return the girl's smile when Sakura decided to insult Naruto and blame him for the whole situation.

Sakura's attitude toward Naruto was well known to Hinata, but the white-eyed girl was surprised to see her still lash out at him while supposedly in the role of a peace-maker. This hypocrisy wasn't lost on Naruto either, because he visibly flinched, then got up from his stool so quickly that she was afraid he was going to attack someone. Instead, he just brushed past Kiba, who was also standing closer than was strictly polite.

Sakura rolled her eyes and sighed. "He's always such a baby," she groused. Kiba scowled, shaking the hand that Naruto knocked away.

Hinata, who'd been staring after her team-mate, turned toward the other girl. The new emotion she'd started feeling on Naruto's behalf began to simmer within her. Her Byakugan activated on their own, and Hinata was surprised by a sudden desire to close all of the girl's Tenketsu points.

Close up, the distended blood vessels and enlarged pupils that characterized her family's advanced bloodline looked rather disturbing. Hinata had always been embarrassed about this before, but now she was secretly pleased when the Haruno girl stepped back suddenly. "What's wrong?" the girl asked.

"You should not say such things to Naruto!" Hinata said in a voice that was little more than a whisper.

Sakura gaped at her for a moment, but then her eyes grew canny. "I understand," she said. "But just because you like him doesn't mean he isn't-"

"I think you fail to understand," Shino interrupted, "that Naruto was wholly focused on his food until Sasuke made his presence known - his killing intent was noticeable to all of us. Your condemnation of Naruto is therefore illogical. I think you also fail to comprehend that it is possible to feel loyalty toward team-mates in the absence of romantic attachment." The bug-user looked from Sasuke to Kiba, ignoring the shocked silence caused by him actually speaking up. "You have my sympathies," he told the dog-user in a matter-of-fact tone.

Sasuke grunted, but didn't dispute anything Shino said.

Hinata wrapped her fingers around the hem of her jacket. "A-ano, Shino-san, I think I've had enough ramen."

Shino looked at her for a moment before nodding. He looked at the cooling remains of his beef ramen. "You are correct, it is best hot, and our meal has been interrupted." He turned to the older man and bowed, a motion Hinata quickly echoed. They left their money next to Naruto's and then Shino led the way as they left Ichiraku.

As Hinata and Shino walked side-by-side down the street, she could hear the man's voice carrying in the late afternoon air: "I would appreciate it if you young punks would not run off my customers!"

It was several minutes before Hinata found her voice again. "A-arigatou, Shino-san."

Shino's head turned toward her, even as he continued to walk forward. "My observations were accurate and relevant. No thanks are necessary."

Hinata absorbed this carefully as they continued down the street. "Gomen," she finally said, "but you seem to have changed your opinion regarding Naruto-kun?"

Shino was quiet for a moment, and Hinata worried that her question had offended the boy. "I am… re-evaluating my assessment," he finally said. "Kurenai-sensei seems to bring out qualities in him that were not apparent in his conduct at the academy. A skilled observer must always be willing to challenge his preconceptions if new data contradicts."

Finally, they reached an intersection where Hinata need to turn to reach the Hyuuga compound. "I will see you tomorrow," she said quietly.

"At ten," Shino agreed.

Hinata nodded and turned toward her home. She noticed the sky slowly darkening in the East as a warm summer evening approached Konoha. It seemed impossible that so much had happened in the span of a handful of hours, and she wondered if life would always be like that around her new friends.

That thought fortified her as she walked, steeling herself for her father's inevitable questions.

6

The Journey to the Borderlands

Naruto kept an eye on Hinata as they ascended the Hokage’s Tower. She seemed a lot steadier than before, which was good, but he didn’t want to take any chances either.

He also studiously avoided making any sort of eye contact with Shino. He was pretty sure the damn bug-user had been silently laughing at him since he’d arrived at the base of the tower that morning. He’d looked down at Naruto and the sleeping Hinata without saying a single word. Finally Naruto had whispered “She’s really tired,” as quietly as he could.

“I can see,” Shino replied, deadpan.

Unfortunately, with that high collar, Naruto couldn’t see the boy’s mouth to be sure. Nonetheless, he silently promised himself to kick the larger boy’s butt the next time they sparred.

And to top off the day’s weirdness, his shoulder still felt warm where her head had rested on it.

At least the chuunin guarding the Hokage’s office had retained their attitude adjustment from the previous day – though Naruto wondered if that would necessarily have been true if Kurenai-sensei hadn’t been bringing up the rear.

At least he knew the Hokage’s smile wasn’t feigned when they entered his office. “Hmmm,” he murmured as they stood at attention before his desk. He held out a pair of scrolls for Kurenai. “The scroll with the blue seal contains the details of your assignment. You will be patrolling that section of the border with Earth Country for three weeks, starting three days from now. That should allow you plenty of time to travel and familiarize yourself with the area. The scroll with the red seal is to be presented to the leader of the team currently in place, a jonin named Dariketsu.”

“We’re relieving Dariketsu’s team?” Kurenai asked, and her voice held a little edge.

“Yes,” the Hokage answered, gesturing at the jonin with his pipe. “Do you know him?”

Kurenai nodded. “In passing. I am… surprised… he was put in charge of such a sensitive location.”

The old man grunted, and a rueful expression passed over his face, disappearing so quickly Naruto wondered if he’d imagined it. “There have been a few incidents lately. Skirmishes that seemed to straddle the line between our two countries. It’s never really clear which side of the border it started on, so there have been messy diplomatic repercussions. There are a lot of people over there that are still angry about a war fought before your genin were born. To give our envoy to Stone something to use, he can now inform them that Dariketsu’s team of combat veterans has been replaced with a genin team, and request that they reciprocate. I’m explaining this because I want all of you to adopt a very… flexible approach to border intrusions.”

“You want us to just let anyone through?” Naruto asked in disbelief.

“No,” the Hokage said firmly as he shook his head. “But I do want you to make sure that if you intercept someone, it happens in a location that makes it very clear who violated who’s border.”

Naruto frowned as he puzzled out his leader’s words. “So you want us to make sure the other side gets the blame if there’s a fight?”

The Hokage nodded. “Yes, although I hope there won’t be any confrontations, especially if Stone stands down their patrol as well.”

Kurenai spoke up again. “We will make sure we always patrol a few kilometers back from the actual border, so any confrontations will occur on Konoha territory.”

The Hokage nodded. “Very well. Good luck and I will see you in about three and a half weeks. Your relief will have a scroll with a red seal like that one. Do not accept messages from anyone who does not have such a scroll. Understood?”

They all nodded, and with that they left the Hokage’s office. Starting his first C-ranked mission, Naruto wanted to jump into the air and shout “Yatta!”, but two things stopped him. The first was Kurenai’s lectures to her team about proper decorum. Hinata already seemed familiar with all the rules, and while Shino appeared mildly interested, Naruto figured they were aimed primarily at him. The other was Hinata’s condition, the reasons for which he did not fully understand.

Team Eight moved through the streets of Konoha at a quick walk, heading for the nearest gate. Stepping through the portal wasn’t anything they hadn’t already done dozens of times, but somehow it felt different. He nervously adjusted the kunai holster on his right leg, and resisted the urge to pull one out and twirl it by the ring at the end of the handle.

They were on the trade road that led to Earth Country for over two hours before Kurenai called for a break. Naruto was still full of energy, but he noticed Hinata was faltering. Her apparent lack of rest the previous night was catching up with her. She slipped her bag off her shoulders, sat down at the base of a tree, and leaned back, closing her eyes.

Naruto frowned and sat down next to his teammate. “You may want to take your arm and leg weights off, if you are still wearing them,” he said quietly.

Hinata started at the sound of his voice, eyes popping open again. After a moment she self-consciously grasped her forearm through the sleeve of her jacket. “A-ano, that is all right, Naruto.”

Naruto frowned. “But if you are tired, it might help,” he said reasonably.

Hinata smiled. “But then I will just have more weight to carry in my bag.”

Naruto shrugged. “We can stick them in my pack. I didn’t stay up all night, and I missed having you Jyuuken the crap out of me last night.”

Hinata smiled wearily, and Naruto thought he heard a small snort of laughter. Her hand tightened around her sleeve again. “Seriously, Naruto, I will be all right. I won’t improve if I don’t keep the weights on, will I?”

“Well,” Naruto said slowly, “it depends. Gai-sensei said that if you overuse the muscles in your arms and legs, you sometimes have to leave the weights off until you recover.” Of course, the stabbing pains and muscle tears the man described to Naruto never seemed to last longer than a few minutes. But then again, he probably hadn’t ever really hurt himself that way.

Hinata looked thoughtful. “I am a bit sore, but not in that way. I should probably keep them on,” she said firmly. Then she looked down at the ground between her legs. “I appreciate your concern,” she added politely.

Naruto found himself scratching at the back of his head again. “Er, yeah. Well, you’re my teammate after all,” he said. For some reason her shoulders slumped after he said that. “And you’re really fun to spar with,” he added. Hinata nodded without looking up and Naruto decided to go see Kurenai-sensei before he said something stupid again.

Kurenai did not want to make Hinata any more self-conscious than necessary, so she was subtle in her attempts to keep an eye on the girl. She took note of the Hyuuga’s condition using her peripheral vision, and always when something else seemed to draw her attention. Naruto and Shino’s concern for their teammate was more obvious, but that wasn’t necessarily a bad thing. Kurenai hoped that the boys’ concern would make an impression on the girl. Naruto was as obvious as he was sincere, a felicitous combination in this situation.

After a couple of hours on the trade road, Kurenai called for a quick break. Hinata’s fatigue was becoming more and more apparent with every step, and it didn’t surprise her that Hinata, after a brief conversation with Naruto, had fallen asleep leaning against a tree.

Naruto walked toward Kurenai as she fished her canteen out of her pack and took a small swallow. He had an uncharacteristically grim look on his face, displacing his normal smile. “She’s exhausted,” he said quietly. “I don’t think her father should have insisted on her training all night.”

Kurenai bit back the first couple of things she wanted to say, and settled for just nodding her agreement.

The blond genin opened his mouth like he had more to say, but after a moment he just closed it, shaking his head as he walked off toward Shino. He deliberately scuffed his feet on the ground, kicking any loose pebbles or twigs in his path, and Kurenai didn’t need any special jutsu to read his frustration.

Ten minutes later, after they’d all had a drink and refreshed themselves, they were ready to resume their journey, but the girl was still sound asleep.

Kurenai was contemplating how best to wake her charge when Naruto and Shino walked up to their teammate in a fairly matter-of-fact manner. Naruto picked up Hinata’s bag and handed it to Shino, who in turn locked the straps with his own pack.

Naruto turned back to his teammate and visibly swallowed. Then he quickly bent over and wrapped one arm around Hinata’s legs, loosely grasping her shoulder with his other hand. He carefully straightened up and Hinata was neatly folded over his shoulder, still sleeping.

Kurenai recognized the Academy-taught method for carrying a wounded comrade who was stable enough to travel, but unable to walk on their own. What amazed the jonin was the fact that the girl slept through the entire process. That could only indicate acute fatigue, combined with almost total chakra depletion as well. It was surprising she made it as far as she did, Kurenai decided.

Naruto turned toward his sensei and slowly nodded. “I’m ready,” he said quietly.

Kurenai frowned. Naruto was holding himself a little stiffly, and she remembered that he was wearing weights on his arms and legs as well. “Are you sure about this, Naruto?”

The boy nodded carefully. “It’ll be good training, I think.”

Kurenai wondered if he’d been spending too much time with Gai and Lee.

Hinata awoke feeling painfully stiff.

She blinked up at the ceiling wondering how she’d arrived. The last thing she remembered was taking a short break on the side of the road, but now she appeared to be in a room of some sort.

Attempting to sit up was a mistake, she immediately realized, as her abused muscles punished her mercilessly. Her body felt stiff as a board, but far tenderer. She stifled a low moan.

“Ah, you are awake,” a voice said in the darkened room.

Hinata’s fingers slowly formed the seals under the coverlet as she whispered “Byakugan.” She released her blood limit as soon as she sensed Kurenai-sensei was the only other person in the room.

“None of that!” Kurenai said sharply, making Hinata twitch painfully. “Your reserves are still very low,” she continued in a kindlier tone. “Kindly restrict your chakra usage until you have fully recovered.”

“G-gomen,” Hinata stammered, her face flushing.

“Now, regarding this ‘special family training’ of yours…” Kurenai began, letting her voice trail off. “Is there anything you’d like to tell me?” she finally asked.

“No, Sensei,” Hinata replied quietly.

“Hinata, I put you to bed,” her teacher said in a chiding tone, “I saw. You were covered with bruises and abrasions. Your chakra was so low, I was amazed you could even move, let alone walk for two hours! What kind of training leaves you incapacitated?”

Hinata opened her mouth to answer, but then closed it. “I am not permitted to discuss certain things with people outside my family,” she finally said.

Kurenai sighed. “Be that as it may, you are still a ninja on active duty with The Leaf. As such, you are required to keep yourself in good health and that does not include letting yourself become disabled when you know you have a mission the next day.”

“Gomen, Sensei, I told…” Hinata began, but then swallowed her next words. It was shameful to spout excuses for her failures and shortcomings.

“You told your father, didn’t you?” Kurenai asked in a shrewd tone. “Remember, Hinata, I was there when you left for the academy. Your father makes no secret of his contempt for the other shinobi of the village.”

Hinata’s only response was a choked sound.

“Do not apologize for matters over which you have no control, Hinata,” Kurenai continued in a kindlier voice. Then her voice changed, becoming more formal in tone. “But I will require you to refuse any training or exercises that could compromise your ability to participate in our missions. As your jonin, I have the authority to do that. Your responsibility is to convey that directive to your father if the situation ever arises again.”

Hinata inhaled sharply at the thought of how such a conversation would go.

As if reading her thoughts, Kurenai sighed. “I know that will not be easy for you, but if something like this happens again, either you or your father will have to answer for it. If, after explaining my orders, you are still… forced… then it will not be your fault. Do you understand?”

Hinata nodded slowly, ignoring the ache. But the thought of refusing her father filled her with dread.

“Good…. And Hinata, if you ever need to… well, my door is open if you need to talk after we return to Konoha. This inn will be serving dinner soon if you are hungry. Your uniform is next to you on the floor. I’m going to go look in on Naruto and Shino.” The door slid aside, and then back, and Hinata knew she was alone.

Shino was limping slightly as he followed his teammate back to the inn. They were only a day’s travel from the border with Earth, so their jonin decided to spend the extra day at a road-side inn that typically served merchants traveling between Fire Country and Earth Country.

Of course, sitting still for a day did not appeal to Naruto. Immediately after breakfast he began urging them to train. Kurenai wanted to keep an eye on the still-sleeping Hinata, so Shino followed Naruto out into the woods to spar.

Naruto had evidently needed to work out some of his agitation and frustration regarding their teammate, because Shino couldn’t recall ever getting the crap kicked out of him this badly since he’d started at the Konoha Ninja Academy.

Fortunately, the blond genin remembered to pull his punches, so Shino only had some mild contusions to add to his puzzled embarrassment. The boy’s speed had increased to a remarkable degree, and the power behind his blocks and counters threatened to knock the larger boy out of his stances every time they clashed.

This wasn’t to say that the bug-user hadn’t gotten in a few shots of his own, one of which he’d inadvertently landed at full force when Naruto tried to duck under it and go for a sweep. The result was a small mouse under the blond’s left eye, and a throbbing wrist that bothered Shino more and more as the adrenalin wore off. The blow barely fazed his opponent, who merely came to his feet after a backwards roll and nodded acknowledgment of the point.

The changes wrought in Naruto’s fighting style by his supplemental training were all too apparent to Shino. Gone were the awkward, exaggerated versions of the basic taijutsu stances. Naruto’s footing was now sure and his movements exceptionally fluid. His attacks and counters were less straight-forward and more circular in motion.

Naruto still favored attacking from unusual directions, but his dependence on the terrain had lessened. He didn’t hesitate to launch himself into the air for a flying kick, confident that his speed would allow him to complete the move without being caught in the air. Indeed, the one time Shino managed to catch one of Naruto’s high kicks, the genin simply twisted in mid-air and used a scissoring motion to bring his other heel crashing into the side of the Kikai-nin’s head.

The worst part was that Naruto had done all this with nearly half of Shino’s colony attached to his back, steadily draining chakra until they let go, replete. That was something he’d rarely seen an individual Kikai bug do, let alone dozens of them at once. The amount of chakra they’d drained from the boy was amazing. The worst part of all was that Naruto didn’t even seem to have noticed.

Shino frowned at Naruto’s back as he followed the boy back to the inn. Chakra reserves that large were rare in a jonin, let alone a genin. Could it be linked to the mystery surrounding Naruto that his father was forbidden to discuss? His mind worked furiously as Naruto, still energized from the sparring, babbled happily about a dozen topics at once. The only thing that came to mind was his father’s words about relying on first-hand observations. Listening to his teammate wonder if Hinata was awake yet and if he could talk the cook into serving ramen, Shino decided to do just that.

For now.

Naruto bounced in his seat as he waited for their food to arrive. Sparring with Shino had really woken up his appetite, especially since he’d actually held his own against his taller teammate.

He was also happy to discover that the inn’s proprietors, a middle-aged couple from Wind Country, didn’t seem to be aware of his prisoner and treated him so nicely it was a little disconcerting. The wife, who ran the kitchen, kept patting him on the head and saying how he reminded her of her son. She was quite a good cook, and boasted experience in many regional cuisines, so she seemed a little disconcerted when her favorite guest asked for ramen. Normally, she said, such a dish was a bit beneath her talents, but she couldn’t seem to say no when Naruto smiled and bowed apologetically with his palms together.

Naruto was working on his second bowl, trying to puzzle out the unusual spices the nice old lady had mixed into the broth, when a voice coming from behind him almost made him fall to the floor.

“Ramen again?” Kurenai asked in a disapproving tone.

“Er, yeah,” Naruto said, ducking his head as he turned toward his sensei. “I’m going without for three weeks as it is,” he continued in a slightly petulant tone.

Kurenai sighed. “Three weeks of trail rations and whatever we can gather on our own. All the more reason to eat nutritious food when you have the opportunity, Naruto. Not just bowl after bowl of noodles.”

“I do not think there is any danger of Naruto becoming malnourished at this inn,” Shino observed. “Not after the breakfast he was served.”

Naruto turned back and glared across the table at his teammate. “You’re just mad because Obasan almost swatted one of your bugs when she saw it on your shoulder.”

“The reckless slaughter of innocent and productive creatures is not something to take lightly,” Shino insisted in a frosty tone. “She might have been more careful in her judgment if she had not been distracted attempting to sate your appetite.”

Naruto stuck his lower lip out and scowled at his teammate. “I didn’t ask her to do that! It’s just, every time she came out of the kitchen and she saw my plate was empty, she put more food on it.” He shrugged. “Maybe she had a lot of food that was about to go bad or something.”

Shino didn’t respond to that, but Naruto did hear the muted buzzing that sometimes occurred when his teammate was displeased about something. Naruto figured it was his bugs reacting, but he really didn’t want to think too much about that.

Kurenai sat down next to Shino, and soon the cook was taking her dinner order as well. With a warm smile at Naruto, the older woman bustled back to her kitchen to prepare the jonin’s food. It had been a long time since Naruto had actively wondered what it would be like to have a mother. Normally, he was too busy for such thoughts, which was at least partially intentional.

But now, waiting for Hinata to recover so they could resume their journey, Naruto had an unusually large amount of time on his hands. He found himself thinking more and more about the innkeepers’ reactions. What would it be like to live in a village where everyone treated him like that? Konoha was his home, but what would it be like to not have people glaring at him all the time, praying for his death, or telling their children to stay away from that Uzumaki brat?

Those thoughts made him very uncomfortable, and he tried to suppress them without much success. Then he followed Kurenai’s advice from several weeks ago, and tried to logically examine his options. If he tried to move to another village, his new neighbors would want to know why. If they ever found out he had a demon bound within his stomach, Naruto knew his welcome would expire soon afterwards. Even if he came up with a believable story, he’d still need to be able to make a living. He knew a little about being a ninja, but not much else. He couldn’t join another Hidden Village as a shinobi for several reasons. One, he’d be hunted down as a missing-nin by the Konoha ANBU squads. Two, his new employers would probably be able to detect that stupid damn fox and he’d be back at square one with everyone fearing and hating him. Three, eventually he’d be sent on a mission where he’d have to fight one of his former classmates. While he wouldn’t mind kicking Sasuke’s butt, having to fight Shino, Lee, or Hinata for real was not something he could even consider without going into a cold sweat.

No, he was stuck with Konoha in much the same way Konoha was stuck with him. A small, perverse corner of his mind was pleased by that. It would make becoming the Hokage even sweeter. With a smile, he re-addressed himself to the oddly seasoned ramen. But after a couple of bites, he noticed that everyone else was staring at something immediately to his left. He quickly swallowed and turned his head as well.

Hinata, a little pale and unsteady, was easing herself onto the bench next to him.

Naruto almost reached out to steady her, but something made him hesitate. Remembering her insistence that she could carry her own bag and wear her weights despite her exhaustion, he realized that trying to help her might make her feel even more self-conscious. So he refrained, and wondered if he was actually getting smarter about such things. Or was his sudden intuition merely dumb luck?

“Gomen,” Hinata said quietly. “You were right, Naruto,” she continued in a subdued voice, “about the weights, and everything.”

Naruto just shrugged at his teammate, wondering if something else was wrong. “I’m just glad you’re feeling better,” he said. “I missed you.” Naruto coughed suddenly as Hinata’s eyes widened. “I mean, I missed sparring with you. Last night. You know. Like we always do,” he added quickly.

Hinata just nodded her agreement, looking downward the entire time.

The next day, they were back on the road again, bright and early. Naruto was still a little groggy and yawned frequently for the first hour. The pallets they’d slept on were far softer than he was used to, so he had trouble sleeping at night.

Surprisingly, the innkeeper’s wife got up early as well, to send them on their way with a good breakfast. Catching Kurenai’s look, Naruto made sure to thank her and let her know how much he appreciated her efforts. The way the older lady just beamed at him made him feel very strange, and he found himself blushing as they left. After they left the inn, Kurenai-sensei walked beside him for a while, and thanked him for not taking advantage of the cook’s friendliness.

Naruto frowned at his sensei. “Why would I do that?” he asked.

Kurenai smiled thinly. “Why indeed. She doesn’t act like most of the other villagers you’ve known. I talked to her briefly the day before. Her son, a boy you bear a passing resemblance to, went to Konoha several years ago to attend the Ninja Academy.”

“Really?” Naruto asked. “What rank is he now? Have we met him?”

“He died during his chuunin exam,” Kurenai answered in a somber tone.

Naruto tripped over his own feet. “Oh,” he said as he stumbled for a moment.

“I will admit,” Kurenai continued, “that I was slightly concerned that you might… inadvertently… take advantage of the situation. But aside from asking her to make ramen for you,” she continued, making him duck his head a little, “your behavior was entirely appropriate.”

“I didn’t think it was that big a deal,” Naruto grumbled. “She did ask me what my favorite food was.”

Kurenai nodded at that. “As I said, I am glad you did not take advantage of the situation.”

Naruto scratched the back of his head. “Ano… Sensei, if I do that when people are nice to me, won’t that encourage them to treat me like everyone else does?”

Kurenai nodded. “Very good, Naruto. You are thinking ahead and considering the consequences of your actions.”

Naruto found his face reddening again. Kurenai nodded at him, and then turned to speak with Shino. Naruto took that as his cue to speed up a little so he was walking beside Hinata.

A good dinner, during which the nice old lady tried to stuff the weary kunoichi with as much food as she could hold, and another full night’s sleep had restored most of Hinata’s energy. She was still moving a little slower than normal, but she was out on point this morning, periodically activating her blood-limit to do quick scans of the area around them.

They walked together in a silence that was actually fairly comfortable. Naruto wondered if concentrating on the woods around them, scanning for an ambush, kept his teammate too busy to get nervous. They hadn’t discussed exactly how Hinata had been transported to the inn, and he wasn’t about to bring up that subject any time soon.

Naruto wasn’t completely sure why he’d been the one to carry the girl. Of course, if there was danger, it would be better if their jonin was unburdened. But he couldn’t say for sure if that had even occurred to him at the time. What he did know was that her arm and leg weights were contributing to her fatigue, and she wouldn’t even have been wearing them if he hadn’t shown his off. He realized that seeing her exhausted and full of pain made him feel worse than he would if it had been himself. He wondered if this was what it was like to have friends, this feeling that you’d rather be hurt yourself than see them in pain.

In a sudden flash of insight, Naruto understood why they’d been taught that shinobi should avoid friendships and close personal relationships with their comrades. The thought of his friend being hurt, or even killed, made him feel physically ill, like he’d drunk all the bad milk in Konoha in one sitting. But why had Kurenai-sensei urged him to become friends with his teammates?

Then Naruto remembered his role in the team. He was supposed to cover their escape if they were ambushed or overrun. In that situation, he supposed it was… useful… if he cared a lot about his teammates. Naruto glanced back at his sensei. Had she pushed him to make friends so he would be more likely to sacrifice himself for them?

That was a very uncomfortable thought, and it made Naruto feel very cold inside. He’d come to value Kurenai-sensei’s wisdom and all the things she’d taught him. The idea that she was doing so just to manipulate him… but she hadn’t really, had she? He needed to think this through, the way she’d taught him.

Naruto recalled their first conversation at Moritake’s. She’d already explained his role on Team Eight, and asked him how hard he was willing to work to achieve his long-term goals. She hadn’t really concealed anything from him, and her expectations were straightforward. If she really was just trying to get rid of the Kyuubi like the other villagers wanted, she wouldn’t have set up extra training for him, now would she? Naruto admitted to himself that when he first became a genin, his taijutsu had been awful. Training with Gai-sensei and Lee, he was much more likely to survive any situation they got into.

Naruto also remembered a conversation he’d had with the Hokage, many years ago, when the old man explained how the Hokage was the shinobi who protected everyone in the village, with his wisdom as well as his strength. That was the day that Naruto decided that he would become the Hokage some day. No one could ignore his existence then… Were his current duties all that much different? True, Kurenai-sensei was doing most of the thinking here, but wasn’t it Naruto’s job to help protect his teammates? Wasn’t that just like what the Hokage did? Or at least a little bit like it? Maybe he was trying to see ‘underneath the underneath’ when there was no real underneath to see.

Naruto tried to think his way through this question as the sun climbed steadily in the sky. Around noon-time, Kurenai called a halt so they could eat some trail mix and drink from their canteens. Seeing as how there was no stream nearby, she also showed them a new jutsu for permanently summoning water by collecting the humidity present in the ground and air around them.

Naruto was eager to learn any new jutsus he could, and watched Kurenai slowly form the seals with eager eyes. Hinata and Shino both performed the simple jutsu without much trouble, while Naruto frantically practiced the seals.

When it was his turn, Naruto was a little nervous, but managed to form the seals correctly as he said “Suiton: Gyoushuu!” However, instead of a two-inch-wide spinning vortex of air appearing over the mouth of his canteen, Naruto summoned one nearly a foot across. The torrent of water that gushed down out of it not only filled his canteen, but it also knocked it over and splattered their sandals and pant-legs with mud.

Naruto managed to grab his canteen before all the water poured out, and then smiled sheepishly at his teammates as they tried to shake the spattered mud off their legs.

Neither Shino nor Hinata said anything, but Kurenai finally broke the silence. “Should I assume that was an accident, Naruto? Or was that intentional?” she asked in a dry tone.

“I wouldn’t prank-” Naruto said and cut himself off. He’d been about to say he wouldn’t prank Hinata since she was just now feeling better, but she probably wouldn’t appreciate hearing that. “Not during a mission, Sensei,” he said in a formal tone.

“I see,” Kurenai replied. “Well, I think it’s safe to say that did not manifest as intended. Do you know why?”

Naruto shrugged, a little frustrated and embarrassed, but did not answer.

“A-ano,” Hinata said, breaking the silence.

“Yes, Hinata?” Kurenai asked.

“Naruto… he always tries his best,” the girl mumbled, looking down as a blush slowly crept up her cheeks. Naruto noticed her fingers clutching the hem of her jacket and he wondered why she was so tense. “He… probably put too much chakra into the jutsu,” she finally said, lifting her head a little. “It didn’t go wrong, not really. He just gathered too much water for the canteen to hold.”

Naruto stared at his teammate, gratified that she wasn’t rubbing it in. Really, she was just saying that he did it too well. He was still staring at her when she looked up, and her head shot back down so fast Naruto wondered if he’d just imagined it.

“That was a very astute observation, Hinata,” Kurenai said approvingly. “Naruto,” the jonin continued, “when using a jutsu, especially for the first time, it’s a good idea to use just the minimum amount of chakra to complete it.”

Naruto frowned and scratched his head, forgetting for the moment that his hand was wet and a little muddy. “How do I know how much to use?” he asked, puzzled.

Kurenai blinked. “As you complete the seals, you should feel a draining sensation as the jutsu attempts to draw the necessary chakra. Release just enough chakra for the draining sensation to stop, and no more.”

“Draining sensation?” Naruto asked quizzically. “What do you mean?”

Kurenai paused for a long moment before answering. “When you use a jutsu, don’t you feel a slight draining sensation as your chakra goes to fuel the technique?”

Naruto shook his head, his eyes widening.

“What does it feel like?” Kurenai asked carefully.

“More like relief,” Naruto answered faintly, staring off into the distance. Then he blinked and nodded. “It’s like when you have to go to the bathroom really bad, and you couldn’t for a while, and then when you do, it’s really…” Naruto’s voice trailed off as he shook his head.

Hinata was blushing again, and Shino’s shoulders appeared to be quivering. Even the corners of Kurenai-sensei’s mouth were turning up. It wasn’t fair! “You did ask me what it felt like,” Naruto finally said in exasperation.

“You are correct, Naruto,” his jonin said with a nod. “While your choice of metaphor is unfortunate, it is also descriptive. You appear to have larger than normal chakra reserves, which would also explain your ability to use Kage Bunshin no Jutsu. While a large reserve is desirable in a shinobi, most do not develop so large a capacity until after they have mastered basic chakra control techniques. You need to practice limiting how much chakra you allow to… flow… into your jutsus, starting with this one. Water any plants along the roadside that appear to be dried out, and see if you can reduce your effect size until it is comparable to Shino and Hinata’s.”

Naruto nodded, grateful that something useful might come out of this debacle, besides managing to embarrass himself.

“In the future,” Kurenai continued, “when we learn new jutsus, I’ll try to give you an expectation of how much chakra to use, in relation to this one.” She smiled. “We wouldn’t want you to destroy your clothes with a cleansing jutsu, would we?”

Naruto laughed at that mental image, and wondered why Hinata squeaked and looked away.

Following his sensei’s directions, Naruto spent most of the afternoon eroding various spots along the trail. Hinata watched him closely each time he paused to practice over some particularly parched-looking bush. Oddly enough, though, it didn’t make him self-conscious. He supposed he was used to her watching him when they practiced chakra-control exercises.

Since the water-walking exercise, he hadn’t had too many problems with the red chakra. According to Hinata, she could still occasionally see bits of it circulating through his coils where they ran close to the surface of his skin, but they didn’t seem to be interfering as much anymore. Given what he knew about the probable source of the oddly colored chakra, Naruto wasn’t sure what to make of that. If the stupid fox was aware of what was going on, it might have figured out that ruining Naruto’s training just made it more likely they would both die on a mission. But this was a demon, after all, so he wasn’t sure he could ascribe normal logic to its actions.

Eventually, Naruto figured out how it should feel when he put just enough chakra into the jutsu. The first time he achieved this, Hinata gave him a broad smile, the first genuine one he’d seen from her since they left Konoha, and he promptly lost control of the jutsu and blasted the poor bush out by its roots. Hinata’s face grew so chagrined that Naruto couldn’t help but laugh out loud. Hinata looked down again, but eventually recovered and flashed a small grin of her own.

“You know,” Naruto said, as they hustled along the road to get ahead of Kurenai and Shino again, “it’s nice to be out of Konoha, at least for a little while.”

“Hai,” Hinata agreed, nodding slowly.

“It’s one of the nice things about being a shinobi, I guess,” he continued. “You get to travel a lot, going on missions.”

“Naruto?” Hinata asked quietly.

Naruto turned toward the girl.

Her face had gone very still, and she regarded him with widened eyes. Her mouth opened and closed once, with no sound coming out. Then she swallowed and was able to speak. “D-do you ever think about leaving Konoha?” she asked quietly.

As Hinata asked the question he’d asked himself the day before, Naruto felt like he’d been punched in the stomach. He’d hoped she hadn’t noticed the villagers’ hateful eyes, and the way they acted. Their attitude was a little more subdued around his teammates than when he was alone, and he tried to avoid the meaner adults as much as possible when he was with them. He thought he’d pulled it off since neither Shino nor Hinata had asked him about it. But Hinata’s question, combined with the look on her face, told him that she knew all too well what was going on. For a moment, Naruto felt exposed, like he’d been caught coming out of the bath.

The blond shinobi didn’t need to ask if his face gave away some of his emotions, because Hinata abruptly turned her head. He understood she was trying to avoid embarrassing him, but the reminder that he’d lost control of his facial expression was unwelcome. “G-gomen,” she said, studying a pine tree that appeared to have been struck by lightning at some point, “that is none of my business.”

“You’re allowed to ask,” Naruto said quickly. “I don’t know, really. Probably not,” he reassured her. “Konoha is my home. I can’t become Hokage if I leave, can I? Besides, someone has to keep you three entertained with ‘unfortunate metaphors’,” he added, grinning as she turned back.

“Hai!” she said in a small voice, and seemed to relax a little. Naruto realized she was probably worried about having to break in a new teammate if he ran away from Konoha, which was understandable. Just their luck, they’d be stuck with an idiot like Sasuke who’d be too busy looking cool to actually watch their backs.

By the time the sun was setting, Naruto felt like he had a pretty good feel for both the water gathering jutsu and how to limit his chakra output. Kurenai led them away from the road for several minutes, until they found a small clearing in which they could pitch their tents. Hinata volunteered to gather stones for a small fire while the others ventured into the woods as Kurenai discussed how they would divide up the necessary tasks. With the assistance of Shino’s bugs, the three of them found some rabbits for their evening meal. Kurenai showed them the proper way to clean the animals. By the time they’d brought the dressed meat back to their camp, Hinata had a bright but smokeless fire going inside the sunken fire-pit she’d dug with the folding shovel from Kurenai’s pack. It was deep enough that the flames would be invisible from more than a few yards away.

Naruto was hopeful when he noticed that Hinata also had several handfuls of greenery that she’d collected. He hoped those were spices, because just eating burnt rabbit didn’t appeal to him that much… but with the way Hinata prepared things, he might be looking forward to dinner after all.

While Hinata tended the herb-stuffed rabbit sizzling on spits over the sunken fire, Naruto and Shino set up the tent they’d be sharing and Kurenai set up a tent for her and Hinata. By the time they were done, it was fully dark, and the appetizing smells were making Naruto’s stomach rumble loudly.

When they sat down to eat, Naruto was dismayed to see that there was a field ration bar set out for each of them. Kurenai seemed to note his expression, because she was looking directly at him when she spoke. “Eat the rations first, then the rabbit. I’m sure Hinata has done an excellent job, if the smell is any indication, but each bar is designed to contain all the nutrients you should need for a day of high activity,” she said. “I don’t want to see any pieces of them left over. We’re going to be a long way from the nearest hospital, so we can’t afford for anyone to get sick.”

“Hai,” Naruto said in a resigned tone. He picked up the bar, unwrapped it, and crammed it into his mouth with little ceremony. He chewed slowly and, with frequent sips from his canteen, eventually swallowed the pasty mess. Then he let out a sigh and picked up the skewer Hinata had stuck in the ground before him. It smelled even better at close range, especially after the offensively bland ration bar. He paused, noting that everyone else was reaching for their skewers, and nodded toward Hinata and said “Itadakimasu!” with a broad smile.

The rabbit skewer lived up to his expectations, and he had to resist the urge to gobble it down. Instead, he ate it slowly, savoring the tasty meat. He glanced up at Hinata, who hadn’t touched hers yet, and was instead looking nervously at her teammates. Naruto was amazed when he realized she was worried they wouldn’t like it. “Hinata!” he said suddenly, making her jump.

“Hai!” she squeaked, and Naruto nearly laughed out loud at the expression on her face.

“What did you use on this rabbit?” he asked.

“Just some herbs I found,” she answered hesitantly. “Did it turn out bad?” she asked, her face falling.

“No! No! No! It’s really good!” Naruto quickly assured her. “I wasn’t really looking forward to dinner until I smelled it cooking!”

“Naruto is correct, Hinata,” Shino added, making Naruto jump a little when the normally silent boy spoke. “It is surprisingly flavorful.”

Hinata just blinked, and a slow flush crept up her cheeks.

“They are correct, Hinata,” their sensei added. But then she frowned. “But that does not mean you should always be stuck with the cooking. We should rotate tasks while we are on a mission.”

Naruto frowned at his teacher for a moment. Then his eyes widened and he turned toward Hinata. “I’ll do the wood gathering and water collection when it’s your turn if you’ll cook when it’s my turn,” he offered.

Shino turned toward Naruto and nodded after a moment’s silence. “I will take your turns setting up the tents and hunting,” he offered.

Hinata’s blush grew darker, but Kurenai’s voice cut in. “I expected better from both of you,” she said in a frosty tone.

“Ano, Sensei,” Hinata said quickly. “It’s all right. I like to cook.”

Kurenai didn’t say anything else, but she gave both Naruto and Shino several dark looks as they consumed the skewers in silence. As they finished, Naruto gathered up the plates and utensils, and then bowed formally to the seething jonin. “Sensei, with your permission, I will demonstrate that I have mastered casting the water gathering jutsu at an appropriate strength level.”

Kurenai eyed him for a moment, but then nodded.

Naruto carried the plates off into the woods. As they stepped away from the camp, he said “I don’t want to get any of our equipment wet if it misfires or runs down the hill.”

However, he led his teacher a lot further from the camp than was seemingly necessary. Finally, he stopped and set the plates down on top of an old log and turned back toward Kurenai. “Before we do anything else,” he began, “I’d like to explain why I asked Hinata to trade tasks with me.”

“There’s a reason besides feeling like she should cook for you?” Kurenai asked coolly, “Or is there something else?”

“I cooked for myself almost every day,” Naruto said, scowling a little. “But Hinata’s really good at it, and I think it’ll make her feel better.”

Kurenai looked a little puzzled. “Explain,” she said. It didn’t really sound like a request, either.

“I’m not really sure why,” he admitted, “but it just seems to. Maybe because she’s so good at it, and she likes to do something she knows she’s good at? When we started training together in the evenings, she began bringing these really huge bento and insisted on sharing her dinner with me. I figured out after a while that she always brought more than enough food for both of us. I never asked her to do it, but she seemed happy when I thanked her.” He scratched his head. “I’m not sure what happened with her training the night before we left Konoha, but I’m hoping letting her do the cooking will make her feel better. We just need to make sure she knows we like what she makes.”

Kurenai just looked at him for a long moment. “I owe you and Shino an apology, it seems.”

Naruto just shrugged. “But it is true that she’ll do a better job than I will,” he said, with a small grin.

Kurenai smiled as well at his small confession. “That was fairly perceptive of you, Naruto,” she said approvingly.

The boy just shrugged, though his cheeks reddened a little. “Maybe, but I’m not perceptive enough to figure out what’s going on. There’s something… wrong, isn’t there?” he asked.

Kurenai took a deep breath. “Perhaps,” she allowed, “but I am not permitted to say.”

Naruto frowned. “I don’t know what to do,” he finally said.

Kurenai thought about his obvious concern for his teammate, and wondered if Hinata had noticed it yet. “I think it will come to you,” she finally said. “Now, you were going to demonstrate your mastery of a certain jutsu?”

Naruto shook his head suddenly. “Hai,” he said as he turned toward the plates and spread them out on the stump. “Suiton: Gyoushuu!” he barked as he finished the seals.

A stream of water an inch and a half wide shot out of the chakra vortex that appeared in front of Naruto’s palm. Though the stream did flow a bit quickly, it nonetheless rinsed off the plates and utensils without scattering them into the undergrowth.

“Much better,” Kurenai said approvingly. “Was it difficult to keep it under control?” she asked.

“A little,” Naruto admitted. “Is it because of… you know?”

Kurenai sighed and nodded. “I think so. But try to look at this positively. In the long run, I think it will be easier for you to learn to release chakra in smaller quantities than it would be for one of your classmates to build up a chakra capacity like yours.”

Naruto frowned. “I suppose so,” he said slowly. “Now I need to figure out the appropriate amounts of chakra to release for every jutsu I know.”

“I can help you there,” Kurenai assured him. “And if you are not overloading them every time you use them, you might find that they will misfire less often.”

Naruto looked thoughtful as he gathered up the plates. “That’s why I couldn’t make a decent Bunshin for my genin exam, wasn’t it?”

“But you can produce a horde of Kage Bunshin with greater reliability because it requires much more chakra… and therefore you aren’t overloading the Jutsu as badly. That would make sense,” she concluded in a thoughtful voice.

“Some times I want to just jam a kunai through that stupid seal,” Naruto growled, “and see how that damn thing likes being messed with.”

“I do not think that would be a good idea,” Kurenai-sensei said in a very quiet voice. Naruto looked up and realized her face had become pale.

“I don’t mean I want to cut my belly,” Naruto said quickly. “I’m just tired of this thing messing up my life.”

“Then the best revenge is living well, isn’t it?” Kurenai asked.

Naruto looked thoughtful again as he shook the water off the plates and stacked them up. “I suppose it would be,” he agreed.

By the time they returned to the campsite, Shino and Hinata had retired to their respective tents. With the watch rotation, Kurenai was to take the first shift, so Naruto went to his tent.

Shino was already in his sleeping bag, with only the top of his head visible. “Why exactly do you want Hinata to do all the cooking? I assume there is a reason aside from her considerable skill,” the boy said, his voice slightly muffled.

“I think it might make her feel better,” Naruto said as he removed his jacket and unzipped his patched bedroll. He didn’t bother to remove the weights. “Just make sure you let her know how good it is.”

“It was unusually well-prepared, especially given the conditions,” Shino agreed. “So this is intended to build up her confidence?”

Naruto was silent for a moment as he stretched out and tried to get comfortable. “I suppose so. Something’s bugging her though. That family training thing seems sort of messed up.”

“The Hyuugas are a highly respected clan,” Shino reminded him.

“Like the Uchiha?” Naruto asked, thinking about their last encounter with Sasuke.

“Point taken,” Shino agreed.

The night passed uneventfully, and in the morning they ate the rest of the rabbit. Oddly enough, it was even better cold, and Naruto noticed Hinata blushing a little each time he made a happy sound as they ate. He watched out of the corner of his eye, hamming it up a little, and wondered why he found it so fun to tease the quiet kunoichi.

After they broke camp and resumed their journey, Naruto asked his sensei for another jutsu to practice as they walked. After a moment’s thought, she agreed. But only if he could perform the water-gathering jutsu ten times without a slip.

The first time, he failed on the ninth attempt, but after that he was able to produce ten without a hitch. Kurenai-sensei agreed that he had, indeed mastered the jutsu along with his teammates, and they took a short break from walking while she demonstrated a new technique.

“Now this is a combat Jutsu,” she said in a serious voice after showing them the seals. “Be very careful how you use it. This was supposedly developed in Cloud Country, by shinobi who were very impressed by the Jyuuken techniques. Rather than forcing chakra out of your hands when attacking, this allows you to convert a small amount of chakra into electrical energy, and keep it confined to your hands. If you strike an opponent while this is active, the electrical energy will arc into your target, causing some additional damage.”

After asking her students some general questions, Kurenai sighed and launched into a lengthy explanation of electricity and how it behaved. Naruto found it a little confusing, but tried to take it all in. After all, he might have to fight someone using electrical attacks someday.

“So metal armor won’t stop it very well, unless it’s insulated,” Naruto repeated back, “and don’t use it in water unless I want to shock myself.”

Kurenai nodded. “I can’t believe they didn’t cover basic physics at the academy.”

“Ano,” Hinata asked, “is it that important for shinobi?”

“There is no such thing as useless knowledge,” Kurenai said in a very serious voice. Then she smiled. “While we walk, I will tell you how a lack of such knowledge caused a jonin to be defeated by a very junior chuunin.”

Naruto understood, as his sensei told her story, that she was trying to teach them all something – and probably him in particular. What he didn’t understand was why his previous teachers couldn’t make their lessons as interesting as she did. He tripped and stumbled twice over ruts in the road, barely catching himself before he hit the ground, as Kurenai described the desperate struggle.

When Kurenai’s tale reached its conclusion and the wounded female chuunin grabbed her opponent’s manriki-gusari and shocked him unconscious, Naruto couldn’t help but leap into the air and cheer in a loud voice.

“I’m gratified that you found the story entertaining, but does anyone remember what we were discussing?” Kurenai asked acerbically.

“Your opponent was ignorant of the conductive properties of steel,” Shino replied, “and did not understand that every time he attacked you with a metallic weapon, he was inviting an electrical counterstrike.”

“I did not say the kunoichi involved was myself,” Kurenai corrected modestly.

“You were not? I would find it hard to believe someone not involved in the fight could recall the pertinent details,” Shino replied in a reasonable tone.

Kurenai inclined her head in acknowledgment, but did not speak further.

Naruto practiced the seals as they walked. According to Kurenai, the Jutsu required a minimum chakra five times larger than the water gathering one. However, since the seals required both his hands to perform, Naruto had to discharge the electricity before he could try again. He accomplished this by stepping off the side of the path and slamming his palm into the trunk of the nearest tree.

The first time he did this, Naruto was disappointed by how little the tree reacted. The bark was totally unmarked, and he began wondering if he’d put the correct amount of chakra into the technique. So the next time he tried it, he increased the chakra, but it still left the bark unmarked.

Naruto frowned and pumped a little more chakra into the next attempt. There was a faint crackle when he slapped the next tree, but no other effect. Naruto scowled in frustration. “Raiton: Shokkingu Haji!” he growled and really pushed some chakra into it this time. Now, the palm of his hand glowed with a bright golden light and a crackling that would drown out angry Kikai bugs filled the air. Naruto let out a whoop and slammed his palm into a tree trunk, even as Kurenai shouted behind him.

There was a bright flash, followed by a thunderous crack, and Naruto found himself picked up and flung bodily through the air. He slammed into the ground, knocking the breath out of his lungs as he slid through the undergrowth, wondering why his face hurt.

A few minutes later, Naruto was sitting cross-legged on the ground, being lectured.

“I can’t believe you could be so irresponsible!” Kurenai fumed. “You could have killed yourself!”

“Ano,” Naruto said, wincing as Hinata pulled another splinter out of his cheek. The flash made him screw his eyes shut which probably saved his eyes. His heavy jacket, gloves, and hitai-ite also blocked the majority of the wooden shrapnel. He was glad of that, because the few bits that lodged in his flesh hurt badly enough. “Sensei, why did the tree explode like that? Every time I hit one before that, I didn’t even leave a mark.”

Kurenai stared at him for a moment. “Naruto, trees are grounded. Small electrical charges shouldn’t damage them at all.”

“Then why did that last one explode?” he asked.

“Because you put far too much chakra into that technique!” she snapped. “So much electrical current passed through the wood that it super-heated the sap inside, converting it into steam, and made it explode! That’s what happens when lightning strikes a tree!”

“Really?” Naruto said, smiling despite the blood smeared on his cheeks. Hinata put away her tweezers and silently handed him a damp cloth. “That’s great!”

Kurenai spun on her heel and quickly walked away.

“It would be great,” Shino observed, “provided you manage to avoid blowing yourself up in the future.”

“Well, yeah,” Naruto said as he wiped off his face.

Hinata pulled out a small jar of medicinal cream, but the tiny punctures appeared to have closed on their own. She frowned slightly as she put the jar back into her bag.

Naruto stood up and dusted himself off. “Arigatou, Hinata-chan!”

Hinata ducked her head and blushed at the familiar form of address.

“Perhaps you should refrain from practicing any more jutsus until we reach the border,” Shino said as they donned their backpacks.

“What are you, sensei now?” Naruto grumbled. He thought the Raiton Jutsu had totally kicked butt. It wasn’t his fault he didn’t know trees would explode.

“No,” Shino replied, “but our orders are to relieve Dariketsu’s team before nightfall today, and we’re going to be late if there are any more delays.”

Naruto looked up at the late afternoon sun and cringed. “Oi! Let’s get moving!” he shouted and set off down the trail again.

The sky was beginning to darken in the East when Kurenai called a halt.

“What is it, Sensei?” Naruto asked. He hoped she wasn’t going to announce that they had failed. They had to be close to the border by now!

“Something…” Kurenai said, looking around. “Hinata?” she called out.

Naruto spun toward his teammate who’d been on point. She was no longer there. “Hinata!” he yelled.

Kurenai cocked her head to the side. “It’s subtle, but… Naruto! Chakra Pulse!” she barked.

Naruto realized that his sensei must have sensed a Genjutsu and immediately began pushing his chakra inwards, compressing it into a small, hard ball. Whoever had done this must have cast it between Hinata’s Byakugan scans. While removing Hinata before she could detect the Genjutsu made tactical sense, it still infuriated Naruto. “Naruto Majutsu: Chakra Pulse!” he snarled when he felt like he was about to explode. He released the pulse.

The trees around them wavered as the chakra shockwave passed through them. Three of the trees were replaced by figures in dark cloaks. An arm protruded from one of the cloaks, holding up Hinata, who sagged limply like she was asleep.

Naruto was about to charge forward when Hinata’s eyes shot open and her body twisted. Her hands flashed toward her captor’s arm and suddenly she was spinning through the air like a doll thrown by a careless child. Hinata twisted in midair, stabilizing her tumble, and managed to land in a crouch next to Shino.

Naruto stepped forward, his hands falling into a familiar seal. “Kage Bunshin no-” he began, but stopped when he felt Kurenai’s hand grip his shoulder. How had she gotten behind him so quickly?

“Aren’t you a little old for playing games, Dariketsu?” his sensei asked in a very disapproving voice.

The middle figure snorted and threw back his hood. Dark hair was drawn back into a short pony-tail and even darker eyes glared contemptuously. “They have you on babysitting duty, Yuuhi?” he drawled, smirking.

Naruto ground his teeth together, but felt Kurenai’s hand tighten even further on his shoulder and subsided. Her fingernails felt sharp.

“Hardly,” Kurenai replied in a frosty tone. “You’ve been recalled to Konoha,” she said as she pulled the red-sealed scroll out of her vest and tossed it to the shinobi.

The man’s eyes widened. “Is this some kind of joke?” he asked as he cracked open the seal with a small flash of chakra.

“No,” Kurenai replied. “The Hokage is tired of your bumbling. You’re supposed to be securing the border, not provoking the Iwa ninjas for your own amusement.”

“And you and these brats are going to do a better job? Have you lost your mind?” Dariketsu demanded, his face growing redder by the second.

“We are more than sufficient to achieve our objectives,” Kurenai said coolly.

The man snorted. “The smallest Hyuuga I’ve ever seen, one of those bug users, and… is that, him?” he asked.

Naruto felt his stomach drop and he watched his teammates from the corner of his eye. He wanted to jump this idiot and pound him before he said any more, but Kurenai-sensei’s hand was like an iron band around his shoulder.

“Yes, this is the infamous prankster Uzumaki Naruto, though his pranking days seem to be over,” Kurenai replied. “He understands that shinobi are bound by the Hokage’s laws, no matter where they are.”

Dariketsu’s eyes narrowed as they flickered from Naruto to his teammates. He turned his head and spat. “Fine, we will report to the Hokage. Try not to get murdered in your sleep by some bloodthirsty animal,” he said in a sardonic tone. “Brand, Chusei, let’s strike camp and leave these ‘shinobi’ to their mission. The sooner we leave, the sooner we get some warm sake in us.”

A wind sprang out of nowhere, causing their cloaks to flap in the mysterious breeze. Then they were gone, with only a swirling torrent of wind-blown leaves to mark their place.

“Baka,” Naruto growled.

7

First Blood

Because they were to patrol a couple of miles within the border, Team 8 was required to set up their own camp well back from the boundary with the Land of Earth. Kurenai merely shook her head when their first patrol discovered the subtle traces of Dariketsu’s camp. They had claimed a small clearing within sight of the actual border. Naruto supposed the Hokage had been right… those idiots were spoiling for a fight if they did that.

Naruto tried to pay close attention to how Kurenai-sensei had them do things, because there was almost always a reason behind it… like the way they randomly varied their patrol patterns to make it harder for someone to slip by them undetected. It was embarrassing, but sometimes he did have to ask her why. At least she didn’t berate him for being stupid when she answered his questions.

Instead, she seemed pleased that he wanted to know. Not knowing why she did this began to bother him until he finally had to ask her about that as well. Some instinct made him wait until Hinata and Shino were sparring after dinner, because he wasn’t sure what the answer would be.

Kurenai kept her eyes on her students as they fought. Running the patrols was helping their speed and endurance, but she said she still wanted them to train a little when they took breaks. If their bodies were too tired, she would go into what Naruto recognized as her “lecture mode” and talk to them about things they needed to know. Those were usually interesting, but it was another time when she also welcomed questions. Why was this so?

“Ano, Sensei,” Naruto said in a low voice as Hinata slapped aside Shino’s punch and made a strike toward his midsection that forced him to quickly backpedal. She still wore the weights, but they were slowing her down less and less. He wondered if she even noticed this.

“What is it, Naruto?” Kurenai replied.

“Er, I’ve been asking a lot of questions lately,” he said, but his voice trailed off. How could he say this without sounding like a fool?

“Yes,” she said, her eyes still on the combatants, “I’m glad you’ve been taking a more active role in learning strategy and tactics.”

“But that’s just it,” Naruto said, the words tumbling out easier now. “Why are you so happy that I’m asking all these questions? Almost all the teachers at the Academy got mad when I ask questions!”

“Everyone but Iruka?” she asked softly, Shino used his greater reach to force Hinata to retreat again.

Naruto shrugged. “Iruka’s different. He grew up without parents like I did, so he cuts me a break.”

“No,” Kurenai said firmly, “he’s not. He’s doing his job properly. Evidently, he’s one of the few instructors that is.”

“Nani?” Naruto asked, his eyebrows drawn together in confusion.

Kurenai sighed. “Naruto, why do you ask those questions? Are you seeking attention? Are you trying to delay me so I don’t start talking about a new subject? Or are you simply trying to irritate me?”

“No Sensei!” Naruto said quickly, “I just asked because I wanted to know!”

“Exactly,” Kurenai murmured as Hinata leapt over Shino’s leg sweep. “A student that actually wants to learn is a blessing to a teacher. Why should I want to discourage that?”

“But… why didn’t the instructors want…” Naruto’s voice trailed off. “It’s because of me, isn’t it?” he asked coldly.

“Not precisely,” Kurenai said in a voice little more than a whisper. “Naruto, I’m not going to excuse their behavior, but I think it might help you to understand. When the Kyuubi attacked, it was like a natural disaster. It was unstoppable. I was miles away from the battle and I could still feel… it. More chakra and killing intent than I’d ever imagined was possible to exist. I’d never been more afraid in my life, and I imagine that was true for everyone else in Konoha. Then it was defeated, but at the cost of the Yondaime’s life. It’s hard explain how much we all loved the Fourth Hokage, but I think any one of us would have given their lives in his place, were it possible. But he was gone, and so was the demon responsible for his death. Everyone was angry and grieving for the Hokage and everyone else who’d died… and there was no real outlet for that grief and rage. I know the Third and Fourth Hokages wanted you to be seen as the savior of the village, but I don’t think it was possible, not with everyone still full of rage. Especially since there was really only one obvious outlet for that rage…”

“Me,” Naruto finished her sentence dully. After another quick exchange of blows, Hinata and Shino sprang apart, panting.

“It’s hard to break an ingrained habit,” Kurenai said, slipping into her lecture-mode for a moment, “but once someone does manage to see the real Naruto, they don’t go back to seeing you as a demon, do they?”

“No, they don’t,” Naruto said with a sigh. “But I was at the Academy for years, and it seems like Iruka is the only one that bothered. All of the other instructors were just trying to get back at my prisoner by making me feel stupid.”

“As I said, I will not excuse their behavior,” Kurenai agreed, “but I also know that Iruka really does care about you. When he heard about the spy, he thought I’d ordered you to fight… until I explained, he looked like he wanted to kill me.”

Naruto was mortified that Iruka almost attacked another shinobi because of him, especially a jonin. Oddly enough, he also felt a strange warmth to know that the man cared about him that much. “G-gomen,” he choked out, apologizing.

“No need for apologies,” Kurenai said. “I’m glad to see the truth of his feelings. We had a very productive conversation, and I think I may be able to call him a friend in the future. But do you realize why my attitude toward questions may be somewhat at odds with what you have previously experienced?”

Naruto looked puzzled for a moment and then nodded. “Because the others wanted me to stay ignorant and fail as a ninja… that was the only means they could see for getting even with the Kyuubi.”

“That is an accurate summation,” Kurenai said as Hinata landed a solid hit on Shino’s shoulder, making him stumble backwards. “Understanding and teasing apart the motivations of others, based upon indirect observations, is a valuable skill to cultivate for a shinobi. Even more so for a Hokage.”

“Everything is a lesson with you, isn’t it?” Naruto asked, half-jokingly.

“Of course,” Kurenai replied softly as she stood up. “We have a lot of ground to make up, and I am responsible for your education now.”

Naruto blinked as he absorbed that statement. He barely listened as Kurenai gave a detailed critique of the sparring match they’d just watched together.

Things were quiet, at least at first. When Kurenai was satisfied that their stamina and chakra reserves were up to the task, they began following their patrol routes through the tree cover rather than on the ground. After mastering the difficult water-walking exercises, using chakra to keep their footing on tree branches was easy. One evening he asked Kurenai-sensei why he’d started with the water-walking first. She said that, as uneven as his control was, she didn’t want him to fall on his head when training by himself. Naruto thought this made sense to him, but he didn’t understand why sensei glanced toward Hinata when she said it.

Before the day was over, they were leaping from tree to tree, subtly boosting their leg strength with small amounts of chakra to improve their leaping distance. Even with his weights, Naruto could make a twenty meter jump from a standing start, without really straining himself. He did, however, make sure he aimed for branches that were sturdy enough to handle his extra weight. Getting dumped on his head once was enough.

While this method was faster, Kurenai cautioned them to not use it in hostile territory, or when they feared they would be ambushed. It was damned hard to dodge a thrown kunai when you were in mid-leap, and landing on an explosive tag can ruin your whole day.

With a little subtle begging, Naruto also persuaded Kurenai to show them some more jutsus. It had been embarrassing to admit it at first, but she also showed him why he had so many problems using the body substitution technique, Kawarimi no Jutsu. It worked some times, like when he ambushed Sasuke-teme, but it failed more often than not.

As he suspected, he’d been throwing far too much chakra into the technique, which surprised him at first. He thought moving your body in the blink of an eye, and replacing it with a nearby object would take a lot of energy. Kurenai-sensei merely shook her head and explained that if the common shinobi technique required as much chakra as he used, it would kill anyone weaker than a jonin who tried it.

It was a little disturbing to realize just how much more chakra he had available than other… well, normal ninjas. Of course, as Kurenai pointed out, as bad as his chakra control was, he wasted so much that it wasn’t that obvious. But in the same breath she promised to work with him until he was as efficient as she was. Naruto couldn’t wait… he wanted to show everyone that he wasn’t just empty boasts.

Kurenai’s repertoire of ninjutsu seemed somewhat eclectic. She seemed to know techniques from a variety of styles. Sensei reiterated her motto of “there is no such thing as useless knowledge” when Shino asked her about it as she introduced them to a Doton jutsu. “Doton: Wana” let one mold chakra to influence the ground around their target. It required you to touch the ground as you released the molded chakra. But making the earth flow up around the target’s feet, slowing them down or trapping them, was really useful if used correctly.

This jutsu was especially tricky for Naruto, because if he molded too much chakra into the technique, the ground would liquefy around Kurenai’s feet, letting her merely step out of it. Fortunately, all the practice he’d had getting Suiton: Gyoushuu under control paid off here, and he mastered it almost as soon as Shino and Hinata.

He was a little puzzled when he finally got it right. Hinata was trying to apologize for something, but when he asked her what she did wrong, she wouldn’t tell him. Remembering Kurenai’s words, he just shrugged and smiled at her. “Whatever you did, I’m not mad at you. You’re a good person, Hinata, so I know you’d never do something to be mean.”

For some reason, she spun around and quickly walked away. Naruto turned to Shino with a questioning expression, but the bug user wouldn’t say anything. Again, Naruto had the oddest feeling that Shino was smirking at him. He hoped Kurenai introduced a Katon jutsu next, so he could ‘accidentally’ burn the collar off of Shino’s jacket.

On the second week of the patrol, Hinata’s Byakugan caught traces of swift movement at the edges of her range. They changed courses to track what had to be a shinobi and followed it all the way back to the border. As quick as they were, it still crossed back over the border before they could catch it, and Kurenai called a halt when they were still several meters short of the invisible boundary. Naruto noticed they were standing near the clearing that Dariketsu’s team had used as a campsite.

At the other end of the clearing, on the Earth side of the border, were four figures that seemed to be around Kurenai’s height. Naruto wondered which one had violated their border to lead them here. He looked left and right, his nostrils flaring, wary of an ambush. Hinata’s Byakugan were active, and some slight motion in the grass around Shino’s feet meant his bugs were deploying as well. A few seemed to have taken to the air after moving well away from their host.

“Have we satisfied your curiosity?” Kurenai called out.

“Somewhat,” the largest of the four Rock ninjas replied. They were all dressed in tans and neutral grays, and the lower portions of their faces were covered as well. “Though I am insulted that Konoha sends a group of children to match us.”

“We are not here to battle with you,” Kurenai said firmly. “The Hokage does not want any more incidents along this border. Dariketsu was recalled for that reason.”

“That’s too bad,” the Rock leader yelled back with an evil laugh. “He was fun to bait, if a bit too predictable.”

Naruto didn’t really want to draw attention to himself… but he’d become rather warm during the extended chase through the trees. He slowly unzipped his heavy jacket so the cool morning air could cool him down.

As slight as that motion was, it still drew the attention of the Rock shinobi. Naruto froze as he felt sudden spikes of killing intent, radiating from across the clearing. His ears strained to catch the whispered words exchanged between the Iwa ninjas, but he could barely make out a few, such as “bastard”, “flash”, and “yellow”. It really didn’t make a lot of sense to him, but he froze in place, not wanting to provoke anything more until Kurenai said the word.

“I see your mission is not as innocent as I would have believed,” the Rock leader called out as they split up and disappeared into the trees. “You will not catch us unaware when you come for our blood.”

“Back into the trees,” Kurenai hissed. Naruto waited until Shino and Hinata were halfway there before he began backing out of the clearing. His senses seemed extraordinarily sharp, and he could almost hear the individual blades of grass flex under his sandals.

As he slipped through the trees, Kurenai caught his eye. Her frown faded as he quickly glanced at Shino and Hinata, verifying their positions. She nodded and motioned for them to follow her. As previously arranged, Hinata sped up until she was even with Kurenai. Her Byakugan was active and checked their path for ambushes or traps. Shino trailed behind them, and Naruto was a little farther back. If any of his team were attacked, he was in a position to see it immediately and counterattack. If he was targeted, Hinata’s all-around vision would let them know as well.

Kurenai-sensei led them on a circuitous route, doubling back many times to check for pursuers. Nothing more dangerous than a frightened deer was found, so eventually they returned to their camp.

“A-ano, Sensei,” Hinata said as soon as they stopped. “What happened back there?”

“I’m not completely sure,” Kurenai said, frowning.

“Their sudden aggressiveness is worrying,” Shino said gravely. Naruto could only nod in agreement.

“I could read their lips, a little, through their masks,” Hinata said, blushing. “What does ‘Yellow Flash’ mean?”

Kurenai stiffened at Hinata’s words, and then she turned and peered closely at Naruto. “I suppose… if they saw him at a distance… and no real clues for gauging his height…” she murmured. She let out a sigh as all three of her genin frowned at her in confusion.

“All right, I think I know what that was,” the jonin said. “You’ve all seen the carving of the Fourth Hokage on the cliff overlooking Konoha, right?”

They nodded.

“Well, from a distance, Naruto bears a passing resemblance to the Yondaime,” she continued.

“Did he have yellow hair like I do?” Naruto interrupted.

“Yes,” Kurenai replied. “And because of that, and a special jutsu of his, he was often known as ‘The Yellow Flash of Konoha’.”

“But why would Naruto’s resemblance to the Fourth Hokage cause such a reaction?” Shino asked before Naruto could.

Kurenai took a deep breath and sat down on a log they’d moved near the fire pit. “Well, as you know, there was a war between Konoha and the Hidden Village of Stone back before you were born.” She paused for a moment while they all nodded. “Before becoming the Hokage, the Yondaime was a jonin who fought in many battles. He was known for his clever plans and skillful leadership. It is suspected that the Rock leaders knew of this and wanted to draw him out. Shinobi historians don’t know for sure that the Iwa ninjas specifically targeted his students, but we do know that one was killed, an Uchiha named Obito.”

Kurenai paused, taking a deep breath. “Whatever they hoped to accomplish by killing the Fourth’s student, it did not succeed. After his remaining students returned to Konoha to recover, he returned to the battlefields and… well, by the end of the war, over half of the Shinobi of Iwagakure had fallen to ‘The Yellow Flash’ and the attacks he led.”

Naruto felt his mouth drop open in shock. That wasn’t something they’d lectured about at the Academy. “H-he killed half of the whole village?” he asked in shock.

“The shinobi, yes. We were at war,” Kurenai said gravely, “and that’s what happens in a war. Some people think the Sandaime is weak because he favors peace… I call them fools.”

Naruto shook his head. “They can’t really believe I’m the Fourth Hokage, can they? I mean, that’s crazy!”

Kurenai shook her head. “No, though scared people often believe irrational things. But they may think you were sent specifically to intimidate or provoke them. I don’t think the Hokage anticipated this reaction when he assigned us this mission. Hopefully, they will be encouraged to stay on their own side of the border for now.”

“If they do not, I will know,” Shino added. “They stood there long enough for at least one of my allies to climb onto each of them. Those were female kikai bugs, so I will quickly know if they get within scent range of one of my sentries.”

“Very good, Shino,” Kurenai said with a smile. “While they initiated this encounter by crossing over into Fire Country territory, we have gained far more than they in the exchange.”

Naruto remembered Kurenai’s words and tried to stay optimistic as he gathered wood for the cook fire. The thought of the heroic Yondaime killing people made him feel ill, but Kurenai was right… it was a war, and he supposed he didn’t have much choice. And neither would he, if war broke out again. He wondered who those fools were that Kurenai had talked about, and resolved to be a little nicer to the Hokage next time he saw the old man.

The blond-haired genin went about his chores, but he would think back on this conversation many times in the years to come.

The first hint of trouble came from Hinata, whose head snapped around while they were on a routine patrol.

“Sensei!” she hissed.

Naruto, who was in the process of leaping toward the next tree, caught himself with one foot still touching bark, so he increased the chakra in that foot and awkwardly recoiled back onto the bough. Hinata was looking to the right of their current course. “They are under a genjutsu,” she said as she shook herself and suddenly launched forward. Naruto watched four dark objects drop toward the forest floor from where she’d been standing and knew she’d discarded her weights.

“Hinata!” Kurenai barked, reaching toward the Hyuuga genin.

Naruto wanted to follow, but he knew he needed to see what was going on. “Naruto Majutsu: Chakra Pulse!” he growled as he hurriedly crammed chakra into his hara, and then practically hurled it in the direction Hinata had jumped.

The recoil nearly blew him backward out of the tree, and the bough his feet were chakra-glued to creaked alarmingly. But the ripple sped outwards, knocking a few leaves from the trees like a stiff breeze, and making several figures shimmer into view under a tree in the distance. Three adult-sized shapes swam into view, two of them carrying large bundles.

Naruto had no idea who these men were, or why Hinata was attacking them, but he wasn’t going to let her go alone. He jumped after her, Shino and Kurenai barely a step behind.

“Kage Bunshin no Jutsu!” Naruto called out, his hands forming the familiar seal sequence as he dropped toward the men. The three of them were joined by a score of clones.

The man on the left dropped his cloth-wrapped burden and began making seals, his fingers a blur. “Katon: Gurando Fenikkusu Kachuu!” he snapped, and a trio of fireballs sprang from his fingertips. They spiraled outwards, leaving trails of fire that grew ever wider as they spread. Shino and Kurenai avoided the worst of it, but the vortex of flames had been aimed directly at Naruto and his clones. Naruto threw his arms in front of his face at the last moment and tried to shift his chakra to protect his face. The heat that washed over him was intense, and he didn’t need to hear the multiple pops to know his clones had been destroyed. When he broke through the funnel of fire, the cool air beyond was incredibly sweet. He dropped to the ground in a crouch as he spread his arms again. His face felt tight and hot, and the smell of scorched hair was unbelievably foul, but he was basically in one piece.

“Damn, Kouro, you’re slipping,” the largest of the strangers said, “I thought you were going to cook that little bastard for dinner.” He was tall and heavily muscled, and wore only loose pants and heavy boots. His shaved head shone in the sunlight that filtered through the trees, and his cold black eyes gleamed like chips of obsidian.

The man on the right wore a blue and black uniform that contrasted with the fire-user’s red and black one. He was fending off Hinata with a staff made of gleaming ice, but was having some difficulty handling the weapon while trying to juggle the large bundle he was also burdened with.

Finally, he growled in exasperation and threw his bundle into the air and swung the staff at Hinata crosswise with both hands. The staff was little more than a blur, but the Hyuuga was even faster as she leapt upward, grabbing onto the bundle with both hands and swinging it onto her back as their combined momentum spun her into a tree trunk. Naruto gaped as her feet found purchase on the rough bark and she ran up the trunk in a continuous motion. She angled toward a large branch and began running along the underside of it without even slowing down.

“Dammit, we can’t let them delay us. Kill them all,” the large shinobi barked. An instant later, his hand flashed upward and deflected the kunai Kurenai had thrown at his face.

“With pleasure, taishou!” Kouro snarled, his hands flashing through seals again. “Katon: Kaenhoushaki no jutsu!” he said and a blot of flame shot from his hands toward the still smoldering Naruto.

“Suiton: Gyoushuu!” Naruto snapped as he ran through the seals. It was a little tricky, trying to align the condensation vortex along a vertical plane instead of a horizontal one, but he didn’t have to worry so much about holding back his chakra this time.

A spinning chakra vortex a foot wide opened up and the air around them became parched of moisture as a blast of water erupted like a fire hose, intercepting the flame blast.

Naruto looked away, blinking rapidly, as steam blasted across the battlefield. There was a loud grunt of pain that brought a fierce grin to his lips. He hadn’t missed. A flash of motion drew his eyes to the side.

When Hinata reached the end of the bough, she didn’t even slow down and instead launched herself toward the ground. She twisted in midair so that she absorbed the impact with her legs, cradling the bundle as she sank into a low crouch. A kunai flashed and the fabric parted to reveal a young girl, bound and gagged, with furious white eyes like Hinata’s.

“The other bundle is Konohamaru-kun,” Hinata said as she quickly cut her sister’s bonds. Kurenai’s eyes widened and she turned toward the package Kouro had discarded, but Naruto was even faster. His fists snapped up and he struck himself a sharp blow on each shoulder, and then threw his arms forward. From under the sleeves of his jacket, his forearm weights flew forward and struck the large ninja in the face, staggering him backward. The discarded weights fell to the ground, where they embedded themselves in the soft forest loam.

In a flash Naruto was running past the leader, whose fist made a crater in the ground inches behind him. Naruto silently thanked Gai and Lee as he grabbed the other bundle and slung it toward his sensei. Kurenai caught it without missing a beat, her kunai already moving.

Things were moving rapidly, too rapidly for him too keep track of. The guy with the ice staff was closing in to reclaim his prize, but Hinata stepped over her sister, leaving her a kunai to finish freeing her legs, and set herself in his path.

The staff flashed forward, but this time she was ready, and shattered it with a Jyuuken strike. A sharp shard left a line of blood along her cheek and Naruto bared his teeth in a feral snarl.

A ball of chakra-enhanced fire struck him in the back, knocking him to his knees as it tried to ignite the tough jacket material. Naruto somersaulted forward, feeling blisters rise on the back of his neck. He raised himself into a handstand, looking behind him. Kouro was starting another set of hand seals, but a volley of kunai from Kurenai made him abort that attack and leap backwards. Naruto saw the thrown knives imbed themselves up to the rings in the earth and silently reminded himself never to get his sensei mad. He flexed his arms and launched himself into the air, marveling at how much easier this was with half of his weights gone. He struck the quick-release catches for the leg weights as he tumbled, and then snapped his legs out straight to launch them at the flame user.

Kouro jumped backward to avoid those as well, hissing in frustration. But his annoyance was brought up short when a mass of kikai bugs swarmed up his legs and Shino’s right arm wrapped around his neck, laying a kunai across the front of his throat. The fire-user’s eyes widened and he froze in place.

“Good one, Shino!” Naruto crowed, then turned back toward the big guy. The leader was moving to help the ice-nin with Hinata. “Hey teme! I ain’t done with you! Doton: Wana!” He slapped the ground and the soil under the large man’s feet writhed and flowed up over his boots.

The largest ninja caught himself as he started to stumble. Then he turned toward Naruto and smiled. His skin took on a metallic sheen and his feet began to sink inches deeper into the ground. With a heave, he tore his feet free of the earth-snare and began striding toward the much smaller green-clad shinobi.

“Naruto! No!” a shrill voice yelled. Roughened as it was from the gag and whatever else he’d been through, Naruto could still recognize Konohamaru’s voice. “Don’t! He, he killed Iruka-sensei!”

Naruto froze in place. He couldn’t move, could breathe. He didn’t just hear that. He couldn’t have. It was impossible. He felt the blood rushing in his ears as his fingers curled into claws. His blood was turning into fire in his veins as his mind shut down.

He saw Hinata hesitate, jumping back from the ice user and turning toward him, her eyes wide. A quick jutsu from the blue-clad ninja launched a volley of ice shards at the Hyuuga. Her Byakugan still active, Hinata avoided or blocked most of them, but the last one struck the side of her head. She dropped to the ground.

Kurenai’s hands were a blur as she launched a volley of kunai. The ice-nin dodged and blocked, but still ended up with one jammed into his shoulder. Kurenai charged at him a blade in each hand. “Get out of here! Run!” she shouted at the children who were gingerly climbing to their feet. Konohamaru grabbed the Hyuuga girl’s hand and they ran into the forest.

“Now!” the leader said as he stomped toward Naruto, beginning to pick up speed.

A sudden roar of flames from behind him made Naruto turn, even as he spun away from a fist that nearly flattened him as it drove into the ground.

“I don’t need to use seals to do this one, boy!” Kouro smirked as his body was wreathed in flames. There was a loud crackling sound as Shino’s kikai bugs were incinerated. Shino himself was blown backwards off his feet, his right arm a mass of flames. Naruto continued sidestepping, trying to keep both of the bastards in front of him, and lead them away from Shino and Hinata. The fire user didn’t seem to be that interested in Shino, because he began flicking small fireballs at Naruto, making him jump to the side as they ignited the parched grass.

Shino rolled over and over in the grass, eventually smothering the flames as he rolled away from the clearing. The right sleeve of his jacket was burned away, and what Naruto could see of his arm was a mass of red that didn’t look good at all. Against all reason, Shino tried to struggle to his feet, holding himself up with his good hand. The ever-present sunglasses gone, the Aburame boy locked gazes with Naruto for a moment. Then his hazel eyes rolled back into his head… he slowly toppled forward and was still.

“Come on,” the leader said. “Cook this little brat and then we can triple team the jonin and get out of here.”

“I’d like to take my time with her and the girl,” the flame-wreathed ninja leered, “but it shall be as you command. Stand still, boy, and I’ll make this quick.”

Naruto froze in place. The thought of these two hurting his sensei and Hinata finished a process that began with Konohamaru’s shout, and gathered momentum as he watched Hinata and Shino fall. He felt something snap inside.

“I’LL KILL YOU!!!” he screamed and charged toward Kouro, whose eyes were suddenly wide. Everything seemed to be covered by a red haze, and Naruto vaguely realized that the Kyuubi’s red chakra was exploding out of his skin. He wondered if this meant the seal was breaking, but he didn’t really care as long as it meant he could stop them from hurting his friends.

The fire-user hurled fireball after fireball at the short ninja, who suddenly didn’t seem so ridiculous an opponent. The pronounced whisker-marks the boy could feel etching deeper into his face probably had something to do with that, along with the pronounced canines that were starting to draw blood from his lower lip. Naruto batted the flaming missiles aside with contempt, ignoring the sting in his palms that disappeared almost as soon as it registered.

As he leapt onto him, Kouro finished a series of frantic seals. “Katon: Okibi Shounetsujigoku!” he screamed as flames exploded outward from his body.

Naruto crashed through the flaming shockwave, feeling it as little more than a warm breeze through the haze of rage and the red chakra that seemed to feed it. He landed on Kouro and drove the shinobi to his knees as his hands locked around the bastard’s throat. The man’s hands tore at his wrists, but Naruto’s arms could not be moved. The fire storm around them gained in strength as the man’s struggles grew more frenzied. Naruto grinned, enjoying the weak man’s terror, but a flash of light grey in the corner of his vision seemed to nag at something in his mind. With a wrench, Naruto turned his eyes away from the intoxicating terror in the man’s eyes and looked to his left. The firestorm jutsu, heightened by mortal terror, was still expanding. Kurenai and the ice-nin, still locked in mortal combat, were forced to move away, but the flames were also creeping toward Hinata’s unconscious body.

Naruto felt like he’d been dunked in ice water. His head snapped back around and he broke the fire-ninja’s neck with one quick motion. He turned toward Hinata, but the metallic ninja was in his way, his face twisted into a rictus of hate.

An enormous fist cocked back and rocketed toward Naruto’s face, but he simply raised one hand and caught it. The man grunted and slammed his foot into Naruto’s stomach, picking him up and throwing him backward into a half-burned tree trunk.

“I don’t know what kind of freak power you have,” he snarled, “But I can turn my skin into solid steel! You have as little chance of defeating me as that stupid teacher that tried to protect those brats. I’m going to crush you, and then your leader, and then I’ll kill your little friends before I collect my prize… and there is nothing you can do to stop me.”

Rather than standing, Naruto raised himself onto all fours, balanced on his fingertips and the balls of his feet. In a flash, he drove forward, sending gouts of churned earth flying into the air behind him. The metallic ninja laughed and launched himself forward as well, his fist poised to crush the runty brat who dared kill one of his men.

There was a loud crunch as the two collided, and dust and debris filled the air around them. As it settled, one could see where a huge fist had smashed into the ground, flattening everything under it as it made a crater nearly six feet across.

A much smaller fist could be seen protruding from the broad metallic back. Blood poured out of the wound, joining the growing pool beneath the crouching giant.

Smeared with blood and dirt, Naruto levered himself out from between the dead man’s arm and his legs. He’d managed to beat the punch, letting it land harmlessly behind him as he slammed his fist through the bastard’s chest… but he hadn’t changed back from steel with death, and he was heavy as hell.

The blond genin finally squirmed free and looked for his sensei.

The ice user, whom Kurenai recognized from the Bingo Book as Lisuke the Ice Knife, was surprisingly skillful with his created weapons, and they’d exchanged over a dozen blows before Kurenai was fatally distracted by the burst of killer intent radiating from her genin. Was the Kyuubi about to break free after all?

Seizing his chance, the ice user bound her feet in ice. She instantly threw her kunai at him, but he’d anticipated that and ducked them easily. Another Hyoton jutsu bound her arms at her sides, rendering her helpless.

But rather than immediately kill his helpless opponent, the ice-nin watched in shock as the blond brat exploded with a ferocious red chakra and killed both Kouro the Flame and Kazuyo the Anvil. Turning toward the boy’s jonin, and now his best ticket to getting out of this alive, he laid the point of his ice-sword alongside her throat and hoarsely asked her the question burning in his mind: “What the hell was that?”

The answer came from an unexpected direction, a whisper from behind his ear as the helpless jonin in front of him wavered and disappeared. “Kyuubi no Kitsune,” was all it said, sounding almost scared. It was the second to last thing he ever heard.

The last was the dull scrape of sharp steel on bone as a kunai was rammed into the base of his skull.

Naruto breathed a sigh of relief as Kurenai-sensei’s genjutsu wavered and faded out… and the last of the kidnappers fell like a puppet with its strings cut. As the red haze disappeared, he suddenly felt horribly tired and sore. After a moment, it was all he could do to stay on his feet.

“Naruto?” Kurenai asked in a quiet voice.

“Hai, sensei,” he answered. “Something weird happened. I… I think it started to get out or something.” He shuddered violently. If Kyuubi was in danger of breaking out… He jumped when Kurenai put her hand on his shoulder. Why was she willing to stand so close to him?

Kurenai looked him in the eyes as she slowed her breathing and seemed to gather her thoughts. “Naruto,” she began, “from what the Hokage told me, your seal was designed to let some of Kyuubi’s chakra filter out into your own. Apparently you drew on that when you became afraid.”

Naruto nodded, not bothering to correct her. He hadn’t been afraid, he’d been furious. “If I’m not going to go insane and kill everyone, can we check on Hinata and Shino?”

“I’ll take care of that,” Kurenai said as she knelt down next to Hinata. “Can you track down Sarutobi Konohamaru and Hyuuga Hanabi?”

Naruto nodded and took a deep breath. “Konohamaru!!!” he yelled.

“Yeah?” a voice echoed from the trees nearby.

Naruto shrugged at Kurenai who had turned toward him, scowling. “He never does what he’s told to do,” Naruto explained.

“All right,” Kurenai said. “If you know him, reassure him that everything is all right, and keep an eye on Hinata. I think she’s just stunned, and I need to see to Shino.”

Naruto nodded and slumped down next to his teammate. He was worried about Shino’s arm, but Hinata looked so still, lying there like that…

“Naruto?” Konohamaru whispered. Naruto looked up, but he couldn’t immediately see the little brat. Maybe he wasn’t so bad at the camouflaging art when it was for real.

“It’s safe to come out,” Naruto said wearily. “We… we got them. We got them all. They won’t be hurting anyone ever again.” He tried to push Iruka-sensei out of his mind, but it wouldn’t cooperate. He’d never get to treat him to ramen like he promised himself he would, dammit.

The bushes to his left stirred and Konohamaru cautiously stepped back into the clearing, still leading the little girl who must be Hinata’s sister. The white eyed girl looked at Hinata’s unconscious form with a curious lack of interest. “She’ll be okay,” Naruto reassured her, “she just got hit on the head.”

“I’m not surprised she was defeated,” the girl said in a clear voice. Her accent was cultured like Hinata’s, but the coldness of her words made Naruto scowl.

“She. Was. Not. Defeated,” Naruto snarled, angrily biting off each word. “She charged in there and rescued you, achieving her objective. The ninjas that kidnapped you are dead and we’re all alive. We won.”

Konohamaru glanced uneasily from his rival to his fellow kidnapping victim. “Ah… that’s good, Naruto-san. I’m glad Kurenai-sama was able to defeat them.”

Naruto sat for a moment, looking down at Hinata. “What happened to Iruka-sensei?” he asked quietly.

Konohamaru looked down. After a moment he sniffed loudly. “I’m sorry, Naruto. They grabbed me at recess, but I saw them at the last moment and called out. Sensei tried to stop them, but… the big one hit him so hard, I heard his bones break. But Sensei kept trying to get up again…”

Naruto closed his eyes, remembering how Iruka fought so hard to save him from Mizuki. “That sounds just like him.”

“The b-big one kept hitting him until he stopped moving. I was tied up and couldn’t do anything, but they made me watch before they put me in the sack. Sensei w-wasn’t breathing,” the boy sobbed.

“He should have been stronger if he was going to interfere,” the girl snapped. “If he’d been properly trained, he would have stopped them and they wouldn’t have gotten away with either of us.”

“You shut your mouth!” Konohamaru shouted at the younger girl, making her flinch back like she’d been slapped.

Her face went red and her eyes narrowed. “How dare you! Do you know who I am?” the girl snarled.

“He’s the Hokage’s grandson, so I believe he outranks you,” Naruto snapped, “not even counting the fact that you are an awful brat. I can’t believe you are Hinata’s sister, or that she’d even bother to try and rescue you.” His revulsion and grief at what had happened was rapidly turning into anger, and this spoiled brat who badmouthed Hinata and Iruka-sensei was really asking for it.

He swallowed his anger with great difficulty and looked down at Hinata. Her breathing was slow and even. Concentrating on that seemed to calm him. He failed to protect his teammates, but at least none of them had died. Shino might be badly hurt though.

As his stomach twisted with worry, he heard footsteps approaching. Naruto silently rolled to his feet, bringing his hands up in a taijutsu stance. Konohamaru inhaled sharply, staring at Naruto’s right arm. Previously concealed behind the genin’s torso, it was coated with drying blood up to the shoulder.

Naruto wearily released his breath and nearly dropped to his knees when Kurenai helped Shino limp into the clearing. There were bandages wrapped around his right forearm, and the sleeve of his red shirt was scorched and seared where it protruded from the right arm hole of his jacket. Naruto blinked. Seeing that unexpectedly bright red shirt at a distance, he’d thought Shino’s arm had been burned far worse than it was. He felt a small smile tug at his mouth, the first since they’d left for patrol that morning.

Hinata stirred at last, rolling onto her side and clutching her head. Naruto carefully pulled a cloth from his belt with his left hand, wetted it down with his canteen, and wiped at the clotted blood along Hinata’s hairline.

His teammate’s eyes shot open and she winced in pain.

“It’s all right, Hinata,” Naruto said. “We got them. Your sister and Konohamaru are safe.”

Hinata seemed to relax slightly at this news.

“My name is Hanabi,” the younger girl snapped irritably.

“Your name will be face-in-mud if you don’t shut up,” Naruto replied with a glare.

“I-it’s all right, Naruto,” Hinata said quietly. “Hanabi, were you injured?”

“No, no thanks to you. Father will be furious when he finds out you were the first to fall.” Naruto thought the girl derived some weird sort of satisfaction from this pronouncement.

Hinata sat up quickly, and Naruto noticed she bit her lower lip and shut her eyes for a moment. He glared at Hanabi, but the girl didn’t comment. What the hell was going on with these two?

Hinata slowly climbed to her feet. Naruto thought she was barely keeping her balance, but some impulse kept him from reaching out to steady her. “If you are unhurt, we should probably return to our camp to regroup,” she said.

“That might be a good idea,” Kurenai said, glancing over at Naruto. “But we should moderate our pace for our guests.”

They set out for their camp, walking slowly along the forest floor. After a few minutes, Naruto felt his energy returning and he no longer had to concentrate to avoid stumbling. Of course, putting his weights back on didn’t help the situation.

Shino was right in front of him, along with the two young children, both of whom seemed to be a little afraid of the quiet bug-nin. Hinata was in the lead with Kurenai.

“Hinata,” Kurenai said, her voice carrying through the still air. “I understand that you were concerned about rescuing your sister, but do you think it might have been better if we devised a plan before attacking the kidnappers?”

“G-gomen, Sensei,” Hinata said, ducking her head apologetically. “I would have preferred to have done that,” she continued, her voice clearer than it usually was when she was embarrassed and apologizing. “But there wasn’t time. As fast as they were moving, if we didn’t immediately intercept them, they might have outrun us to the border with Earth Country.”

“I see,” Kurenai said thoughtfully. “I agree with your reasoning, Hinata. Your decisive action not only saved two lives, but it also prevented a diplomatic incident, if not a war.”

Hanabi let out a snort. Konohamaru shushed her, glancing worriedly back at Naruto.

Naruto didn’t say anything, but he could feel his upper lip curling. Hinata really had saved their butts… so why was her sister being such a brat about it?

The sun was setting and Naruto was very happy when they reached the camp so he could sit down for a moment… even if Hanabi didn’t seem to think much of it.

Konohamaru, on the other hand, thought it was ‘really neat’. Naruto knew he was training to become a ninja of the Leaf. Maybe this was a preview of what he might be doing in a few years when he’d have missions of his own. On the other hand, there was no telling what Hanabi’s problem was.

After a moment, he rose to his feet and made his way to the nearby stream. The blood came off his hand fairly easily, as did the bloody mud that stuck to his pants. But the blood in his jacket had soaked in, and he really had to scrub to get it out. The heavy fabric was waterlogged before he was done. He grimaced and carried the folded jacket back to the tents, planning to dry it by the fire.

The evening air was cool on his skin, and the breeze ruffled his black t-shirt as he walked toward the fire. Konohamaru looked up and peered at him curiously. “What’s that, Naruto-san?” he asked, pointing at Naruto’s wrist.

Naruto peered down at the rounded bracer of leather and metal. “Ah, that’s my wrist-weight. It helps me increase my speed and strength.”

Out of the corner of his eye, he saw Hinata look up suddenly, her expression chagrined. Kurenai wordlessly reached into her bag and handed Hinata her weights. Hinata accepted them with a blush.

Hanabi peered at him curiously. “What’s the point of slowing yourself down with those?”

She hadn’t noticed Hinata, for which Naruto was quietly grateful, so he answered her question, ignoring the tone. “If I wear these all the time, my muscles get used to moving with the extra burden… then when I really need it, I get rid of the weights and I move that much faster. Wearing these when you train is also good for building up your endurance.”

“You spar with weights on?” Konohamaru asked, eyes wide.

“Yeah,” Naruto said. “I learned about them sparring with an older shinobi named Rock Lee.”

Hanabi let out a laugh. “I know him. He’s that loud crazy baka that Neji-nii-san is saddled with on his team. I wouldn’t do anything he told me to do.”

“It was Gai-sensei’s idea,” Naruto said coldly, “who is Lee’s sensei and must therefore be this Neji’s Jonin sensei as well. Why don’t you ask your ‘Neji-nii-san’ if his Sensei is a fool? That man knows more about taijutsu than almost anyone I can think of.”

“NARUTO!” a loud voice cried out, making him cringe reflexively. “It warms my heart to hear you defend my teachings! You have truly not forgotten the fire of youth!”

“Gai?” Naruto gasped.

“Yosh, Sensei!”

“Lee…” Naruto said, rubbing at his eyes.

Gai and Lee leapt into the clearing, obviously practicing their “Dynamic Entry” jutsu. They were followed - less dramatically - by several ANBU in their distinctive animal masks, a large, rough-looking woman with red marks on her face and shaggy hair, a huge black dog, a man with long hair and white eyes, and a tall man with sunglasses and a large concealing full-length coat that had to be related to Shino. Tenten and a boy with the distinctive Hyuuga eyes rounded out the crowd.

Hanabi immediately ran toward the white-eyed man in long, flowing white robes. She quickly bowed before him and he nodded his acknowledgement. Hinata shakily rose from her seat and presented herself similarly… but her bow did not receive any acknowledgement.

The tall woman grunted and scratched the black dog’s ears. “I told you the kids had been released,” she grumbled. “Their scent trails held no hints of duress, and Kuromaru can always tell the difference.”

“I am… surprised that those three were bested by a team of mere genin,” the white-eyed man said. “It would be more likely that they had their prize stolen by Iwa-nin taking advantage of the Hokage’s laxness.”

Naruto scowled at that. Their counterparts across the border only tried something once… well, that they knew of. Still, they didn’t seem eager to test them after that first confrontation.

“However unlikely it may seem, Hiashi-sama,” the man wearing sunglasses replied in an urbane tone, “it would appear that those three missing-nins were, in fact, defeated by a genin team.” The man turned toward Shino. “To what extent were you injured?”

“I sustained first degree burns to my right forearm, with some second-degree tissue damage in one spot on the top of my wrist, along with mild smoke inhalation,” Shino replied in a curiously detached voice. But then he frowned enough for his eyebrows to become visible. “Unfortunately, I was surprised by a seal-less fire jutsu and sustained significant losses to my colony. I estimate my kikai-jutsu capacity has been decreased by sixty percent.”

The older man nodded slowly. “It was fortunate that you had not committed more of your reserves. However, when you accompany us back to Konoha, you can bind more to your queen to restore your colony.”

But Shino shook his head. “Unfortunately, our relief is not due for another three days.”

The large woman let out a loud bark of laughter. “I think the ANBU can cover for you for a couple of days. Your team looks like it went through a meat-grinder, you most of all.”

“A-ano,” Hinata said hesitantly, drawing annoyed glares from the two Hyuuga men that made her falter for a moment. “The Hokage ordered us to stay here until we received a specific written message,” she continued quickly, ducking her head.

Naruto blinked. He was honestly surprised that she’d managed to get that out… not to mention a little proud of his shy team mate. “Hinata’s right,” he said loudly, drawing the attention of the angry Hyuugas. Not that he cared – they were probably idiots like Hanabi, anyway.

Gai-sensei frowned. “Kurenai?” he asked.

“My genin have accurately summarized our orders,” she said, and the pride in her voice was unmistakable. “We would be failing to complete our assigned mission if we left the border now… unless you have specific orders from the Hokage?”

“Are you openly defying my authority?” the elder Hyuuga asked in a dangerous tone.

Kurenai lifted her chin. “Not at all,” she said coolly. “But our orders came from the Hokage, and only he may countermand them. You, Hiashi-sama, are not part of that chain of command.”

“No one wishes to usurp your mission, Kurenai-san,” Shino’s father said quickly, cutting off Hiashi and earning a glare of his own. “We merely thought your team was not in a condition to complete it.”

“Your concern is appreciated,” Kurenai replied politely, “but Hinata and Naruto are basically uninjured, and Shino’s mobility is unimpaired. Additionally, the Rock ninja appear to be… less than eager to test our defenses.”

“Were they scared off when we all arrived, sensei?” Lee asked Gai.

“No,” Shino answered, shaking his head, “they think Naruto is the Fourth Hokage and are therefore terrified of him.”

Naruto wanted to sink into the earth – without using a Doton jutsu – as the adults all turned toward him in shock. One of the ANBU snorted behind his mask. Naruto supposed Shino was getting payback for all the times he’d knocked him around during their latest sparring sessions. “Hey! They were standing a long distance away!” he grumbled.

“A very long distance,” the wild-haired woman agreed, laughing coarsely, “if they though you were the Yondaime!”

Naruto scowled and stuck his lip out. The patient, watchful corner of his mind that Kurenai-sensei had been encouraging him to develop noted the way his antics had dispersed the tension in the air. Most of the adults were smiling slightly, except Hiashi-teme, who was glaring at him, and the other genin looked bored. At least no one was glaring holes in Hinata, or acting like they were going to try to force them to abandon their mission.

“However,” the older version of Shino continued after a moment, “my son will still be operating with a significant handicap with his depleted kikai swarm.”

“My sentries are still in place,” Shino replied calmly. “While I may not have as much directed capacity, Naruto and Hinata’s capabilities have grown well beyond my projections. They will more than offset the deficit.”

Naruto was a little embarrassed that Hinata puzzled out their teammate’s words before he did, and was the first to turn toward Shino in mild shock. Was he actually praising their strength, in his own weird way? He found himself anticipating bragging about such an unexpected development the next time he saw Iruka-sensei… then his stomach tried to turn itself inside out and it was all he could do to control his facial expression.

“I am gratified that your first-hand observations have proven to be superior in terms of accuracy,” Shino’s father replied. “However, there may be another option. I will leave one of my smaller colonies with you, and replace it when I return.”

“A-a second colony?” Shino said, stammering for the first time Naruto could remember.

“Yes,” the man replied. “You are due to begin hosting a second group, as you are well beyond my own projections regarding your development. I commend your sensei for her suggested training regimen.” He paused to nod slightly toward Kurenai, who returned the acknowledgment, blushing slightly. “We have already discussed the theory behind managing multiple queens,” he continued, “just make sure their reproductive cycles do not conflict and you should do well.”

“Thank you,” Shino said as his father put a hand on his shoulder. Naruto tried not to make a face as a large number of bugs crawled out of the man’s sleeve and flowed over Shino’s collar. Just watching it made him itch between his shoulder blades. He knew Shino probably had him bug-tagged as a precaution – he just preferred not to think about it.

Naruto decided to casually look away before the compulsion to scratch became too strong. Gai-sensei caught his eye and nodded gravely. “I hope you are keeping up with your training,” he said. “Lee has already increased his weights again.”

Naruto grimaced. Crap… “I’ve sparred as much as I am able, but we’ve been working more on Jutsus and chakra control.”

Gai planted his fists on his hips and struck what he probably thought was an encouraging pose. “That’s all right, Naruto. You can practice those while you are away. Lee and I will get you back in shape when you return. I’ll also want to hear about your battle. Those missing-nins were serious opponents, and I’ll want to hear about your contributions to your team’s victory.”

Naruto made a face, but nodded and quickly changed the subject. There was a question that was eating at him anyway. “Er, do you think the, uh, funeral will be held before we return.”

Gai frowned in confusion. “We won’t hold a funeral for those criminals, Naruto. The ANBU will retrieve their bodies for study, but they deserve no better than that for what they did.”

Naruto shook his head. “No, I mean for I-Iruka-sensei,” he said in little more than a whisper. His throat was trying to close for some reason. Just saying it made it all too real.

Gai let out a laugh, which sparked a momentary rage in Naruto. “Iruka was badly injured, but he was found in time and brought to the hospital. Before the ANBU located the kidnappers’ trail, I was told that he is expected to make a full recovery.”

Naruto’s eyes widened. “YATTA!” he screamed as he leapt into the air, pumping his fists. All the others were staring at him, some of them with obvious distaste, but he couldn’t care less.

Gai, after a quick consultation with Kurenai, led his team on a quick circuit of the border zone “for practice” as Shino’s father, Aburame Shibi, finalized the colony transfer to his son. Hiashi stood at the edge of the camp, his arms folded in obvious impatience, as the rough-looking woman (who’d been introduced as Inuzuka Tsume, Kiba’s mother!), stood next to him, telling jokes to the silent ANBU; of course, she might have received more reaction if they had been good jokes.

Konohamaru joined Naruto in a relieved mixture of crying and laughter when he realized that he’d been wrong about Iruka. Hanabi looked like she was about to say something when Hinata suggested that she should report to their father. The younger girl looked sharply at her sister, her eyes widening slightly in surprise, but she didn’t say anything before she stalked off.

“I’m glad Iruka-sensei will recover,” Hinata said in a quiet voice.

“Yeah,” Naruto said. “I’m sorry I kind of went nuts when Gai told me.” He scratched at the back of his head as his face colored a little. Recalling the contempt of the Hyuugas’ faces made him scowl.

“Is… is it a bad thing to care about people, Naruto?” Hinata asked. “It’s not something… something you should be ashamed of, is it?”

Naruto frowned. Was she asking him or telling him? He wondered if she thought about that a lot. “I don’t know, Hinata. We were told in the Academy that shinobi are supposed to be emotionless, but Kurenai doesn’t seem to feel that way.” He recalled how she encouraged him to think of his teammates as friends to be protected. Even if that was his role on Team Eight, she didn’t seem to just think about it in that way. “That’s good, too,” he concluded after a moment, “because I don’t want to be a ninja like that, do you?”

Hinata smiled shyly, shaking her head as her eyes veered downward.

“You were worried about your sister, weren’t you?” he asked after a moment’s thought. Konohamaru still sat off to the side, listening quietly.

Hinata hesitated before nodding.

“When you grabbed her from that missing-nin… you should have seen how you moved, Hinata. You were incredible!”

“I was?” she asked. “I don’t remember… I just remember being scared she would be hurt.”

Naruto shook his head. “You grabbed her and ran up that tree so fast I could barely see you. In a flash, you had her behind Kurenai and were cutting her free. Do you think you would have done as well if you didn’t care?”

Hinata shook her head slowly.

“Good!” Naruto said, “and if caring about people is not the regular way for shinobi… well, we’ll just make our own way of the ninja, right?”

Hinata looked up, meeting his eyes for once. “Right!” she said, her normally velvet-soft voice carrying a hint of steel.

Naruto couldn’t help but smile at her fierceness, and she immediately looked away and excused herself, saying she needed to see about dinner. He frowned at her back as she walked toward the fire. What had he said wrong now?

He looked down at Konohamaru, whose face was scrunched up in a frown. “I like that nin-do, Naruto-san. I’m going to tell Oji-san that I want to follow that nin-do as well!”

Naruto made a chagrined face as Konohamaru stood up and walked over to get a better look at Tsume’s enormous nin-dog, Kuromaru. He didn’t want to think about all the trouble he would be in if people thought he’d corrupted the Hokage’s grandson into following some heretical nin-do. Of course, the aggravation it would give that stuck up ero-baka, Ebisu, might be worth it.

The blond genin sighed as he stretched before leaving to gather more wood to build up the fire. Hinata was preparing most of their stored meat and dipping heavily into the rice bag, using the largest collapsible pot to boil it. He supposed she was right to do so, if she planned to feed this many people.

Kurenai gave Naruto a pointed look as he returned with an armload of dead wood. She cut her eyes toward a very industrious Hinata and smiled slightly. Naruto nodded and left to get more wood. A lot more.

The campsite smelled rather appetizing when Team Gai returned.

“Your system of semi-random paths is very devious,” Gai announced in a grand voice. “It would be quite difficult for an intruder to anticipate your position at any particular time… especially if young Shino has made good use of his ‘little friends’, ha ha ha!”

Naruto did his best to show respect and not wince at Gai’s… humor. Shino and his father nodded at each other and stood up. Naruto’s ears could almost make out what sounded like a faint buzzing sound coming from them, but he couldn’t be sure.

Hinata was setting out their entire store of eating utensils, and Tsume was eagerly walking toward the fire when Hiashi’s voice interrupted them. “If the Aburames are done, we should leave now,” he said.

“Hey, she just fixed dinner for us!” Tsume objected.

“It will soon be dark,” Hiashi said in a patronizing tone. “We are very near a semi-hostile border. You may risk the Hokage’s grandson if you wish, but I do not want my heir to linger here any longer than necessary. Now that the Aburame is finished with his son, I insist that she be brought back to Konoha. With a full escort. Immediately.”

“Hiashi-sama is within his rights to make such a demand,” Shino’s father said in a very bland tone. Naruto glanced at Shino out of the corner of his eye. He had some suspicions about when Shino talked like that, and they were now being confirmed. “We will return now. Kurenai-san, we will report to the Hokage as soon as possible. Understand that I will advise him to recall your team immediately for a thorough debriefing. Try to record any words the kidnappers may have said or any clues as to the identity of their employers. The direction of their flight may not be a completely reliable indicator of their objectives.”

Kurenai nodded as the visitors all stood up. Naruto noticed Hinata hurriedly placed some of the rice balls and seasoned deer skewers into a folded cloth and quickly handed it to Tenten. The weary kunoichi smiled and bowed to the girl, as did Lee, whose stomach let out a low growl.

Naruto guessed they would be traveling fast, because the Hyuuga boy, Neji, picked up Hanabi and Gai lifted a protesting Konohamaru into his arms. They leapt into the trees, surrounded by most of the ANBU squad. Shibi, Hiashi, and the rest of Team Gai followed. Tsume scowled after them, but smiled when Hinata handed her another bundle of food. The jonin playfully mussed the girl’s hair as she thanked her, then she followed the others into the trees, Kuromaru loping into the woods below her.

Still, when she turned back around, the blushing Hinata looked at all the remaining food she’d worked so hard to prepare and her face fell.

“Well…” Naruto said, racking his brains for something to say to her. “More for us! I’m really starving, and Shino is eating for three now!”

In all honesty, the fight had taken a lot out of him, so he joined his team at the cook fire and proceeded to stuff his face. Shino and Kurenai also seemed unusually hungry as well. In the end, his stomach hurt, a little, but there weren’t any leftovers from the large meal. Hinata’s eyes had gone a little wide as Naruto continued to eat the simple, but well-prepared food.

When he was finally done, Naruto leaned back and patted his slightly distended stomach. He could barely move, and they’d have to hunt tomorrow, but Hinata was smiling, a little ruefully, at her teammates.

That night, as Naruto struggled to find a comfortable position to sleep in, he wondered about this new nin-do he and Hinata were going to follow. He’d need to think about this. A lot.

9

Returning to Konoha

Yuuhi Kurenai couldn’t recall ever being quite so relieved to see the familiar skyline of Konoha again. The only time that even came close was when she returned alone that time… but she’d been too numbed by the death she had seen to feel much of anything. She was annoyed to find herself unconsciously smoothing her sleeve, but the fabric wasn’t stiff with Mattai’s blood.

Perhaps Sarutobi was correct about her living far too much in the past.

She glanced back at her genin team, proud of the way they maintained their formation and remained alert. Only the occasional smile from one of them indicated that they weren’t still in the border zone.

Shino, of course, was as reserved and taciturn as usual, even disregarding how little of his face was visible. Hinata had been quiet since they’d received orders to return to Konoha, and her face seemed to settle into a mask as the gates appeared in the distance.

No, it was Naruto who was different. The blond genin had changed since the day he’d finally revealed the truth to his team mates. Kurenai wasn’t normally one to become overly smug, but she’d been exactly right about the effects of him opening up to Shino and Hinata. A weight, present for as long as she’d known him, seemed to have lifted from his shoulders. She knew that her acceptance of him had made a difference, but the acceptance of his peers, especially given the implications of the Hokage’s law, seemed even more crucial.

Rather than rejecting or fearing him, as the Sandaime seemed to fear, Hinata and Shino had accepted the presence of the Kyuubi within Naruto in as positive a way as Kurenai could have hoped. Indeed, if what she’d pieced together was correct, Hinata had reacted in a rather… violent… way to the implication that Naruto was a monster. Nothing else could explain the distant shout that had carried up from the stream.

Kurenai grew more concerned for her other students now. After her father’s abominable behavior at their camp, she wasn’t surprised that Hinata seemed to dread returning to Konoha. More surprising was the undercurrent of anger she seemed to sense in Shino. The boy was as quiet as ever, but his forehead, the only portion of his face fully visible, seemed to be furrowed with a frown more and more often. When she’d asked him if anything was the matter during a rest stop, he’d merely said that he was “being forced to re-evaluate his assessments of a large number of parties”. This was unusually opaque, even for an Aburame, but he seemed to be feeling an echo of her own anger regarding how Konoha dealt with… certain issues.

All the same, she needed to caution the boy to be circumspect. If her suspicions were true, there might be a deeper issue than simple bigotry – not something a genin should be directly involved in, no matter how talented he might be. She supposed she might be hopelessly paranoid, but she’d rather that than to repeat the mistakes of the past.

Maybe Umino Iruka would be ready for a visitor after they reported to the Hokage.

Aburame Shino let his body move automatically, his team mates and allies alert for danger, while his mind composed a list of people.

At the top of the list, of course, were his parents, especially his father. While he appreciated the strictures the Hokage’s law forced him to operate under, Shino did not appreciate the paucity of hard information that his clan had acquired before formulating their opinion of Uzumaki Naruto. He hadn’t missed the concerned silence among many of his relatives when his team assignment had been announced. Even more galling was the realization that he’d allowed their unreasoning distaste for the prankster to color his own opinions while they were both students at the Konoha Ninja Academy.

Shino did not know whether it was more annoying to realize he’d been wrong, or that he’d picked up their attitude without realizing it. Either way, it was past time for him to realign some peoples’ attitudes to make them more congruent with the reality of the situation.

In short, he was highly offended.

That was the only word that really fit. His clan had compromised the integrity of his logic and his objectivity. And that was completely unacceptable.

Not for the last time, Shino heard the low buzz as his new colony became agitated. He forced himself to let his aggravation abate. It would not do to upset his new allies.

Hinata felt her stomach contract with dread as the gates of Konoha appeared in the distance. She loved her village, but in this situation, she dreaded what the sight of it symbolized. Their mission was coming to an end.

The border patrol had been a dangerous, dirty, strenuous job. Her muscles still ached, with or without the weights, from the endless patrols they’d run. Despite bathing in the stream as often as possible, she still felt grimy, and her jacket was several shades of grey darker than when she left, due to the build-up of ground-in dirt. She’d been in dangerous situations more than once, and if it hadn’t been for Naruto, she would likely have died trying to rescue Hanabi.

Yet, it had also been one of the happiest times of her life.

It was puzzling at first, the joy she’d taken in such a difficult mission. It wasn’t until she thought back on her father’s visit to Team Eight’s camp site that it began to sink in. It was reasonable for him to join the pursuit of Hanabi’s kidnappers, and to make sure every means was used to secure her freedom and guarantee the safety of the Hyuuga bloodline.

Nonetheless, it had felt… wrong… for him to be there. The camp site that they had spent so much time preparing, the fire pit that had witnessed so many meals and idle conversations with her team… it felt violated by her father’s presence. When Hinata realized that she didn’t want him to be there, she was initially scandalized by her blatant disrespect. He was her father, and more importantly the head of the clan. She should have felt honored by his presence, however fleeting.

She tried to make him and the others feel welcome, preparing as good a meal as could be managed in such rustic surroundings, but she was too slow and that had been thwarted as well. Even now, her face burned at the thought of all the wasted food – the sign of a foolish host. She regretted it later, but she’d been gratified that Naruto and Shino ate so much, even as she realized that they were doing it solely to save her feelings.

Just thinking about her team mates made her wish they were leaving for another patrol, rather than returning from one. She knew she’d sleep better in the small tent she shared with Kurenai-sensei than in her soft bed in the Hyuuga compound. A place where no one wanted a failure like her.

Naruto’s heart sped up when he saw the gates of Konoha. Their mission was coming to an end. More importantly, everyone was returning under their own power. Shino’s burned wrist was hardly more than an annoyance at this point, and the larger boy made a point of sparring with Naruto more than once on the way back. Shino was a little careful how he blocked with that arm, but when Naruto found himself unconsciously easing up on his team mate, the bug user blew him off his feet with a side-thrust kick that drove the air from his lungs.

Naruto shook his head at the memory of rolling to his feet, gasping, only to see Shino standing in a taijutsu stance, right arm extended and making a “come get some” gesture with his fingers. After that he relaxed and went all out against his friend, and they were both thoroughly bruised within half an hour.

Friend. That word again. He wondered if Kurenai-sensei ever got tired of being right all the time. It made a huge difference to know that Shino and Hinata knew about the Kyuubi, and just didn’t care. Moreover, Shino figured it out on his own, and Hinata had guessed. His team mates would have to have been extremely dense or self-centered for him to be able to conceal his differences for much longer.

But they knew, and more importantly, they accepted him. He didn’t think he’d ever forget the shock when Hinata had just exploded like that. He never imagined that she could ever get angry like that, but watching her get absolutely furious on his behalf – that was an odd feeling. Unsettling… but nice.

However, as they returned to Konoha, the kunoichi became increasingly quiet and withdrawn. Naruto wasn’t the most perceptive shinobi in his class, but the change in her demeanor was more than obvious to him. It was puzzling, especially in its timing. They were leaving the danger zone now, and returning to a safe area – as safe as any village full of shinobi, that is. Naruto was looking forward to some civilized amenities involving heated water – ramen and showers – and he would have thought Hinata would as well. At least the showers anyway.

Instead she looked increasingly uncomfortable as they approached the gates. He wondered about some things he’d learned during their mission. Hanabi was a brat, of that there was no question. Naruto had no siblings, but he’d heard Kiba complain about his older sister often enough to realize that brothers and sisters didn’t always get along.

On the other hand, her father should have been proud of the way Hinata had rescued her sister. Instead, he and that jerk cousin of hers looked at Hinata like it was her fault Hanabi had been kidnapped in the first place. Naruto didn’t understand it. But he didn’t have to understand it to know he didn’t like it.

Uzumaki Naruto rubbed at the back of his head as he thought it over. Thinking like this wasn’t one of his strengths, but Kurenai-sensei had been pushing him more and more to see ‘underneath the underneath’. It was a really goofy phrase that meant trying to understand all the subtle undercurrents in a situation. It was a good skill for a shinobi to develop, because on a mission, unseen things could end your life. On the other hand, Naruto didn’t think it was supposed to be applied to understanding kunoichi.

But for all that, it wasn’t too hard to put together. He remembered how tired and sore Hinata had been from that special Hyuuga training, and how she seemed to revive once they were out in the woods. He remembered the long hours she volunteered to do extra training with him, and her embarrassed silence when he’d asked if her family wouldn’t object to her working so late and missing dinner. Combining that with the cold way her father had treated her at the campsite led Naruto to only one inescapable conclusion.

Hinata’s family sucked worse than cold ramen.

Naruto was about to congratulate himself on his perceptiveness when the natural follow-up question left him stumped. What could he possibly do about it? He didn’t think beating the crap out of Hyuuga Hiashi would help, even if he were capable of such a thing. Puzzling over this eroded any sense of triumph he’d gleaned from his realization. Furtive glances at his team mate seemed to confirm his guess, as her gaze seem to sink lower and lower toward the ground as she approached the walls of Konoha.

Naruto’s mood sank as well. Even though he thought he knew the source of the problem, he couldn’t think of anything he could do to help. He hated feeling helpless, especially when one of his friends was hurting, but how could he protect her from her family? He let out a sigh as they passed through the gates, causing Yuuhi Kurenai to glance back at him.

Maybe Kurenai-sensei will know what to do, he mused. A little weight seemed to lift from his shoulders at the thought. He’d never seen her at a loss before.

Well, maybe except for that one time with the Lee-Henge.

In accord with standing orders, no sooner had Kurenai reported to the Chuunin guarding the Hokage’s door than they were ushered into his office. The old man was concerned, but he still smiled as Team Eight filed into the room and stood before him. They stood at attention, but he waved over one of the Chuunin and folding chairs were brought for all of them.

“This may take a while, he explained. “But before we begin your official debriefing,” he began, setting down his pipe, “I want to personally thank you for my grandson’s safety. Konohamaru still grumbles about having to be saved by his ‘eternal rival’,” the old man paused, smiling as Naruto rolled his eyes, “but I can tell from his voice that it was a very close thing. I can’t tell you how relieved I am, or how proud I am that you are all shinobi of The Leaf.”

The three genin all looked down, clearly embarrassed from his praise.

The Hokage cleared his throat and asked Yuuhi Kurenai to make her official report. He listened intently as she summarized the events of the last few weeks, but he did stop her at some points for clarification.

“They mistook Naruto for the Yondaime?” he asked, both startled and alarmed at that revelation.

“That is correct, Hokage-sama,” Kurenai confirmed. “The Iwa shinobi grew quite alarmed at his presence, but they did not seek to test our vigilance again after that initial confrontation.”

Sarutobi rubbed at his chin as he pondered this. “A quiet border is a blessing, but I will send a communiqué to our representative in Earth Country to explain their mistake. I would rather they did not feel that we were provoking them in such a fashion.”

“Send them my grades from the Academy, oji-san,” Naruto said with an impudent grin. “Let them know they were scared of the ‘dead last’ in his class.”

The Sandaime was shocked by two things. The first was the fact that Naruto would make a joke about his poor grades in the Academy, something that had previously been a sore point with him. He couldn’t imagine him bringing that up, even for the opportunity to make someone else look foolish.

The other was the reactions of his team mates. The little Hyuuga girl turned toward Naruto, eyebrows drawing together and mouth half-opened. She hesitated, and the Hokage imagined that his presence was the only thing preventing her from protesting Naruto’s words.

Even more surprising was the Aburame boy’s reaction. He merely turned his head and glared at Naruto. Well, it was impossible to see his eyes, but his body language was unmistakable.

Naruto’s reaction supported the Hokage’s assessment as well, for he immediately flushed and scratched the back of his head, smiling sheepishly. “I was just kidding,” he mumbled. Beside them, Kurenai kept her face immobile, but her eyes were dancing with a mixture of pride and vindication. Sarutobi gave her a small nod of agreement. He was gratified to witness that Naruto was less defensive, and that he had made such loyal friends of his team mates. Perhaps one day the boy would be able to share his secret with others of his generation.

The light mood darkened as Kurenai began to describe the battle against the kidnappers. He was a little surprised to learn that the Hyuuga Hinata initiated the engagement, but her sensei made a point of explaining the rushed nature of the interception and how she fully supported Hinata’s reasoning. He also noticed Naruto nudging the girl, who was looking down and blushing.

“Yuuhi Kurenai is not one to lightly praise another’s logic,” the old man observed, making Kurenai grimace as the girl’s blush deepened. “The ability to make sound judgments on the spur of the moment is not one to take lightly.”

“Arigatou, Hokage-sama,” the girl said in a quiet voice.

As Kurenai described the battle, which had been as brutal as it was abrupt, the Hokage’s tension was only visible in a slight tightening of the weathered skin around his eyes. One of the hardest parts of this job, at least for him, was hearing about the battles of his shinobi after the fact, too late for him to do anything about it. The blood was already drawn, the lives ended. The only thing he could do now was try to draw as many lessons as possible from the now-concluded missions.

He winced internally when he learned of Shino’s burns, but the bandages on his arm were compact, and he did not seem to favor it. He grew alarmed for other reasons when he heard how Hinata was stunned by a lucky hunk of ice. With only Kurenai and Naruto facing three opponents…

“At this point,” Kurenai continued, “I heard Naruto shout as I fought Lisuke. He successfully drew on the Kyuubi’s chakra and used it to shield him from the flames so he was able to close with his opponent and…”

She stopped as the Hokage’s hand slammed down upon the desk. He stared at his jonin, wondering what had possessed her to break the law concerning… and then he noticed that her genin were all staring at him. And while they might have been startled by his outburst, they didn’t seem to have reacted to her casual mention of the nine-tailed fox.

“They already know,” Naruto said quietly, his voice sounding far too old for the energetic prankster he knew. “Shino figured it out on his own, and Hinata mostly guessed it. But I was the one who confirmed it, so no one broke your law.”

“And we did not run screaming into the night,” Shino murmured. Hinata frowned, and Sarutobi noticed her hand twitch, like she wanted to reach out to her team mate, but the motion ended almost as soon as it began, and he doubted anyone else even noticed.

“Naruto… ” the Hokage began, then stopped to consider his words. “It’s good to know that they accept you. Perhaps I was being too cautious when I made that law, but I decided to err on the side of caution regarding your future.”

Naruto looked up and locked eyes with the Third Hokage. “I understand,” was all he said, but it still shook the old man to his core. The boy’s eyes were an odd mixture of emotions: anger, sadness, and loneliness so poignant it shriveled his soul. But overriding all the rest was another emotion: forgiveness. Maybe there were better ways the whole situation could have been handled, but Naruto acknowledged that he’d tried his best.

It was both a liberating and a humbling experience. He wondered what else the boy had gone through during the mission.

Kurenai continued her narrative. He was a little shocked and saddened that Naruto had been put in the position of having to kill two of the kidnappers. But all that was forgotten when he heard the words “…and I learned that his psychological preparation at the Academy had been sabotaged. However, we were able to discuss what he should have learned, and…”

“Sabotaged?” he asked sharply.

“Yes, Hokage,” she replied. Her voice was calm, but her eyes were not. Naruto looked somewhat uncomfortable, but his team mates were staring at their Hokage, almost daring him to speak.

“Give me a written summary of his actions,” he said in a hard voice. “Once I have reviewed it, I will have him brought to Ibiki.”

“Thank you, Hokage-sama,” Kurenai said. Naruto and Hinata looked mystified, but the Aburame boy merely nodded approvingly. Sarutobi had little doubt that Aburame Shibi had acquainted his son with the names of Konoha’s important shinobi. The chief interrogation specialist would definitely be on his list, the old man mused as Kurenai resumed her report.

When she was done, the Hokage gave each of them a labeled envelope. “Here is your pay for an extended C-class mission,” he said. He then took out three more envelopes with official Konoha seals on them. “These are for the three missing nins that were eliminated,” he continued. “There were substantial bounties placed on their heads by their home villages, as well as other people they’d committed crimes against.” He gave one of the envelopes to Kurenai, and tried to hand the other two to Naruto, but the blond boy shook his head.

“Naruto,” Kurenai said gently. “You’ve saved some people a lot of trouble by your actions. It’s all right to accept this reward. For many of their victims, offering a bounty is the only way they can strike back at someone who had hurt them or their family.”

“That’s not what I mean, Sensei,” Naruto corrected her, his voice grave. “I understand the rewards, but these two shouldn’t be for me alone. We fought as a team. I mean, I wouldn’t even have seen them if Hinata hadn’t spotted them through their genjutsu, right?”

“Ano, Naruto, it’s all right,” the girl said hesitantly. But the boy just shook his head stubbornly.

“By the rules, Naruto struck the killing blows,” Kurenai observed. “But that means the money is his to do with as he will. If he wishes to share with his teammates, then so be it. I can get all three of these vouchers cashed and we can split the rewards.”

“Ah, sensei,” Naruto said quickly, “I didn’t mean you had to-”

Kurenai cut him off with a gesture. “I just happen to agree with you, Naruto. And am I not a member of the team as well?” She turned back toward the Hokage. “You will have a written report of my observations by tomorrow morning,” she promised in a tight voice.

The Third Hokage of Konohagakure dismissed Team Eight with a bemused smile on his face. He really should have talked Kurenai into taking a genin team long before now. He hadn’t seen a team that seemed so in tune with each other since…

It was hard, dreadfully hard, not to let other faces over-shadow the young ones before him. His own genin, that grew up to become the Sanin, the Yondaime’s first—and last—genin team, the Nara-Akimichi-Yamanaka trios that seemed to crop up in each generation… They were all unique, really. The human mind just tries to find patterns to make sense of life, even when there are none to be found.

But it didn’t require a historical perspective to realize that Kurenai’s genin had grown together as a team, and had done so to a greater extent than many experienced shinobi even realized was possible. Hatake Kakashi might understand, when he wasn’t too distracted by the ghosts of his past.

And while Kurenai had done an excellent job assembling her team, much like a skilled mason might build a brick wall capable of withstanding anything, the Hokage also realized something else. While Kurenai was the mason, Naruto was the mortar that held them all together. Their acceptance had given him something he’d always craved without even being able to understand why. But at the same time his awkward and often foolish demeanor masked a drive and a… wisdom… of a sort that the Sandaime only caught rare glimpses of during their infrequent talks. For someone with few real friends, Naruto was amazingly open and accepting. As he’d anticipated, once someone showed the boy some simple kindness, they discovered they’d also made a friend for life… one of surprising loyalty and determination.

The Third Hokage sighed and rubbed at his eyes. He got up from his chair and paced around his office, wincing at the pops and crackles as his old bones realigned themselves after sitting too long. He paused near the window and looked out across his beloved Konoha, toward the Hokage monument. His eyes lingered on the stone visage of his successor, and, sadly enough, predecessor as well.

“You did better than you knew,” the old man whispered before returning to his paperwork.

Oddly enough, Kurenai did not immediately dismiss them once they left the Hokage’s office. Naruto frowned a little when she said they had one more task to perform as a team, but that ended the moment she said it was a tradition she’d learned from her old sensei.

It didn’t take a genius to realize that Kurenai-sensei never talked about her original team, except in the most general of terms. Having been around shinobi much of his life, Naruto noticed how many of them would mention their old teachers or team mates. According to Shikamaru’s complaints, his father did little else when they talked, much to the lazy boy’s annoyance. However troublesome such habits might be for others, it only made the exceptions to the rule that much more noticeable. Naruto was curious as to why Kurenai never talked of them, but he hesitated to ask. Kurenai was a very private person in some ways, despite her forthright nature, and he suspected that her reasons for not speaking of them were sad ones.

It wasn’t that Naruto ever forgot that they were all shinobi, trained assassins who could be assigned any mission, no matter how dangerous, for the good of their village. But after a while the dangers just seemed so normal, that it was hard to keep them in the forefront of his mind. And perhaps that was for the best, because every time he even considered the possibility of losing his team mates on a mission, his mind sheered away from the enormity of that potential loss. Not for the first time, he realized that he literally would rather die than suffer the loss of one of the few people that cared for him. Kurenai-sensei said that she never expected Naruto to intercept every attack aimed at Shino or Hinata, but that was exactly what he wanted to do. He’d do whatever it took to keep his friends safe. Anything at all.

Naruto felt the hairs on the back of his neck begin to rise and realized with a start that the unnatural chakra he’d felt during the battle was beginning to stir. Remembering Kurenai’s words, he took a deep breath and made an effort to calm himself. He clenched and unclenched his hands, trying to ignore how sharp his fingernails were becoming, and hoping that his canines didn’t look as large as they suddenly felt. He looked up at his team mates, to remind himself that they were all right. Shino was walking silently beside Kurenai, hunched inside of his spare trench coat. Hinata was walking beside Naruto, seemingly lost in thought.

Though she walked with her eyes downcast, Naruto noticed that she’d fully adapted to her weights, and walked as gracefully as ever with their mass added to her arms and legs. Somehow the sight of her seemed to calm him, quelling the rising tide of anxiety about the future that wanted to overwhelm him. He could feel his body returning to what, for him, counted as normal.

Almost as if she were sensing his thoughts, Hinata glanced toward Naruto, only to jump a little when she locked gazes with him. Her face turned red and she clasped her hands together. “A-ano?” she asked hesitantly.

“Looks like you’re ready to increase your weights again, Hinata-chan,” Naruto said brightly, relieved that the anxious pressure building inside of him was draining away.

“Oh!” Hinata said, looking crestfallen. “S-sorry,” she stammered, “I should have noticed sooner, a-and-”

Naruto frowned and her words cut off suddenly and she looked away. Why was she always apologizing for things that were not her fault? “Er, you know, Hinata, we’ve been out in the woods for several weeks. It’s not like you could buy extra weights from a squirrel.”

The kunoichi didn’t respond to his lame attempt at humor, and just looked down at her feet as they walked.

Naruto sighed. He didn’t know why his words always came out weird when he talked to Hinata, but he was getting tired of it. “Look,” he said. “I was just trying to say that you’ve fully adapted to wearing the weights, probably because you work really hard and probably slept with the damn things on. I need to get more weight added to mine as well. I’m sorry if it came out wrong, but I was trying to say ‘Nice work.’ And I’m really glad you’re on my team, too. I can’t picture Ino or Sakura working as hard as you have.” There, he thought with some satisfaction, no way can she take that wrong. He smiled at his team mate.

Hinata was left several paces behind as her legs momentarily froze in place. Her face turned bright red and Naruto wouldn’t have been surprised if her hair started to smoke and frizz up. He blinked, then ran back and waved his hand in front of Hinata’s eyes, startling her out of her daze. She ducked her head down with a small smile and they turned to follow their team mates…

Only to discover that Kurenai and Shino had turned around as well, and were staring at them.

Naruto shrugged and scratched the back of his head with a sheepish grin. At least he’d made himself understood properly. It was about time.

Hinata managed to get her face back under control by the time Kurenai-sensei led them to their destination. She found it difficult to concentrate after Naruto’s blunt, but honest words. She realized he was mirroring her words to him when she reassured him that she still wanted him to stay on Team Eight, Kyuubi and all, but it still shocked her when he said that he’d rather have her on his team than Ino or Sakura. Especially when she considered all the times he’d tried to ask Sakura out when they were in the Academy.

Naruto was glad she was his team mate. Her. The Hyuuga reject, who failed everything she ever tried to do… except maybe at being Naruto’s friend? She knew she’d helped him, at least a little, that day by the stream – even if she had gone about it all wrong. She supposed she should be grateful to the fates: if she were only going to be allowed to do one thing right, then this would be the one that she would pick.

Hinata’s bemused thoughts cut off in surprise when Kurenai led them to Moritake’s for their last task of the day. The jonin’s face was even more somber than usual as she explained that her jonin sensei always brought his team here after a long mission away from Konoha to discuss the mission, plan what they would work on next, and generally celebrate their success.

Hinata knew from the way their sensei always spoke of them in the past tense that Kurenai-sensei’s team was no more. She was nowhere near as skilled at reading people as a proper Hyuuga should be, but she didn’t have to be to know that something dreadful must have happened to them. Shino and Naruto seemed to pick up on this as well, because they were silent as Kurenai led them inside, greeted the owner with a nod, and settled them at a table in a darkened corner.

Despite their stated purpose of celebration in coming there, they were all silent as they waited for their orders to arrive. Kurenai seemed extremely distracted by something, and frowned off into the distance. Hinata noticed Naruto fidgeting nervously. If she wasn’t used to the frequent formal dinners at the Hyuuga compound, she’d probably do the same. Finally, Naruto could no longer contain himself and spoke up.

“Sensei?” he asked, “what was your jonin-sensei like?”

Kurenai froze with her sake halfway to her lips and Hinata held her breath. While she was equally curious, she couldn’t believe Naruto had just asked their sensei like that.

“Why do you want to know?” Kurenai asked in a far-too-quiet voice. Hinata had only seen Kurenai become really angry once, after speaking to her father. She’d come out of the conversation possessed by a cold fury that was frankly terrifying. She didn’t understand what her father had said to provoke such a reaction, but she knew she never wanted to see such rage in her sensei again.

Naruto’s voice took on an unusually thoughtful tone as he stared into the distance. For an instant, Hinata pictured his unusually somber expression under the Hokage’s traditional hat and felt a shudder of premonition. Was she watching destiny change before her eyes?

“He was your sensei,” was all Naruto said after a moment.

To their surprise Shino spoke up as well. “If he’s had anywhere near as large an effect on you, as you have had on your students, then a desire to know more about him is only logical.”

“Yeah,” Naruto added, nodding, “That almost makes him our sensei as well, doesn’t it?”

“I would be honored to hear of him as well,” Hinata heard herself adding. She was horrified at the thought of prying into potentially painful memories, but Naruto and Shino’s reasons had moved her. And she had to back up her team mates as well.

Kurenai-sensei was quiet for a moment as the waitress brought out their orders. After she left though, the jonin began to talk. “Kobaru-sensei was not the sort of person you would picture as a shinobi. He was even stockier than Sarutobi Asuma, who works with your class mates on Team Ten, and Kobaru was nearly a head taller; as… a team mate… once said, he looked like a boulder that had grown legs and gone for a walk.. With his size and strength, he was formidable with taijutsu, but he always said “only a fool hunts with one arrow in his quiver”, so he made a point of learning…”

Hinata sat, utterly still, as her sensei’s voice painted a vivid picture of the man who’d played a major role in making her the kunoichi that sat before them. Their food sat, cooling and forgotten.

It was after dark before they left Moritake’s. It was odd for Naruto, to feel like he’d come to know someone he’d never met, but it was a good sort of odd. He could see where Kurenai-sensei had learned a lot from the man, but added her own spin to his lessons before she passed them on. He wondered what he would teach his genin when he was a jonin. Hopefully by that time everyone would have forgotten about ‘Sexy no jutsu’; if they didn’t, he was going to have to have a little “talk” with Konohamaru…

Naruto shook his head at that thought. When Kurenai dismissed them, the pensive jonin gave them the next day off to rest and replace any damaged or worn gear. It was well past visiting hours at the hospital, but he’d make time to visit Iruka-sensei tomorrow. Naruto grimaced at the thought of all the laundry he needed to do before he went to sleep. The sooner he resumed working with Gai and Lee, the less pain would be involved in catching up. Tomorrow morning he would seek them out again. Maybe Gai would have some heavier weights he could borrow…

Naruto’s musings were interrupted as Shino and his sensei made their goodbyes. He turned toward Hinata, but the slump of her shoulders suggested that she was less than enthusiastic about going home. Naruto frowned as he wondered how accurate his conclusions about her family were. If he wasn’t delusional, that might explain why she lingered outside the restaurant instead of immediately going home.

“Er, Hinata?” he asked.

Hinata jumped and looked up from the fingers she was absently pressing together. “Y-yes, Naruto?”

“I’m going to do some extra training tomorrow with Gai-sensei and Lee, if they aren’t out on a mission. Would you like to come as well?” he asked.

“A-ano,” she said hesitantly as her cheeks reddened slightly, “wouldn’t that be rude? To come uninvited?”

“Nah,” Naruto said. “I’ll just tell Gai that you were so impressed with my progress that you wanted to see his training methods… He’ll go crazy, so just nod politely every time he says something about that ‘Power of Youth’ thing.” He shook his head. “And don’t look at their teeth when they smile or you’ll be rubbing the spots out of your eyes for a while.”

Hinata’s eyes widened at Naruto’s open duplicity. “I-I- I mean, I can’t-”

Naruto nodded quickly bouncing on the balls of his feet. “Sure you can. He’s actually nice, in his own weird way. And Lee really wants to beat your cousin, who is his ‘eternal rival’, and practicing with another Jyuuken user can only help him, right?”

Hinata nodded slowly.

“Great!” Naruto said with a smile. “But you better get some sleep. Those two keep some really early hours. Can you meet me in front of Ichiraku’s at five thirty?”

Hinata smiled a little this time, and Naruto felt an odd sense of accomplishment. “Hai!” she said, agreeing.

“See you in the morning, Hinata-chan!” he called out as he raced toward his apartment. He needed to get his laundry going, take as hot a shower as he could stand, and then reacquaint himself with his bed.

Hinata stared after the boy as he left, wondering what she’d just gotten herself into. If Naruto actually wanted her there, she supposed she could deal with the awkwardness. If Gai and Lee didn’t want her around, she doubted they’d be shy about letting her know. No one else was.

She tried not to dwell on where she was going as her feet carried her home. The branch family member on duty acknowledged her return with the barest of nods as she entered the compound.

Hinata was relieved she was able to slip into her father’s house without encountering anyone. Once in her room, with the door shut, she let out a shuddering breath and tried to relax. She unpacked her bag, setting out the items that desperately needed cleaning. The uniform she was wearing was definitely in that category as well, so she changed into a bathing robe and, after setting out her laundry, crept into the bathroom for a long soak.

The hot water soothed her muscles, but just being in this house was increasing her mental tension. She wasn’t wanted here. She didn’t belong here. She was a failure in a clan that didn’t tolerate failures. The realization she’d come to on the way back to Konoha burned ever brighter in her mind.

She didn’t want to be here.

Naruto’s fingers were still tingling from his shinobi alarm clock when he arrived in front of Ichiraku’s. Hinata had evidently arrived a little early, and was watching the old man fuss over his stove as he prepared for another busy day.

He waved goodbye, promising they’d be back for breakfast, and led Hinata to Gai and Lee’s favorite training ground.

“Ah, Naruto!” Gai called out as they entered the clearing. “I heard your team had returned to Konoha, flush with victory and the fire of youth! Are you ready for more steps on the path to become a Genius of Hard Work?”

“Er, yeah,” Naruto said, rubbing at the back of his neck while Hinata stared at the odd duo. “And I brought someone who works even harder than I do.”

“Yosh!” Lee cried out. “My favorite sparring partner and rival of hard work has returned to Konoha!” Naruto wasn’t sure if it was possible, but his eyebrows seemed even thicker than he’d remembered.

“Lee! You are so passionate! You are truly my student!” Tears were streaming from the jonin’s eyes, making them sparkle unnaturally in the dim morning light.

“Gai-sensei!”

“Lee!”

“Gai-sensei!”

“Lee!”

“Uhm,” Naruto said, interrupting the happy duo; he could have sworn that he heard music off in the distance. “This is Hyuuga Hinata,” he said, nudging the dubious-looking girl forward.

“Ah!” Gai said, distracted from their cacophonous duet. “You must be the cousin of my student Neji.”

“Hai!” Hinata said, bowing quickly. Naruto thought she looked like she wanted to bolt out of the clearing and hide.

“She’s heard me brag about your incredible training techniques,” Naruto said quickly. “And she wanted to see for herself. I think they are probably superior to the Hyuuga methods, but only Hinata can judge that for certain.” Hinata spun toward Naruto, her mouth hanging open in shock.

The blond shinobi had been a little worried about laying it on too thickly with the green-clad jonin. He shouldn’t have wasted the energy.

“Yosh! The fire of youth extends even into the cold Hyuuga clan!” Gai exclaimed happily. “Neji is a genius, but he lacks Lee’s fire and enthusiasm! I will be more than happy to fan the fires of her determination to excel!”

Hinata gaped at the jonin as he and Lee broke into another chorus. She turned to Naruto, her expression puzzled.

“That means you are more than welcome to train with us, Hinata-chan,” Naruto translated with a grin and a roll of his eyes.

As they set to work, Naruto braced himself for an unpleasant task – getting caught up to Lee again. The spandex-clad genin was even faster than he remembered, and while Naruto wore his weights on the border patrol mission, he couldn’t afford to train himself to exhaustion in hostile territory.

At first, all Naruto could see were green blurs as he tried to block a typhoon of kicks and punches. Even when he did successfully block, Naruto had to lock his stance to avoid being blown off his feet. He could feel his sandals skidding backward on the grass.

He grew frustrated enough to anchor his feet to the ground with chakra, only to have Lee go aerial on him, and send him flying with a spinning jump-kick that went over his block.

Naruto tumbled when he hit the ground, finally skidding on his shoulders and back as he tried to get his eyes to focus. Then he pulled his knees up to his chest and did a kip-up. He was a little dizzy, but his feet were steady. “I see you got soft while I was away,” Naruto said cockily, even as his vision swam slightly. “That should have knocked me out!”

“Yosh!” Lee shouted and came at him again. As Naruto’s blood got moving, his aches faded away in the excitement of combat. Lee scored three more solid hits, but Naruto sprang to his feet even faster and returned to the battle.

Finally, he successfully ducked away from one of Lee’s palm-heel strikes, and managed to grab the boy’s elbow before he could pull back. Lee chopped at Naruto’s elbow, but the blonde’s other hand grabbed that wrist before it could connect. Naruto forced his hands apart, yanking Lee temporarily off-balance and right into the knee Naruto slammed into his stomach, even as his forehead cracked into Lee’s jaw.

Lee staggered back, gasping for breath and rubbing at his jaw. “It’s great to have you back, Naruto-san!” he exclaimed happily. He turned to Gai. “Sensei, do you think I can attempt that move again?”

Gai frowned thoughtfully, his eyes wandering over Naruto, and then Hinata. “With me here to supervise, I think it will be safe. Naruto, Hinata, Lee has been working hard to perfect a special finishing move. He would like to work with Naruto for his first attempt, but it is important that no one mention this move with others. It is to be Lee’s secret weapon!” His voice rose at the end, and he gave one of those “nice-guy” poses that made his teeth shine with unnatural brightness.

“All right,” Naruto said dubiously. Then he shook his head. Gai wouldn’t let him be injured, even if this was a ‘finishing move’ – Kurenai-sensei would kill him. For all his quirks, Maito Gai didn’t appear to be suicidal.

All the same, Naruto couldn’t help but gulp as he dropped into a defensive stance. Lee had his hands clasped together and gasped “First Gate: Open!”

Then he disappeared in a blur of motion.

Naruto’s eyes had just begun to track downward when Lee’s foot drove upward into his stomach, launching him into the air. He heard Lee shout “Kage Buyo” and suddenly he could see his sparring partner out of the corner of his eye, leaping into the air behind him, in a parallel arc.

Naruto felt something wrapping around his arms. He looked down as he struggled to free himself. It looked like Lee’s arm bandages. Then the boy’s arms wrapped around his upper arms in a grip of iron. “Omote Renge!” Lee shouted as they began to spin rapidly. As he struggled to break free, a corner of his mind observed that he was very lucky to have not eaten breakfast yet.

It was hard to tell with all the spinning, but Naruto thought they had passed the top of their shared trajectory and were now shooting toward the ground at high speed. As he frantically tried to break free, he realized the purpose of this strange attack. With the way Lee gripped him, his head would strike the ground first – with their combined momentum behind it. Truly a deadly technique.

Naruto’s appreciation of the technique was, of course, marred by the fact that he was about to become its first victim. He was seriously considering calling on the red chakra when the two of them jarred to a halt.

“That’s enough!” Gai shouted as he caught the two of them. With Lee’s grip relaxed, Naruto was able to burst out of the bandages. He tried to turn around and immediately fell to the ground, too dizzy to walk.

“Did I do it right?” Lee asked in a worried tone as leaned forward, resting his hands on his knees.

“If you didn’t, I don’t ever want to see the right version,” Naruto groaned as he tried to swallow. Empty or not, his stomach was feeling rather delicate at the moment; that launching kick certainly hadn’t helped either. He saw Hinata, out of the corner of his eye, watching anxiously. He gave her a small wave and she looked down with a sigh of relief.

“Yes, Lee…” Gai said, pausing dramatically. “You have mastered the Omote Renge!” he shouted.

“Such a flowery name for a move that plants your opponent like a turnip,” Naruto groused as he tried to climb to his feet, sternly addressing his rebellious inner ear; how Lee was able to stand up at all was completely beyond him.

“Yes, Naruto,” Gai said as he helped the genin stand up. “It’s a very dangerous move, and only to be used in extreme circumstances. Is that understood, Lee?”

Lee nodded, and then pulled out a small notepad and pencil and began writing. “Yes, sensei. Now that I know I can do it, I will only use it in ‘extreme circumstances’.”

“When I tell your team mates of your success in the first phase of your initial training, they will be so proud!” Gai exclaimed.

“Yosh, Gai-sensei!” Lee agreed.

“Lee!”

“Gai-sensei!”

At this point Naruto’s stomach had enough and he vomited on Gai’s sandals. “Sorry!” he murmured as he stumbled backwards, still feeling like the world was spinning around him.

“Ah, the aftereffects were more severe than I anticipated!” Gai exclaimed, raising one be-smeared foot and frowning at it. “Make a note of that, Lee.”

“Yes, Sensei!” Lee replied with a serious expression, notepad in hand.

Paradoxically, Naruto felt better after puking, which didn’t make much sense to him. A light touch on his shoulder made him turn his head. Hinata offered him a clean cloth and a cup of tea from her thermos. Naruto accepted both gratefully, realizing that she seemed to always be prepared for any emergency with her bag – something he would do well to emulate.

“While Naruto-san recovers, would you do us the honor, Hyuuga-sama?” Gai asked politely.

Hinata’s face immediately reddened, but after an encouraging smile from Naruto, she nodded.

Watching Hinata spar with Lee was interesting, and soon Naruto’s spasming stomach was forgotten. Lee was still pretty fast, but doing the Omote Renge seemed to have taken a lot out of him. Nevertheless, after the first few exchanges with the Hyuuga girl, he started to go all out again.

Naruto noticed Hinata doing many of the things she used against him when they sparred. He supposed his personal taijutsu style had been influenced by Gai and Lee’s goken, but it was still illuminating to see his team mate flow around Lee’s attack and make delicate-seeming jyuuken strikes that left the boy moving slower and slower.

Finally, she got through his guard and scored a glancing blow to his left shoulder that made the whole arm freeze up. Lee jumped back with a frown, rubbing at the joint. “Ah! Just like with Neji,” he groaned.

“Lee! Do not let yourself become discouraged!” Gai said in a serious voice. “Naruto-san, you regularly spar with Hinata, do you not?”

“Hai!” Naruto agreed with a nod, ignoring the way Hinata’s fingers were pushing together again.

“How do you defend against her Jyuuken strikes?” he asked.

“Well,” Naruto said slowly, trying to ignore the way Lee had his notepad out again, hanging on his every word. “I usually can’t block them directly without getting zapped, and slowing down until she has me at her mercy.” He said the last bit with a straight face, but grinned at her blush. “I have to dodge more and block less. In fact, unless I am close enough to block her upper arms, I don’t block at all. Otherwise, she pushes chakra into my arm muscles or one of my tenketsu points and that hurts.” He shrugged. “I have to come in at odd angles a lot more. And I have to be ready to re-open any tenketsu that get closed.”

“Re-open?” Gai asked sharply.

Naruto nodded. “Yes, if I push a hunk of chakra towards that point on my body, it usually pops back open.” He shrugged. “Hurts like hell, though; like that pins-and-needles feeling, only about a hundred times worse.”

“I see…” Gai said dubiously.

Lee’s eyes had gone wide however. “Sensei! Can I learn to do this?”

Naruto shrugged. “Hinata helped me figure out how,” he said.

Now the jonin and both genin were staring at the Hyuuga girl, causing her cheeks to glow a bright red. “A-ano,” she said hesitantly, “Naruto did most of it out himself. I just told him when it seemed to be working.”

Still, Lee’s enthusiasm would not be deterred. After fifteen minutes of effort though, Lee’s shoulder was just barely able to flex. According to Hinata, his chakra couldn’t push quite hard enough to re-open the tenketsu point she had closed. Lee looked downcast as he told them that the reason he concentrated so much on taijutsu was because his chakra coils were severely underdeveloped.

Hinata looked mortified that her technique had forced the proud young genin to admit to his weakness, and Naruto didn’t miss the way her hands bunched into fists holding the hem of her jacket.

“Hey,” he said quickly, causing Lee to look up, “at least you didn’t fail the genin exam three times like I did.” He smiled ruefully. “If Mizuki hadn’t been a traitor, I might still be at the Academy.”

Of course, after saying something like that, he had to explain the whole mess that ended with him wearing Iruka-sensei’s hitai-ite. Naruto hadn’t had much experience telling stories before, but with this audience it was easy. Both Hinata and Lee seemed to hang on his words, and even Gai-sensei listened quietly, nodding thoughtfully.

It wasn’t until halfway through the tale that he hesitated, wondering how he should handle Mizuki taunting him about the kyuubi. Gai, of course, already knew, as did Hinata. Only Lee was ignorant, but Naruto knew Lee would follow Gai’s lead. He’d been right to trust Hinata and Shino, maybe telling Lee would turn out as well…

“So Mizuki started taunting me about the village’s secret law, which made Iruka-sensei really mad. He continued, though, telling me about how when the Nine-Tailed Fox attacked Konoha, the Yondaime wasn’t really able to kill him – no one could. Instead, the Hokage sealed the demon up inside a new-born baby, namely me. Well, suddenly things started making a lot more sense – like how all the adults hated me, because I was holding the demon that killed their loved ones, including Iruka-sensei’s parents. I was so shocked I could barely move when Mizuki hurled this huge fuuma shuriken at me. Next thing I knew, I was on the ground, and Iruka was crouched over me, with that big shuriken stuck out of his back.”

Naruto paused to catch his breath and check his audience. Lee’s unnaturally round eyes were practically bulging from the sockets, and Hinata looked to be on the verge of tears. Gai nodded grimly, though his eyes were bright as well.

“Iruka told me that he didn’t blame me at all, and that he could tell I wasn’t a demon. He said we were both alike, in that we grew up very lonely…” Naruto’s voice trailed off, as he hadn’t originally intended to go into that part.

“Anyway,” he continued after a deep breath. “Mizuki came after us again, only this time I was mad more than anything else. So I tried the new technique I’d learned from the forbidden scroll, Kage Bunshin no Jutsu.” He grinned. “Iruka looked like he was going to have a heart attack, but Mizuki just started screaming as all my clones jumped on him and beat him down. Then Iruka-sensei stood up and told me to close my eyes. When I opened them, he’d tied his hitai-ite onto my head and told me that I’d passed.”

“YOSH!” Lee roared, making Naruto and Hinata both jump. “Naruto-san,” he continued in a slightly quieter voice, “you are such an inspiration! Surely you are an incarnation of the Power of Youth!”

Naruto wasn’t so sure about that, since it sounded a little painful. But at least Lee wasn’t making his ears ring anymore, so that was something.

“Lee is correct, Naruto,” Gai added in a more reflective tone as he nodded at the blond genin. “That was no doubt a very difficult tale to share. Thank you for using it to inspire Lee.”

“If Naruto can overcome such obstacles,” Lee declared, his eyes seeming to catch fire, “then a lack of chakra is nothing. I will find a way to defeat Neji, even without chakra!”

“You ever catch him with that turnip-planting move, you’ll kick his ass,” Naruto agreed, his stomach rolling slightly at the memory.

“Lee has indeed worked very hard to perfect that move,” Gai agreed. “Tonight, we will celebrate his success!” he declared. “You two are both invited, as well.”

Hinata’s eyes widened, but Naruto answered for both of them. “We’ll be there,” he said.

“Good, good,” Gai said punching the palm of his hand. “Hinata-san, you are welcome to join us any morning you wish. Any assistance you can give Lee, will be most welcome. However, I would ask that you not mention any of this to your cousin, Neji. He is highly skilled, but I think it would be good for his training if he were to receive some ‘youthful surprises’ when he spars. It will demonstrate how he should never underestimate his opponents. Is this acceptable to you?” he asked politely.

Hinata nodded, eyes wide.

At this point, Naruto and Lee were both recovered, but Gai had Naruto and Hinata spar while he and Lee took copious notes. Hinata seemed a little self-conscious at first, but they soon settled into a quick rhythm of attack and counter-attack.

Naruto slipped first, and felt a spike of chakra blast through his elbow, locking the joint as capillaries ruptured and the muscles cramped painfully. But he was able to grab Hinata’s forearm with his good hand before she could pull back. Naruto rolled backward, planting his feet in Hinata’s stomach like he’d done before and launching her into the air. His working hand flashed toward his kunai pouch and he sent a trio of blunted shuriken toward his team mate. Hinata’s kunai appeared in her hand like magic and she deflected the two shuriken that would have hit her. She tucked her legs up to speed her rotation so she would land feet down.

But no sooner did her feet touch the earth than Naruto was right on top of her, a flash of yellow on his palm as his hand brushed the sleeve of her jacket. “Raiton: Shokkingu Haji!” he said as the jutsu discharged.

Hinata flinched violently at the shock, but Naruto had summoned just enough electricity for her to feel it, but not enough to hurt.

Naruto stepped back, proud of scoring a hit, as well as the proof of his hard-earned chakra-control. Then he saw Hinata’s head and the grin froze on his face. The electrical discharge left Hinata’s hair standing on end, forming an indigo cloud around her head. It was pretty funny, but Naruto refused to laugh at her expense as he massaged his bruised elbow.

As the kunoichi settled back into a ready stance, Naruto hesitated. He knew Hinata was easily embarrassed, and the condition of her hair would probably mortify her, as funny as it might be. He was tempted to just not say anything, but Gai and Lee were watching. Finally, it came down to the fact that she was his team mate. If he let it go without saying anything, he was turning his back on that.

“Hey Hinata?” he asked.

Hinata frowned. But she didn’t make a connection between her hair and the vague gestures Naruto was making over the top of his own head. Finally, he just gave up and stepped forward, rapidly patting down her static-raised hair. Unfortunately, individual strands wanted to cling to his fingers, so he had to stroke the dark blue hair a couple of times before it would lie flat.

He’d been hoping to save the kunoichi some embarrassment, but her face was bright red when he stepped back and reassumed a ready stance. “Er, your hair, it was sticking up from the jutsu,” he explained.

“Oh,” was all Hinata said. Then she dropped into a Jyuuken stance and came at him again.

By the time they left Gai and Lee, Hinata was as tired and hungry as her team mate professed to be. Even her stomach growled once as they walked back toward town, making Naruto crack up as she looked horrified.

“Neh, Hinata,” he reassured her, “you’re hungry because you’ve been working hard all morning. No one’s going to think you’re rude because you want to improve!”

Hinata tried to draw encouragement from Naruto’s words, but she could still feel scourged by her father’s contempt for crude behavior. Her face was downcast as she tried to banish his hateful words. “Ano,” she asked after a moment, “where are we going?”

“This is the other half of my morning routine,” he explained. “Gai and Lee train too early for me to eat breakfast first, and they work me hard, so I always have a healthy appetite… and here we are!” He gestured grandly and Hinata realized that they were standing in front of Ichiraku’s. “I get something to eat before I meet with Team Eight! Go to make sure I don’t pass out when we’re looking for that damn cat again!” Naruto said enthusiastically. He quickly looked left and right and then leaned forward. “It’s not quite as good as yours, of course,” he whispered confidentially, “but nice and quick.”

Hinata found herself blushing again. It was nice how Naruto, and even Shino, always complimented her on cooking, especially since she wasn’t that good. She’d prepared a few meals for her family on special occasions and none of them had remarked on their quality. Still, it was nice that her team mates tried so hard to make her feel better, so she obliged him by smiling a little.

A couple of villagers got up from the counter at that moment, and Naruto grabbed her hand and hauled her forward before someone else claimed the vacated stools. Hinata thought her knees were going to collapse when his fingers closed around hers, but she managed not to squeak. She knew her team mate was just concerned about filling his stomach, not that she wasn’t hungry as well, but it was pleasant, for a moment, to pretend that he was holding her hand for other reasons. Futile, but pleasant.

“Oi! Old man! You have no idea how much I missed this place!” Naruto called out as he plopped down on one of the stools. Hinata was a bit quieter as she sat down as well, a little disappointed when Naruto let go of her hand.

“Hello Naruto!” the old man called out happily, “it’s been far too quiet these last few weeks. Hey Ayame! Look whose back!”

The cook’s daughter looked up from the vegetables she was chopping. She smiled and waved at Naruto, and to Hinata’s surprise the young woman winked at her when Naruto had turned back to her father.

“So what’s the special today?” Naruto asked eagerly.

“Himono with rice, miso soup, and pickled daikon,” the old man replied with a smile.

“That sounds perfect,” Naruto said as he pulled out his bulging gama-chan wallet. Before they went to Moritake’s sensei had stopped at the bank and cashed in all three Bingo Book vouchers, splitting the money between the four of them. Hinata wanted to refuse at first, but after distracting Naruto for a moment, Kurenai-sensei had whispered to her that sharing the reward was one way for Naruto to lessen his anguish at being forced to take two lives. She didn’t think he’d be able to enjoy any of the reward unless it was shared with his friends. That had effectively stifled any of Hinata’s objections – she’d do anything to make him feel better.

That said, she still didn’t want him spending his money on her now. “Ano, Naruto,” she said quickly, “I can pay for my own,” she objected.

“That’s okay,” he said with a grin. “You can pay for tomorrow’s.”

Hinata opened her mouth and then closed it again. The strange jonin and his student had invited her to train with them any time she wanted, but she was sure he was just being polite. Or perhaps he was just being courteous to Naruto, who they both seemed to respect. She was happy to see others who appreciated her friend’s positive qualities, but she didn’t want to presume upon that either.

On the other hand, they did seem interested in studying her Jyuuken techniques. Lee’s commitment to defeating her cousin was laudable, and reminded her of Naruto’s unflagging determination. While she was nowhere near Neji’s level, perhaps she could help in some small way. But did that make her disloyal to her family? Gai said it would be good for Neji to be surprised occasionally, as it would make him less likely to underestimate a real opponent.

At first she’d been a little dismayed to see how easily Naruto revealed his secret to Lee, in comparison to the difficulties he had telling her. In truth, he hadn’t told her so much as give a few hints and then confirm her guesses. It… hurt… to think that he could be so much more open with Lee. But then she noticed how he was smiling at her when he paused for breath in the middle, like they were sharing some secret joke. It made her very warm inside, this inclusive feeling. It was then that she realized that it was her and Shino’s acceptance of him that made it easier to him to tell Lee. That alone had made the whole morning worthwhile.

Lost in thought, Hinata was slow to notice as Naruto’s face fell, but his words captured her attention. “Don’t worry about it, Hinata,” he said in a falsely cheery voice that she was only lately able to detect, “I know I keep some ridiculously long hours with all this training, so…”

Hinata shook her head. “I would be honored to train with the three of you, but will I not be more of a bother?” Whether she attended or not, she wasn’t about to let Naruto think it had anything to do with him. She almost cringed when she realized he was hiding his true feelings again. That would not do at all.

Naruto shook his head firmly. “Did you see all those notes Lee took while we sparred? When they were assigned to Gai, he and Neji were put on the same team because Neji had the highest scores in the Academy, while Lee barely passed. He doesn’t talk about it, but I think your cousin said some things that first day that really ticked Lee off. He’s been dying to find some way of defeating his ‘eternal rival’, and Gai wants all his hard work to pay off in the end.”

Hinata’s eyes went wide at that explanation. Naruto didn’t show it often, but she was occasionally surprised by how much he picked up on. Of course, training with someone three or four hours every day would doubtlessly give you a lot of insight into their character, but still… “I see,” was all she could say to that. “I don’t think it would be disloyal to my family to assist in training my cousin’s team mate.”

The grin that split Naruto’s face was genuine this time, much to Hinata’s relief. The fake one made her feel slightly ill, wondering how long he had worn it to make the disguise so seamless. “You’re the greatest, Hinata-chan!” he beamed.

Hinata ducked her head down instinctively, even as her cheeks reddened again. Fortunately, her embarrassing moment was cut short as the kindly older man set a pair of plates down before them.

“Itadakimasu!” they both said, Naruto in a far louder voice, and then they fell on their food like a pair of starving wolves. Hinata, as a Hyuuga, of course maintained perfect table manners at all times – but her chopsticks moved rather quickly nonetheless.

Aburame Shino awoke and performed his morning ablutions with the same precision he always followed when at home. He moved through the house like a soundless wraith, and was soon tending a rather promising-looking colony of winged kikai bugs. Their ability to fly at an extremely high rate of speed gave them exceptional maneuverability, but they performed somewhat erratically under stress. It was thought that the enhanced speed with which they moved made that inevitable, but he and his father were testing that hypothesis by crossing them with more phlegmatic ground-borne strains. Only three of the resulting sub-strains retained their wings, and only this one showed any signs of improved responsiveness or obedience.

Despite his concentration, Shino was fully aware of the opening and closing of the door behind him.

“Is there something you’d like to discuss?” his father asked in a low voice as he looked over his shoulder at the armature-mounted magnifying glass Shino was using to observe the queen’s egg production.

“Perhaps,” Shino allowed. He’d said barely three words since arriving home late the previous night. He was highly annoyed regarding some issues, but that was not sufficient reason for him to behave in an overly emotional manner. Shouting at his parents and the clan elders would be highly counterproductive, even if it would entail a certain, visceral, satisfaction. “I know the secret behind the Hokage’s law regarding Uzumaki Naruto,” he finally said.

“I see,” his father said with a quiet sigh. “I suppose I should petition the Hokage about getting you assigned to another team?”

Shino turned toward his father. “Why would I desire such an irrational action to be taken on my behalf?” he asked in a clipped monotone.

Aburame Shibi opened his mouth, but then closed it without speaking. After a moment he began again. “I assumed that your anger was related to the secret being revealed. As this is apparently not the case, I will await your interpretation of the situation.”

Shino adjusted his sunglasses. “My dissatisfaction with the situation stems from the attitude of the elders toward my team mate, a shinobi who had borne a large burden, practically since birth, with a dignity and aplomb that leaves me embarrassingly humbled,” he said in a tight voice. “Despite this, the elders of our clan openly disparaged him throughout his childhood. This attitude, promulgated through the elder generation, infected the thinking of myself and others of our cohort, to the extent that their distaste for Uzumaki Naruto was communicated, in full, to practically everyone he came into contact with. I now find myself questioning the judgment, rationality, and fitness to lead of the elders, as well as the rest of their generation. I find myself questioning the Aburame clan’s commitment to logic, and whether I still have a place within it.”

Shibi’s eyebrows were completely visible above his sunglasses. Shino’s statement was the equivalent, in Aburame terms, of shouting himself hoarse and setting all their houses on fire. “I… see,” he said slowly. “I admit I have had little to no contact with the boy; most of my opinions were likewise formed listening to reports from our representative to the village council. I believe he is known as a chronic prankster, and many have petitioned the Hokage to have him removed from the Academy or censured in other ways.”

“Naruto’s… eccentricities…” Shino said, choosing his words with care, “are somewhat understandable when viewed in light of his almost total social isolation. It is also a matter of public record that since he began working with Kurenai-sensei and Team Eight, Naruto has yet to pull a prank on any of the villagers.”

Aburame Shibi stared at his son for a long moment. “What do you intend to do at this point?” he finally asked.

“I would speak with the Aburame elders regarding Naruto,” Shino answered. “Loyalty to my team mate and a fellow shinobi of The Leaf demands no less.”

“And if they refuse to ameliorate their attitudes?” Shibi asked.

“I believe one of Uzumaki’s sayings comes to mind,” Shino replied. “We’ll burn that bridge when we get to it.”

12

Stress Testing

Naruto stared down at his paper, holding his head in his hands. The rules, as explained by the scarred special jonin, were pretty straightforward. The teams were split up into randomly assigned seats before the test papers were passed out. Everyone started with ten points, but wrong answers cost a point for each question. Getting caught cheating cost you two points every time you were caught. Run out of points and get removed from the exam. Simple, right? Oh, and if you get a zero your teammates fail as well… Just answer the questions and don’t cheat, right?

Except for the fact that Uzumaki Naruto was abysmally bad with written tests. They were the bane of his existence at the Konoha Ninja Academy. Practical exercises were different. He failed a lot of those too, but at least there was a chance. Sometimes he could figure out a way to succeed, or work around the rules. Like with the kunai-throwing examination – Iruka hadn’t specifically forbidden him to use an explosive tag, and the bull’s eye was certainly destroyed, even if he’d struck the target three inches to the left of center…

But a written test… there was only one way to answer them correctly. No way to distract the examiner and move the starting line. And only one correct way to do the problem. No room for creativity at all. Especially with one that was mostly multiple-choice like this one.

A drop of sweat rolled down Naruto’s forehead and traced a path down his nose. He rubbed at it irritably. At least the first question wasn’t multiple-choice. The parabola, B, represents a shuriken’s path after being thrown by an enemy ninja from a height of seven meters. Calculate the strength of the enemy ninja that can be observed from the trajectory followed by the shuriken and figure out the maximum throwing distance on flat ground. Explain your reasoning.

Oh crap, he thought with horror, it’s even worse - they want me to do math!

Hinata leaned forward with her eyes closed, appearing to be lost in thought to an outside observer. This motion also caused her short hair to hang slightly forward along the sides of her face, as her hands moved under the desk. She oh so carefully twisted her concealed fingers into the seals that would activate her family blood-limit, whispering “Byakugan” in a ghost of a whisper. Her chakra flow was so slow, and so controlled, that the students on either side of her didn’t even look up. The bulging veins on her temples were now concealed by her hair, so she gave no outward sign as her closed eyes scanned the papers of nearby candidates. If she was going to cheat, as this test seemed to require, she was determined not to get caught.

Finding one who seemed to have filled out most of his test, she began memorizing his answers. Everything was going according to plan. She’d hoped when they began assigning seats that she’d be able to sit near Naruto-kun, but of course the ‘random’ assignments would be altered to separate teammates. Much as she wished she could help her friends, she was confident that they would find some way to succeed.

Shino nodded slightly as his spy returned. A specially bred subspecies of kikai, it had extremely well-developed compound eyes to assist with reconnaissance missions.

Unfortunately, its brain wasn’t quite as well-developed. Though he could communicate with it easily by using one of his attuned queens, its conversational skills were as underdeveloped as those of his teammate when contemplating ramen. In addition, the flying insect’s memory was only sufficient to memorize a single answer at a time.

Though tedious to use, it was effective nonetheless. He only hoped that his teammates were also finding ways to succeed. A single zero would bar the entire team from progressing.

Naruto sweated as he looked over the other test questions. None of them looked particularly easy. Most of them he felt he could eventually puzzle out given unlimited time or access to the right books, but he had neither at the moment.

Why is this test so freaking hard? he asked himself, grinding his teeth in frustration. I don’t think anyone in my class, except maybe Sakura, could answer all of these in time! Why did they even let us take this test? We’re not going to get any experience if we fail in the first hour!

That gave him pause, and Naruto’s face went blank as he pondered this. Kurenai-sensei wouldn’t put them into this situation if it was impossible, so there had to be a way around it. He went over the rules again, how the points were awarded and how points were deducted if you were caught cheating. Funny how lenient that was. Iruka-sensei would kick you out of the room if he caught you cheating on one of his tests.

Naruto’s eyes narrowed. Why is this test so hard, but so lenient on that one aspect? It’s almost like they want to encourage… I’m an idiot. This is a Shinobi Rank Exam. They want to see how sneaky we can be.

Right at that moment, one of the proctors called out a number, making Naruto jump in his seat. “Number 52, you fail,” he said in a bored tone. “17 and 43, you can follow your teammate out into the hall.” Naruto glanced over at the chuunin as the angry genin filed out of the room. The predatory gleam in the older shinobi’s eyes held a hint of triumph, but no anger or outrage.

His suspicions were correct. The chuunin proctors were his real opponents.

As more teams were eliminated, Naruto began to sweat harder. He needed to find the answers, but he kept his eyes on his own paper. Those proctors were not messing around!

It wasn’t until one of the shinobi wearing a Suna marker and lots of face paint asked to be excused that he got some inspiration. By the time the foreign genin returned, Naruto had the rough outlines of a plan worked out. He just wished he had Shino handy to look for flaws…

“What is it, twenty-three?” the young-looking proctor on his row said when Naruto raised his hand.

“I, uh, need to go to the bathroom,” Naruto stammered. He grimaced and held his stomach. “I think I drank some bad milk,” he added.

The proctor didn’t react, other than to smoothly rise to his feet and gesture for Naruto to follow. Naruto wisely kept his eyes down for the most part, but out of the corner of his eye he saw Sakura look up, eyes widening in surprise, as they walked past.

In a quiet voice, the proctor directed him to go to down the stairs to the second floor, before proceeding down the hall. Naruto guessed that they wanted to make sure he and that Suna-nin didn’t come into contact. That was fine with him; if he was with Sabaku no Gaara, he was at least dangerous by proxy.

But to Naruto’s dismay, the proctor followed him into the bathroom, standing beside the sinks. Naruto clutched his stomach again and ducked into one of the stalls. Aware that the chuunin could see under the stall doors, Naruto dropped his trousers and sat down. He also pushed up the jacket sleeve on his left arm, leaving the skin of his forearm exposed. After pausing long enough to very carefully mold the chakra, he coughed loudly as his fingers formed the seals.

There was a loud pop, immediately supplemented by Naruto placing his mouth on his forearm and blowing hard. The noise was deafening in the enclosed space as mist billowed out under the stall door.

In a flash, Naruto fixed his sleeve and pulled his pants up. He flushed and opened the stall door and stepped out toward the sinks, in time to see the chuunin edging back from the smoke. “Gomen,” Naruto said as he quickly washed his hands, “definitely some bad milk, but I’m lucky it was just gas. Wouldn’t want to do that in the middle of the exam though.”

The chuunin didn’t say a word, but his steps as he led Naruto back to the examination room were a bit quicker than before, as if he was reluctant to let Naruto get too close.

No sooner did the sound of their footsteps fade within the bathroom than the other stall doors flew open and the three Narutos crouched on top of the toilets jumped out. Their faces screwed up in concentration and suddenly they were replaced by Umino Iruka, Maito Gai, and Yuuhi Kurenai.

The three jonins left the bathroom quickly, moving with purpose. But not before washing their hands, of course. It was fortunate that no one was on hand to wonder what the genjutsu mistress was doing in the male restroom.

Moving quickly across the rooftops of Konoha, the three clones descended on the library. They only had a handful of minutes to get the information Naruto needed and get it back to him. Luckily, each only needed to look up information for three or four questions, and Naruto had already given some thought to where to find the information. So while the Kurenai-clone was opening up a book on ciphers, looking for a match to the one seen on the exam, the Iruka-clone had a physics book open and was scratching down equations for the kunai problem and the Gai-clone was looking up the members of the original Konoha village council. Working independently, the kage bunshin found the answers, or most of the answers, within their allotted time and met up at the entrance to the library.

But as they made their way back to the building where the examination was being held, the final obstacle confronted them, one the original Naruto didn’t have enough information about to work out ahead of time. Their information was useless if they couldn’t get it to Naruto before the test was over.

With all the foreign shinobi, the building was heavily guarded, and getting out without speaking to someone was a lot easier than getting back in. The closest they could get without a risky encounter was a rooftop that had a view of the side windows to the examination room.

Using a well-polished forehead protector as a mirror, they tried to reflect the mid-day sun at an angle to catch Naruto’s eye. Using a signal code to transmit their information would be time-consuming, but it was better than nothing at all.

The only problem was the original Naruto’s determination to not get caught cheating. He never looked up enough for the light to catch his eye.

Unfortunately, their efforts did not go completely unnoticed.

“I can’t believe you three,” an annoyed-sounding voice spoke up behind them.

In spite of themselves, the three clones jumped guiltily and spun around. A Konoha shinobi with a cloth over his head and a senbon needle in the corner of his mouth was glaring at them. “I thought it was a little odd to hear of three rookie teams in the exam, but I never thought I’d find you cheating for your students. The Hokage is going to be very disappointed.”

The Kurenai-clone, realizing the man’s mistake, spoke up without thinking. “No, don’t!” he pleaded, before he realized that he wasn’t acting anything at all like his cool and rational sensei. The thought of getting Kurenai-sensei in trouble with the Hokage had evidently short-circuited his common sense.

The other Shinobi picked up on this as well. “Okay, who the hell are you?” he demanded as senbon needles appeared between his curled fingers. When the clones didn’t immediately answer, he whipped his hands up and flung the needles at the imposters.

The clones tried to dodge the missiles. Often senbon were coated with drugs or poisons to disable the target, but given how much chakra they had left, the first hit would be fatal. But as they crouched down or threw themselves to the side, the Konoha Shinobi did a seal and the senbon seemed to multiply in mid-air. Each clone was punctured by one or more needles and exploded into a puff of smoke.

Naruto abruptly stiffened in his seat as his brain was suddenly flooded with information. That jerk! He cursed to himself, why did he have to interfere with… Wait! How do I know what happened to my clones? I wasn’t there…

His questions cut off as he abruptly realized that he had the information needed for the test now. He went back to the first question and began writing down the equations before he forgot them. There would be plenty of time to think about his clones when he wasn’t taking a test.

Naruto’s pencil moved frantically as he filled in the squares allotted for his answers. As he provided workable solutions to the first nine questions, the knot in his stomach slowly began to loosen. It was by no means perfect, but at least he’d been able to ‘show his work’ on all of them… better than he’d ever done at the Konoha Ninja Academy.

Of course, all his nervous tension quickly returned when Ibiki’s voice jarred him out of his reverie, almost making him drop his pencil.

“Okay,” the scary-looking man barked, “I will now give the tenth problem!”

Naruto couldn’t help but glance at the clock. Indeed, forty-five minutes had passed since the beginning of the test. It had only felt like an eternity. This Ibiki guy really should be working at the Academy – he was perfect for that place.

His musings were cut short as the weird Suna shinobi finally returned from the bathroom, only to get a sarcastic remark from the examiner. Naruto wondered if the guy didn’t get enough fiber in his diet – he certainly looked dyspeptic enough as he returned to his seat.

“I will now explain,” the scar-faced man in the black trench coat continued. “This is… a hopeless rule. First, you are all going to choose if you wish to take this tenth problem or not.”

“Choose?” asked a blond kunoichi with a Suna hitai-ite worn loosely around her neck like Hinata. Despite her hairstyle, she was the most normal-looking person from Suna that he’d noticed so far.

“If you choose not to take it, your points will be reduced to zero,” Ibiki answered with a faint smile, “In other words, you will fail. Your two teammates will fail along with you.”

That statement, of course, sparked off a low rumble of muttered comments and denials from the remaining candidates. Naruto’s eyes narrowed. This couldn’t be that easy.

“And here is the other rule,” Ibiki continued, ignoring them all as he seemed to savor the moment. “If you choose to take it and you get it wrong, you will lose the privilege of taking the Chuunin Exam forever.”

Unsurprisingly, Inuzuka Kiba was the first to break the shocked silence. “What kind of dumb rule is that?” he demanded. “There are people here who have taken the Chuunin Exam in the past!” Of course, the boy’s indignant fury was not enhanced by the small white dog on his head punctuating his statement with two high-pitched barks.

Ibiki just laughed at that, a sound that seemed to send chills down Naruto’s back to gather in the pit of his stomach. “You were unlucky,” he said. “This year, I am the rule. That is why I give you the option of quitting. Those who are not confident can choose not to take it, and take the exam next year, or the year after that.” He chuckled again, and Naruto felt his jaw clench.

“Let us begin,” Ibiki said. “Those who will not be taking the tenth question, raise your hands. After we confirm your numbers, we will have you leave.”

After a long moment, the first hand went up from a seat near Naruto. An older-looking Konoha genin with a goatee and a pinched-looking face stood up. “I quit!” he said, looking like he was in pain, “I won’t take it!” The man apologized to his teammates as their numbers were called out as well, but the one Naruto could see didn’t seem to mind very much.

As he turned to watch them file out, he saw Hinata. She seemed to have shrunk down in her seat and her face had gone very pale. He tried to give her an encouraging smile, but her eyes seemed frantic with worry. That puzzled Naruto as he turned back around. Hinata didn’t seem to be that concerned with her rank, so much as becoming stronger so her father would appreciate her, the bastard, so why… then it hit him. His dream was to become Hokage, not hers. She was worried about him. Naruto frowned as he pondered this.

That first surrender seemed to open the floodgates as others raised their hands. After their numbers were called, each team filed silently out of the room. Some looked relieved, some looked angry… but to Naruto, the worst were the ones who filed out silently, their faces impassive masks. He wondered if those would remain shinobi much longer – he doubted those teams would remain intact for the next Chuunin Exam. How bad would it be, to fail the examination because one of your teammates lost… their nerve? Or chose to make the team fail so they didn’t personally risk being barred forever from Chuunin?

Naruto’s eyes narrowed as they focused on the chief examiner. He was playing with them, in some sick way. The man had a slight smile at the corner of his mouth. Seeing that, and remembering Hinata’s obvious distress, made something inside of him snap. In a sick way, it was gratifying to have someone more concerned about his ambitions than their own, but she deserved a lot better than to be tormented for it. He couldn’t talk to her, and hand signals were not practical for this, so he’d have to do it indirectly.

Naruto vaulted onto his desk, taking care not to step on his test paper. He pointed accusingly at Ibiki and yelled, “This is a load of crap!”

The examining room went dead silent.

Hinata’s hand was twitching, about to be raised, when Naruto-kun’s voice rang out. She’d been engaged in a fierce internal debate since the terms of the tenth question had been explained. She didn’t want to see the end of Naruto’s ambitions occur in this stuffy classroom. It would crush him if he was forever limited to genin, and she didn’t ever want to see such a thing happen. For a moment she wondered if this whole examination had been constructed as a trap to trick Naruto into destroying his dreams. Once, she would never have thought people could be so cruel, but the more time she spent with Naruto, the more she saw how he was treated. There were adults in Konoha who wouldn’t hesitate to do something so cruel in an effort to avenge themselves on what they saw as the Kyuubi no Kitsune. She wasn’t sure if Naruto saw the trap laid before him or not… would it be up to her to save him from himself?

She’d darted a quick glance at Shino, but he seemed unperturbed by the situation. Not that he ever really showed any emotion when he was caught off guard. Her hand had been trembling from nervous tension when Naruto’s shouted accusation made her go rigid in her seat.

“Number twenty-three, what is your problem?” the examiner asked in a bored tone.

“Even if they gave you the authority to make such a rule,” Naruto growled, “do you think another village’s kage will cooperate and not allow their own genin to ever test again?”

“You seem awfully sure of that,” Ibiki said. “Are you willing to bet your future on that? This is a choice that will impact the rest of your life.”

Naruto put his fists on his hips and straightened up even more. Hinata’s breath caught in her throat. “I bet my life every time I go on a mission – it’s my way of the ninja! And even if they did let you bar me forever, I’ll still get stronger and I’ll just be the first genin to become Hokage… and then I’ll fire your ass for making up stupid rules!”

With that, Hinata relaxed a little, because it was true. Naruto would not let them stop him from realizing his ambitions. She was wrong to have doubted him, even for a second. She was wondering if she should get up on her desk as well, to show her support, when the examiner spoke at last. “We’ll see if your gamble pays off, twenty-three. Now get off that desk before I disqualify you immediately for insubordination!”

Naruto hopped back into his chair, but Hinata could still faintly feel the waves of killer intent coming from her teammate.

“For the rest of you, this is your last chance to leave before your fate is sealed,” the scar-faced examiner announced in a deep voice that made Hinata’s insides twist. She concentrated on the spike of anger that came from her friend. She would see it through with him, or not at all. As teammate, friend, or even the Chuunin guarding the door to his office… where he led, she would follow… watching his back.

Ibiki-san waited, looking around the room. But Hinata didn’t think anyone else would leave after Naruto’s words.

And she was right.

“For the First Exam, everyone here… passes!”

Naruto stared at the examiner, wondering if he’d heard him correctly.

Sakura, surprisingly, was the first to ask the question they were all thinking. “Wait, what’s the meaning of that? We pass already? What about the tenth question?”

That led to the one of the scariest things Naruto had ever seen… even worse than Gai and Lee trying to sing karaoke of, “I Got You, Babe!”

Morino Ibiki was laughing.

Not a sarcastic chuckle, either. A full-blown, mouth hanging open, belly laugh. “There was no such thing to begin with,” he explained with a wide smile that made Naruto want to reach for a kunai, “or you can call the choice you made the real tenth question.”

“So what were those previous nine problems?” the Suna Kunoichi asked in an annoyed tone. “It was all a waste!”

“No, it wasn’t,” Ibiki disagreed. “Those problems accomplished their purpose, testing each individual’s information gathering skills…”

As Ibiki explained how testing as a group just added to the tension, since people didn’t want to let their teams down, it just reinforced Naruto’s opinion that the man was a natural sadist… and that his guesses about the test had been correct. At least that was somewhat gratifying.

It wasn’t until the examiner removed the cloth covering the top of his head that Naruto was distracted from his musings. He had a similar cloth for concealing his hair color, but Ibiki’s was for a far different purpose.

“Information can have greater value than life at times, in missions or on battlefields,” he said as everyone stared at the gouges and massive keloid scars that covered the top of his head, leaving no hair at all on the ruined scalp. “Information is paid for with the lives of people!”

“If you are detected acquiring information, the enemy can then account for that, making it far less useful. They may even use what you learned to lure your side into a trap,” Ibiki continued as he re-tied the cloth around the top of his head. “That can lead to a disaster for your team and your village. So we eliminated those that were not able to gather information without being caught.”

“But then what about that last question?” the Suna kunoichi asked, although this time in a much more subdued voice.

“That question was the main point of this exam,” Ibiki answered spreading his arms dramatically. “You were presented with a ‘do or die’ situation, being given the choice to go for the question or not… Look at it this way. You are a Chuunin, and your mission is to capture a secret document, but the opposition, their numbers, and their capabilities are unknown. There may be traps set up in advance by the enemy. Now… will you accept this mission or not? Just because your life and the lives of your teammates may be in danger, are you able to avoid dangerous missions? The answer is no.”

Naruto frowned, trying to reconcile this with what Kurenai-sensei had been telling him. She’d been awfully cautious about all the situations Team 8 seemed to get into… But she hadn’t turned down the border patrol mission, had she? And Kurenai-sensei had agreed that Hinata was right to lead them against the kidnappers. Maybe it was less avoiding dangerous missions than it was planning ahead and working to minimize those dangers?

“There are missions that carry heavy risks,” Ibiki continued, “but cannot be avoided. This is what we look for in a Chuunin, or squad leader. Those who cannot bet their lives in a critical situation… those who give up when given the chance because there is a next year, and let their minds be swayed over an uncertain future… They are fools with no determination who have no right to become a Chuunin. You are here because you gave the right answer for the tenth question, and you can deal with the difficulties you will face.”

Naruto blinked and swallowed.

“The first portion of the Chuunin Examination ends now,” Ibiki announced. “I wish you luck,” he concluded in a voice that sounded strangely sincere to Naruto.

Of course, this touching scene was utterly disrupted when a dark object exploded through the side windows in a hail of glass that narrowly missed the head examiner. Two kunai were thrown into the ceiling supporting the corners of the unfolding bundle of dark cloth. When the cloth finished unfolding behind the figure straightening up from her landing, it announced “Second Examiner, Mitarashi Anko is here” in kanji characters two feet tall.

To say the woman was dressed oddly, even by Konoha Shinobi standards, was to make a massive understatement. She wore a skin-tight metal mesh body suit that ended well above her knees, along with shin guards over her sandals, a very short miniskirt, and a tan, knee-length trench coat.

“Everyone, there’s no time to be happy!” she announced. “I am the Second Examiner, Mitarashi Anko.” As if they couldn’t read.

“Let’s go to the next exam!” she roared, raising her fist into the air. “Follow me!”

The silence as all the genin stared at her was deafening.

“I don’t think they get you,” Ibiki said quietly as he stepped out from behind the hanging cloth.

She didn’t answer, but just frowned at the remaining candidates. “Ibiki,” she said out of the corner of her mouth, “why did you let so many pass? The First Exam must have been too soft,” she concluded with a glare.

“It looks like there are a lot of good students this time,” Ibiki said diplomatically, and Naruto had the impression that they’d known each other before the exams.

“Oh well,” she said. “I’m going to have to make more than half the teams fail in the next exam. I’m getting excited!”

Naruto swallowed. If anything, she was even weirder than Ibiki.

“I will explain the details tomorrow,” Anko announced. “We will go somewhere else, so ask your jonin sensei about the rally point and time. That is all. Dismissed.”

Several of the Konoha jonin sensei were occupying an unused lounge at the Hokage’s tower. The space was normally a back-up ready room used when a full ANBU muster was called, something that almost never happened. But the seats were comfortable, there was an ashtray for Asuma, and talking amongst themselves gave the jonin something to do while their students were tested.

The fact that the Hokage always reserved the room for them, and that it was far away from the examination building, was surely just a coincidence.

Despite her intentions, Yuuhi Kurenai found herself on edge as she sat there, brooding about how her team would do… especially under a sadistic genius like Morino Ibiki.

She’d come to know Ibiki from her debriefing after the disaster that claimed the lives of her sensei and teammates. It was only later that she realized the significance of having a man of his talents in charge… but by that point she could view the circumstances dispassionately enough to understand.

When all but one member of a team was wiped out, it was natural that there should be some suspicions. Had she betrayed them? Was she a disguised infiltrator? Had she struck a deal with the attackers to spare her life?

Ibiki listened once to her fragmentary, disjointed description of what had happened. He asked her a few questions, and then sent her off to the hospital to have her wounds tended. He’d visited her there several times to check off various details in her story, but his face had not betrayed any signs of disbelief… or any other emotion.

It wasn’t until over a month later, when she’d had time to think about what had happened and gone looking for him, that she discovered he was the head of the ANBU Torture and Interrogation Unit. The realization that she’d been under suspicion when she returned was daunting, but it didn’t stop her from telling him of her own thoughts.

He’d stared at her for a long moment after she finished. His eyes flickered toward the seals painted on the walls and she realized that, with his door closed, his office was one of the few places in Konoha that guaranteed absolute privacy.

That’s when he agreed with her that the circumstances of the attack did not add up. Too much force had been used to gain too small an objective. There was something else at stake - that much was clear. He’d also cautioned her to keep her head down and her thoughts to herself until such time as she had iron-clad proof of her accusations, lest she be made to join her team in the afterlife.

Kurenai’s stomach was churning as she left that meeting, which Morino Ibiki had logged as the ‘final debriefing from aborted mission #2579-b’. It was gratifying that he’d taken her seriously – too many sexist fools would disregard the words of a young kunoichi, regardless of her intelligence. It was a relief that such a professional agreed that something was going on here – she wasn’t just suffering from paranoid delusions triggered by her grief. But at the same time, his observations had chilled her. Whoever had set them up had access to resources and information to a degree that was frankly terrifying when she stopped to consider the implications. And this unknown party had demonstrated no compunctions about shedding blood to achieve their goal. Her future survival truly depended on her discretion.

She never thought she’d ever felt so alone as she walked back to her family’s house. Fortunately they were out of town on a visit to one of her father’s suppliers in Wind Country when she’d returned to Konoha – at least she’d been able to spare her mother the worry of her only daughter being in the hospital. But any mistakes she made if she tried to pursue an investigation could cost them their lives as well… so she decided to wait until they returned and speak to them both.

It wasn’t until a week later, when the scroll regarding the fire that claimed her parents’ lives arrived, that Yuuhi Kurenai realized what being all alone really meant.

Kurenai shook her head, as if to clear it of unwanted memories, and glanced up at the clock. The test should be over by now. She glanced at the others sitting there. Kakashi was reading one of his little orange books, Gai was doing push-ups on the floor, and Asuma was smoking and trying to talk Gai into joining him in some elaborate betting pool regarding the exam results.

The door to the temporary waiting room opened and everyone looked up. However, instead of Ibiki with the test results, they saw two of the younger special-jonin, Gekko Hayate and Shiranui Genma. The latter stopped after entering the room and just started laughing for some strange reason.

“What’s so funny?” Asuma asked in a faintly belligerent tone.

Hayate just shook his head and elbowed Genma. “Sorry, but we have to ask. Have any of you left the lounge since the exam started?”

All four jonin shook their heads.

Hayate let out a sigh. “That’s what I thought,” he said.

By this time Genma had mastered his amusement and cocked his head, peering at them. It seemed to Kurenai that his attention was focused on her and Gai. “At least the henge was a good likeness,” he said after a moment.

“Excuse me?” Kurenai asked, narrowing her eyes.

Genma looked over at Hayate, who sighed and nodded. “I was assigned to patrolling near the examination building this afternoon,” Genma explained. “I caught three people on a rooftop trying to signal someone in the examination room. They appeared to be you and Gai-san, along with Umino Iruka, one of the Chuunin who teach at the Academy, but when I confronted them they didn’t act quite right.” Genma shook his head at that point. “I hit them with some poisoned senbon, but they just exploded… I’m pretty sure now that they were shadow clones. I stopped them, but we’re still wondering who did it.”

Kurenai shook her head. She knew of only one clone-user that would pick her, Gai, and Iruka as models. But what the hell was he thinking?

Kakashi looked up from his book. “Since the first exam is over now, did Ibiki-san use the Prisoner’s Dilemma, the Impossible Task, or something even more devious and twisted on our students?”

Hayate looked puzzled at the question, but he answered the copy-ninja nonetheless. “I believe he went with the second option, with two of his confederates seeded into the examinees to copy from.”

At that point, Kakashi’s face twisted under his ever-present mask. It wasn’t until Kurenai noted the tilt in his visible eye that she realized he was smiling. “You’ve been had, Genma-san.”

“What do you mean?” Kurenai asked sharply.

“Do any of you regularly use Kage Bunshin no Jutsu?” Kakashi asked.

Everyone shook their heads.

Kakashi shrugged. “It’s not surprising; it takes a lot of chakra to summon a clone that will disappear the first time it’s hit. More than a few will tap my reserves, so it’s only useful in certain situations. One of the reasons it’s such a chakra drain is because you are molding enough chakra for it to have a physical presence, without a sustaining material to give it mass, like with Mizu Bunshin. Another reason is because the user is creating a faint impression of his consciousness on the bunshin, allowing it to think somewhat independently.”

Kurenai remembered working with Shino on the roof repairs, and carrying on a conversation with one of Naruto’s clones, thinking it was the original. “Does the degree of independent thought depend on the amount of chakra used to create the clone?” she asked curiously. It was odd, once you got Kakashi talking about the technical details of an advanced jutsu, how his goofball persona seemed to just fall away for a time.

“To a degree,” Kakashi agreed with a nod. “One side effect of this impressioning process is this: when a clone is dispelled, the knowledge and memories gained by this secondary consciousness will revert to the original.”

“So what you’re saying,” Asuma interrupted, crushing out his cigarette, “is the jutsu user will know everything the clone knows?”

“That’s right,” Kakashi said. “I remember the night we agreed on the team assignments, Iruka said something about Uzumaki Naruto mastering Kage Bunshin no Jutsu?”

Kurenai frowned. “Yes, and those were probably his clones. But from the way you described Ibiki’s strategy… I believe you called it ‘The Impossible Task’, and his use of confederates… the students were supposed to cheat to pass?”

Kakashi shrugged, but Hayate nodded slightly.

“It sounds like Naruto had enough time that night to learn a jonin-level technique,” Kakashi said with an obvious smirk, “but not enough time to read all the fine print. Otherwise his clones wouldn’t have been trying so hard to signal him… they could have just dispersed themselves to give him whatever information they had collected.”

“Wait!” Genma shouted, the ever-present senbon falling out of the corner of his mouth. “That means when I…”

“When you disrupted his clones, you helped them achieve their mission,” Kakashi said lightly. “I’m sure Kurenai-sama appreciates you helping her genin… maybe you should ask her out on a date?”

Kurenai glared at the infamous copy-ninja. “Do you really think you have enough traps guarding your ‘literature’ collection, Kakashi?”

Kakashi paled for a moment, but then nodded.

“If I hired my team for a C-rank mission to burn them all, it would be money well spent,” she replied. “Do you really want to bet all your little orange books against the deviousness of the most notorious prankster to ever graduate from the Academy? I must warn you, he’s been saving up – he even fooled me once with a genjutsu.”

Kakashi visibly swallowed and slowly shook his head.

Asuma grunted. “You fight dirty,” he said approvingly.

Kurenai just smiled at him.

At this point Genma was banging his head against the wall, while Hayate tried to console him. Gai finished his push-ups, but seemed to still have a lot of nervous energy. He jumped to his feet and began lecturing Kakashi about how he should never try to be ‘cool and hip’ toward Kurenai-san, a sensei who so obviously understood the power of youth… not noticing that Kakashi had his nose again buried in the book cradled protectively in his hands.

All the noise was starting to give Kurenai a headache, so she got up and began walking toward the door. As she reached out to open it, it moved aside on its own. Ibiki stood in the doorway, his face impassive but his dark eyes glittering as she stepped back to allow him entrance.

“Is that Uzumaki brat one of yours?” he asked without greeting.

Kurenai merely raised an eyebrow. His words betrayed more emotion than he usually allowed to show. “Yes. Yes, he is. What of it?”

“That’s what I thought,” he said as he handed her the test results. “Got your fingerprints all over him, so to speak. Got one of the highest scores without being observed cheating at all, my assistants are still trying to figure out how.”

“He had some unwitting assistance,” Kurenai replied absently as her eyes flitted down the scoring summary. She smiled slightly. All of her genin had done well, exceptionally well in fact. She looked up at Ibiki, who was visibly glowering. “We just figured it out – you can ask Genma. Now what else happened?”

Ibiki sighed. “The last question was a gut-check, to see if they could commit in a high-stress situation. I told them that if they chose to answer the last question and failed, they could never take the exam again.”

Kurenai frowned. “That must have gone over well.”

“Well, it did the job. All the wimps were bailing out like rats leaving a sinking ship, when your genin jumps up on his desk and starts shouting at me,” Ibiki continued, scowling. “He tells me I don’t have the authority to declare such a rule, and if I did, he’d be the first genin to become Hokage and then he’d fire me.”

“Fire you?” Kurenai asked, going very still. When Asuma nudged her shoulder, she handed him the exam results, still maintaining iron-rigid self control.

“Yes,” Ibiki confirmed sarcastically. “I believe the exact words were ‘I’ll fire your ass for making up stupid rules!’.”

“I’ll have to speak with him about that,” Kurenai said as she carefully edged toward the doorway. “I’ll have a word with him immediately regarding his language,” she promised as she slipped out into the hallway.

If anyone in the room heard the sound of muffled feminine laughter receding down the hallway, they chose not to say anything about it.

To his credit, Naruto actually blushed at Moritake’s that evening when Kurenai questioned him regarding his words toward Morino Ibiki. It was clear he’d been overwrought when he’d confronted the special jonin, so she eventually let it pass. Overall, she was in far too good a mood to let anything minor spoil it. All three of her genin had tested out near the top of the group, even when counting only those who had passed. Though she would never say so aloud, Hinata and Shino doing well was only to be expected… but Uzumaki Naruto had never seemed to be much for scholastic excellence, or even subtlety. It was true that his use of kage bunshin had been inspired, even if it did indicate that he wasn’t fully aware of how they worked.

Not that she refrained from bringing that up when it was his turn to describe his tactics. The rosy blush that returned to his face more than made up for any embarrassment she’d suffered in the jonin lounge. On the other hand, it was gratifying to note that he’d already mostly figured out that aspect of kage bunshin on his own.

Moreover, she was cautiously optimistic regarding the confrontation between Naruto and Ibiki. Of course, the jonin had been irked at how… publicly… Naruto had called his bluff. But at worst, he’d only have to deal with some kidding from the other instructors. Out of anyone in Konoha, she was sure the head of the ANBU torture and interrogation squad could appreciate what had been done to Naruto, and respect the boy for not turning into a murderous beast. Even his comments earlier that day had been laced with grudging respect. Hopefully when the time came, he would regard defending Naruto from a faceless conspiracy to be in the best interests of Konohagakure.

As they finished their meal, Kurenai also couldn’t help but notice that Hinata had been even more quiet than usual. The pale eyed girl described her surreptitious use of the Byakugan in as few words as possible, looking down the whole time. She even looked uncomfortable when Naruto praised her for being ‘extra sneaky’.

After giving her students directions on how to reach the second examination, using a map of the Konoha training areas, Kurenai suggested that they go home early to pack their equipment and get as much rest as possible. But after she paid the bill, she followed her students out.

“Hinata, would you stay a moment?” she asked the Hyuuga girl in a voice that was little more than a whisper.

The girl nodded. As soon as Naruto and Shino were out of sight, Kurenai spoke again. “Now what’s bothering you?”

The young kunoichi looked even more uncomfortable, if that was possible. “A-ano, Kurenai-sensei… I am j-just disappointed in myself,” she said quietly.

Kurenai refrained from comment as she gestured for Hinata to follow her. After they both sat down on a bench not too far from Moritake’s entryway, she took a deep breath. Hyuuga Hiashi’s treatment of his daughter was atrocious, and every time she had to deal with the consequences, it became harder and harder to restrain her anger. “Please explain to me why you are disappointed, Hinata,” she asked in as gentle a voice as she could manage. “I have heard nothing tonight that you should not be proud of.”

“I’m sorry, sensei,” Hinata said in a miserable tone, “it was wrong of me to conceal my failures. But I didn’t want the others to know…” her voice trailed off. “To know how close I came to making us all fail,” she added rapidly, the words practically tripping over each other.

Kurenai frowned, trying to make sense of the girl’s words.

“During the tenth question…” she choked out. “I almost raised my hand. I couldn’t bear the thought of Naruto being limited to a genin for the rest of his life. I know he isn’t stupid, but I thought maybe they’d introduced that rule because he was taking the test this year. So many people are cruel to him… I couldn’t bear the thought of… but I should have believed in him!” Hinata’s shoulders hitched as her words became fragmentary.

There were few people on the street in the early evening to witness the Hyuuga heir having a public breakdown, but nonetheless Kurenai quickly cast a simple genjutsu to conceal their identities. The last thing she wanted was word of this to reach the girl’s father. Then she stiffly leaned over and wrapped her arm around her student’s thin shoulders.

Hinata went utterly still for a moment, and Kurenai worried that she’d misread the girl’s psychological state. She was about to lift her arm when Hinata turned and wrapped her arms around Kurenai with surprising strength. The girl was shaking like a leaf, but Maito Gai’s weight training program had very noticeable results.

Kurenai swallowed the lump that tried to form in her throat. She’d long ago discarded any plans of settling down and raising a family, but moments like this made her question that decision. For other reasons, Hinata’s reaction made her scowl. She wondered how long had it been since anyone had comforted her in such a manner. Since her mother passed away?

When Hinata’s trembling began to ebb and her breathing returned to normal, Kurenai finally spoke up. “Hinata, I don’t see where you did anything wrong. You were concerned for your teammate, and were looking out for his best interests. When it was clear that he correctly assessed the risks and chose to continue, you went along with that. You have nothing to apologize for, either to me or to your teammates.”

Hinata let go of her sensei in order to look up in at her in confusion. Kurenai ignored the odd pang she felt as she let go as well. “But I would have made us fail,” Hinata protested in a small voice.

“But you didn’t,” Kurenai reminded her.

Hinata slowly shook her head. “Only because Naruto-kun stopped me,” she protested. “It was foolish of me to think people would go to all this trouble to make Naruto fail,” she continued.

Kurenai froze in place for a moment as she weighed the risks. It was only an instant, so she was mildly surprised when Hinata looked up at her. “Sensei?” the genin asked in a worried voice.

“Hinata,” Kurenai said, choosing her words carefully. “There is something you should know, but you are under no circumstances to discuss this with anyone besides myself. Do I make myself clear?”

Hinata nodded, eyes even wider than normal.

Kurenai glanced around. No one was nearby, but she quickly performed another genjutsu that would mask their words from any curious ears. “Your suspicions are not completely unfounded,” she told her student after a moment. “Between Shino, Iruka-sensei, and myself, we have uncovered signs that some people are acting in ways to hurt Naruto and prevent him from being accepted in the village. I don’t think they would be able to change the Chuunin Examination rules to accomplish this, but I am cautious about everything where Naruto is concerned.”

Hinata’s next words caught Kurenai completely off-balance. “Is my father involved?” she asked, tension visible in the trembling of her jaw.

“I don’t know,” was all Kurenai could say. She hadn’t anticipated Hinata making that connection so fast. “The head of the Hyuuga clan would have the influence to do some of the things we’ve uncovered, but that alone is not proof.”

Hinata’s eyes had gone very still, and seemed to bore into Kurenai’s as she spoke. “He asked me, after we returned from the border, about the fight with the kidnappers,” Hinata said.

Kurenai’s breath seemed to catch in her throat. If he knew that Naruto had drawn on the Kyuubi’s chakra, he could use that to…

“However,” Hinata continued, “I was unconscious for some of the battle and could not answer his questions. He seemed very disappointed.”

Now Kurenai finally recognized why Hinata’s eyes seemed to unnerve her for an instant. Her student was angry. “Your discretion is highly appreciated, Hinata,” she said evenly as she remembered a discussion between her parents that she’d overheard a year before she graduated from the Academy.

They’d just returned from the funeral of one of her father’s trading partners, one Hiroto Yasuri. He and his daughter Natsuki both died after eating a meal prepared with some wild mushrooms that turned out to have been highly poisonous. It was ruled to be an accident, but Kurenai’s parents didn’t believe it. The daughter had been thirty-nine at the time, an unusual age for a once attractive girl to remain unwed. It wasn’t however, for a lack of suitors. Her father had rejected the young men of the village who’d asked permission to court his daughter, hoping she would catch the eye of one of the nobility. He was extremely wealthy, but money couldn’t buy entry into the nobility of Fire Country, so his only option was through marriage. Unfortunately, his insistence that his daughter could only marry someone of that class had left her alone until her youth had fled. While many who knew the family felt bad about the situation, Natsuki never complained and never spoke about it… But she’d prepared the meal that claimed her and her father’s life.

Kurenai blinked, as she wondered what had stirred up that memory. As a shinobi of the Leaf, Hinata was not quite as constrained as Hiroto Natsuki had been. Perhaps it was the reminder that a carefully maintained exterior could conceal surprising depths. It was a lesson she was sure that Hyuuga Hiashi had yet to learn.

Naruto made sure he arrived at Training Area Forty-Four at least an hour before the second exam was scheduled to begin. As it was, Shino was already there, and Hinata arrived at roughly the same time. After all the nervous tension of the first exam, and then unwinding at the celebratory dinner at Moritake’s, he’d fallen asleep as soon as his head hit the pillow. Now, after sleeping far later than he was used to, he felt ready to take on the world.

Which was a good thing, given how some of the other examinees were eyeing him as they arrived at what signs announced was a ‘forbidden area’.

Shino was quiet as he paced back and forth, facing the fence that marked the boundaries of the training area. Naruto had never seen his friend, well, fidget like that before. He supposed that the seriousness of the situation was finally getting to the normally unflappable Aburame.

Serious or not, he doubted Shino would appreciate him commenting on his behavior, so Naruto stood next to Hinata and went through his mental checklist of the equipment he’d packed. The instructions relayed from Kurenai-sensei said to come prepared as they usually would be for a mission. Given that some of their missions were weeks long - that could mean a lot. Also, when he looked at sensei’s map of the training areas, Area Forty-Four, located at the northwest edge of the village and extending well out into Fire Country, was a circle twenty kilometers in diameter. That suggested that the second exam might last far longer than the first.

So he, and to a lesser extent Hinata, had packed heavily for this ‘mission’. The chakra-enhanced training weights on their wrists and ankles could always be adjusted to make up the extra weight. While doing this slightly changed their balance, they had adjusted by the time they reached the training area.

Hinata left the normal bag she carried around Konoha at home, and instead wore a full-sized backpack over her jacket. Naruto’s pack was slightly oversized for his height, but was strapped on tightly and didn’t interfere with his movements. He’d even tested this by wearing it during a sparring match with Lee the day after he’d purchased it from Tenten’s father. The fabric directly over his back concealed a thin layer of metal links between it and the lining. It might not stop a kunai, but it could slow one down.

He also wore both kunai holsters and equipment pouches today. Some of the other genin looked at him curiously as they arrived, but others looked thoughtful or worried. He wondered briefly if they thought he had some inside information about the next stage, but it wasn’t like they couldn’t make the same deductions his team had.

He scowled for a moment. He was starting to sound like Shikamaru. Next thing he knew he’d be lying on his back, staring up at the sky and calling his teammates ‘troublesome’.

He glanced over at Hinata. Truth be told, if he’d been stuck with Ino, it would have been troublesome. There was no doubt in his mind regarding which kunoichi he’d rather have backing him up. His mind wandered back to his former crush on Sakura, and he was surprised that his lingering anger and disappointment were gone. Perhaps talking with Lee had helped himself as well.

“Hey Hinata?” he asked quietly.

Hinata jumped a little, but quickly turned toward him.

“Do you think we might have forgotten anything?” he asked.

Hinata shook her head. “I went over my list three times last night before I went to bed. I checked it again this morning.”

Naruto nodded. “I checked too, but I think I might have forgotten something.”

Hinata shook her head again. “I don’t think you’d-”

He smiled at her. “When I get excited, I sometimes forget the little things. You’re more… what did Kurenai-sensei call it? Detail-oriented?”

Hinata blushed and looked down. “I’m sorry,” she said. “I just get worried about forgetting something, so I tend to go over things compulsively.”

Naruto frowned at her. “I think it’s a good thing that you do. We’d probably screw up a lot more if you weren’t looking out for us.”

“Shino-kun is very careful with –” she objected, her cheeks coloring slightly.

“Okay,” Naruto capitulated with a grin. “I would probably screw up a lot more if you weren’t looking out for me.”

This time an unmistakable blush spread over her face, giving Naruto an odd sense of satisfaction. He’d been giving this a lot of thought. Kurenai-sensei wouldn’t say exactly what was going on with Hinata, but she’d hinted a lot. Remembering how he’d felt when Kurenai complimented him on something… acknowledging that he’d done something praiseworthy… he’d started to understand why Hinata seemed so flustered and embarrassed when he tried to compliment her.

The problem was, he could understand why he was so unused to praise. But what reasons could there be for Hyuuga Hinata, heir and member of main family of one of the most prestigious clans in Konoha? That wasn’t something he’d figured out yet, and sometimes he wondered if he really wanted to know. But in the meantime, he could build these elaborate traps out of words, maneuvering Hinata-chan into accepting his words at face value. It was odd, of course, how she seemed to want to believe him, but still couldn’t… of course, that just added to the challenge, didn’t it? And Uzumaki Naruto lived for challenges.

“Hinata,” he said suddenly. “Could you use your eyes to check me out?”

His teammate froze, her face turning even redder. “N-Naruto?” she choked out after a moment.

“I mean, with your Byakugan, you can see inside my backpack and see if I forgot anything,” he explained. “I don’t want to open it up and dump it out here in front of everyone,” he continued. “I don’t want anyone to see all the ‘surprises’ I have packed.”

“O-oh,” Hinata said after a moment, as her face began to return to normal. “That makes sense, I suppose.” Her fingers quickly formed the seal for her bloodline ability. “Byakugan!” she murmured. A hint of red remained on her cheeks as she circled around Naruto. “I can’t see anything you missed,” she said quickly, as her attention drifted down to his weapon pouches and kunai holsters for a moment. She quickly spun away and her eyes went back to normal. Oddly, her cheeks were flaming again.

“You seem to have plenty of shuriken,” she said quietly, facing away from him. “Though you only packed one box of ration bars in your backpack. What if this takes more than a week?”

“That’s still in there?” Naruto asked in surprise. “I thought I’d decided to throw it away. I figured I can always eat some tree bark if I get hungry and can’t find anything else. It would taste better.” Maybe that would remind her of how much better her cooking tasted.

Hinata stifled a giggle at his comment. Unfortunately, her self-restraint wasn’t perfect, as an extremely unlady-like snort escaped from her nose. She froze, mortified, as Naruto burst out laughing.

He wasn’t trying to be cruel, but Uzumaki Naruto couldn’t help it. It wasn’t unheard of for someone to make an odd noise when muffling laughter, but to hear it come from his refined teammate was just priceless. The horrified look on her face just made it even funnier. It was a few moments before he could even stand up straight again. “Arigato, Hinata-san!” he said, bowing deeply before his embarrassed teammate.

“Naruto?” she asked, her curiosity seeming to override her embarrassment for the moment.

He gave her his widest smile. “Here I am, getting nervous about the exam, and wondering if I forgot something… and then you do something like that to distract me. You rock, Hinata!”

Hinata’s face paled dramatically, then gradually returned to normal, albeit with a slight pinkish cast to it. Naruto felt inordinately pleased. He’d done something right, even if he wasn’t sure what it was.

Shino finished his nervous-looking pacing before too many of the other examinees arrived and stood next to them. Given some of the hateful looks they’d been given the previous day, Naruto preferred that they all stand together when around strangers. That wasn’t even taking into account what they knew about Sabaku no Gaara.

Of course, this Mitarashi Anko wasn’t exactly increasing his sense of security. He didn’t even notice her arriving, which was unnerving enough. Her words didn’t help either. “This is where the second exam will take place: the forty-fourth training area, also known as the Forest of Death,” she explained in a casual, yet creepy voice.

Some of the candidates murmured at that.

“You will soon be able to experience why this place is called the Forest of Death,” she continued happily. “But before we begin the Second Exam, I’m going to pass these out to everyone.” With that, she pulled a thick stack of official looking forms out of her trench coat. “These are consent forms. Those taking the exam must sign these.”

“Why?” several examinees asked.

“From here on, people will die,” she replied in a casual tone. “Therefore we need people’s consent before we continue. Otherwise, I’d be held accountable.” She ended with a chuckle, but no one else seemed to find her words funny.

“Now, I will begin to explain the second exam,” she continued after a moment. “To be brief, this is going to be a survival test.” She handed the stack of forms to Hinata, who took one and handed the stack to Naruto, who took a pair for himself and Shino before handing the rest to Shikamaru.

“This area,” she explained as she unrolled a map she’d pulled out of her trenchcoat,“is a circular region surrounded by forty-four locked gates. In addition to rivers and forests, there is a tower in the middle. It’s around ten kilometers from any entrance to the tower. Inside this area you will have to fend for yourselves as you battle over these scrolls,” she explained, pulling two sealed scrolls from inside her trench coat as she replaced the map. Naruto wondered briefly if there was a jutsu that allowed her to carry so much stuff in it. The light-colored scroll displayed the kanji for ‘Heaven’, while the darker-colored one displayed the symbol for ‘Earth’.

“Twenty-eight teams passed the First Exam,” Anko explained. “Half of those teams will get the Heaven scroll. The other half will get the Earth scroll. Each team gets one scroll.”

“What is needed to pass?” Sasuke asked in a serious tone, making several people look around.

“Bring the Scrolls of Heaven and Earth to the tower with your teammates,” Anko answered.

“In other words, fourteen teams, half the people here, will get their scroll stolen and therefore fail,” Sakura said thoughtfully.

“It also needs to be done within the time limit,” Anko added. “This Second Exam has a time limit of one hundred twenty hours, or exactly five days.”

“Five days?” Ino asked, incredulous.

“What about food?” Chouji asked, horrified.

“Scrounge it up yourself,” Anko said in a dismissive tone, “This forest is a treasure box of nature. There should be plenty of food.” Naruto had a feeling that Team Ten hadn’t taken a look at a map, or realized the implications of the training area size, until now.

“However,” Kabuto added helpfully, “there are a lot of man-eating beasts, poison bugs, and poisonous plants.”

“Oh no!” Chouji murmured as Ino scolded him.

“This test seems quite difficult,” Lee said with a grin that made his teeth gleam. Neji gave him a dirty look.

“And we’re surrounded by enemies,” Sasuke added thoughtfully. “We won’t be able to sleep in peace.”

“People will get hurt in the process of fighting over the scrolls,” Anko said, “and those who cannot deal with the difficulties will be revealed.”

“So can we forfeit if that happens?” Shikamaru asked.

“As a rule, you are not allowed to give up during the exam,” Anko announced. “You will spend the full five days in the forest.”

“Just as I thought,” Shikamaru said with noticeable disgust in his voice. “How troublesome.”

“While we’re on this topic,” Anko continued, ignoring the Nara boy, “here are the conditions that will fail you. First, if you do not arrive at the tower with three teammates and both scrolls, you fail. Second, if your team loses a member, you automatically fail. Finally, you are not allowed to look inside the scrolls until you reach the tower.”

“What happens if we do?” Naruto asked curiously.

“Then you will get a surprise,” Anko promised with a nasty smile. “If you become a Chuunin you will be handling top secret documents. It’s a test of your reliability. That’s it for the explanations. We will exchange three signed consent forms for one scroll over in that hut.”

Naruto’s eyes looked where she was pointing, and saw it was manned by several Chuunin proctors, some of which he recognized from the previous day.

“After you are assigned a gate entrance,” Anko continued, “everyone will begin at the same time.” She sighed gustily. “Here’s a last piece of advice: Don’t die!”

Naruto’s eyes narrowed as he clenched his fists.

It took a few minutes for the chuunin proctors to set up a curtain around the hut where the forms were to be turned in. This gave them plenty of time to fill them out, with a little left over for Ino and Sakura to snub each other. Naruto stretched to get some of the tension out of his shoulders, and saw Lee doing some warm-ups. The two boys exchanged a nod. While their teams had a fifty-fifty chance of competing directly against each other, depending on how the scrolls were distributed, they wouldn’t forget Gai-sensei’s words either. The shinobi of the Leaf would stick together if the situation got out of hand and there was a chance of permanent harm.

When it was their turn, Team Eight moved silently behind the curtain. When the chuunin offered up a Heaven scroll, both Hinata and Shino gestured toward Naruto. Naruto shrugged and silently removed his backpack, shoving the scroll all the way to the bottom before closing it and putting it back on. He was touched that his teammates wished to trust him with carrying their team’s scroll, and vowed not to let them down.

After all of the teams were done, Anko sent each team off with a chuunin to guide them to their assigned gates. It wasn’t long until they arrived at gate sixteen and waited for the chuunin guide to allow them inside. After consulting his chronometer, he unlocked the padlock and stepped aside.

In a flash the three of them were through the gate moving into the forest at high speed. The first chakra-assisted leap got them up into the canopy so they stopped leaving tracks on the ground. Hinata was between the two boys, and slightly in front, allowing for the best possible coverage with her all-seeing eyes.

Shino signaled danger ahead and to the right, so they smoothly veered to the left. At Hinata’s signal they came to a sudden halt on a thick bough that easily supported their combined weight.

“No one is in range of my eyes,” Hinata whispered.

“Good,” Naruto grunted. “Shino, what was that back there?”

“I saw signs of a large colony of Konoha Forest Leeches,” the Aburame answered. “I assumed you wanted to avoid them.” He paused. “I don’t sense any of the other teams near us,” he reported.

Naruto frowned. “How…?”

“I arrived early and seeded the grass in the meeting area with female kikai bugs,” Shino explained. “I believe that one or more members of every team have one riding on them now. And as you know, specialized drones in my colonies can-”

“-smell them from a mile away,” Naruto finished, grinning. “Shino, you sneaky bastard!” he congratulated his teammate.

“As a reconnaissance team, it would be foolish not to play to our strengths,” Shino said as he adjusted his dark glasses.

13

The Forest of Death

Naruto flew backwards, his ears ringing from the heavy blow. Arching his back, he managed to get his hands and feet in front of him before he smacked into a tree-trunk with stunning force. Bits of bark shot into the air and he barely managed to concentrate enough chakra to stick his hands and feet to the wood before he fell. That freaky grass genin was strong.

He shook his head to clear it, scanning the clearing for his teammates and allies. They’d only been traveling an hour before things started to get hairy. They’d avoided one team by using some forest leeches as a distraction, and were circling around to ambush them when Shino’s colonies sensed the pheromones of a single kikai bug approaching at high speed.

His super-sneaky teammate planted his kikai on all the other participants, but they should have been together in groups of three. Whether a lone competitor was a threat or an opportunity, they decided to see who it was.

Whatever it was that they had expected to see, it hadn’t been Kiba being chased by a giant snake.

Shino could see that the Inuzuka was clearly winded, and the snake was gaining on him. As the monstrous reptile reared up to strike, Naruto came in from the side, tackling Kiba out of the way. Unfortunately, Akamaru went flying from the sudden change in momentum. But Hinata was a heartbeat behind, and caught the tumbling canine with little more than a startled yelp. The snake, angry at being robbed of its meal, turned to pursue them, but that mistake proved fatal.

Shino dropped out of the trees above the snake, his arms trailing behind him. His hands flexed and a long baton of dull black metal shot out of each sleeve of his jacket. He caught the ends with the sureness of intensive practice and there was a distinct click as narrow, slightly curved blades folded out of each baton. They locked at a right angle to what were now the shafts of the modified kamas, the razor sharp metal pointing downward. With his arms above his plummeting body, they resembled scythe-like wings. Shino’s sandals landed on the back of the snake’s head, but before it could even register his presence, the blades continued their trajectory, curving into tight arcs as he straightened, his arms snapping downward.

The blades buried themselves in the snake’s eyes, ramming deep into the creature’s brain. The carcass slammed down, skidding on the ground. Shino extracted his weapons with a sharp jerk, cleaning the blades on the grass before folding them up again. By this time, his teammates had circled back into the clearing with their ‘prisoner’ – though by this time Kiba had reclaimed his dog.

But not before it had licked Hinata’s face several times, to her visible embarrassment.

Naruto let out a low whistle before speaking. “Is that what Misato-sama was teaching you?” he asked, clearly impressed.

Shino nodded as he slid the hafts of his weapons into his sleeves again. With an audible click, the spring-loaded holders locked them into place.

“You have the coolest parents,” Naruto muttered as Kiba got his breath back and began to explain. He’d been separated from the rest of Team Seven by some freaky wind attack, only to find himself on some monster snake’s dinner menu. As he talked, he began to lead them back to where he’d been attacked.

As they approached the clearing where Team Seven had been separated, Akamaru began to bark and Shino started scanning the greenery around them. “Something is wrong,” the boy murmured, “my colonies are sensing a large amount of chakra being expended up ahead.”

“Akamaru senses it too,” Kiba added as he patted the puppy that was now burrowing down into his jacket.

“Up above,” Hinata whispered, her Byakugan gleaming with the bits of late afternoon sun that filtered down past the leaves.

Shoving a bit of chakra into his legs, Naruto leapt into the canopy in a single bound, the others less than a step behind. Entering a potentially hostile situation at ground level was to be avoided whenever possible. Iruka-sensei’s lectures on tactics seemed so boring back at the Academy. Now, it was all Naruto could do to keep the remains of his last meal down.

Landing on a thick bough in a stealthy crouch, Naruto scanned the branches. Sasuke and Sakura were there, still alive too. On the other hand, Sakura looked like she’d seen better days and Sasuke had a bloody wound on his thigh. He ignored the slight twinge in his stomach and examined the third person, who was standing on a separate bough.

The Hidden Grass genin stared right at him with a look that was simultaneously bored and contemptuous. Naruto hadn’t made more than a whisper of sound when he landed, but he’d still been detected. He swallowed as the stranger’s eyes bored into his with a mixture of mild annoyance and more killing intent than even Sabaku no Gaara generated. There was no way this creep was a normal genin.

“More insects here to interfere?” he… it murmured in a peculiarly androgynous voice. “I’ll have to talk to my friend about his performance. I send him to kill one, and instead four come back. Very disappointing, but I’m only interested in testing Sasuke’s potential. I’m afraid you’ll all just have to die. Maybe Sasuke would like to watch, hmmm? Just like before…”

Sasuke launched forward a fraction of a second before Naruto. The Uchiha threw a rapid flurry of punches that the genin blocked with a single hand. The instant before Naruto’s fist connected with the back of the freak’s head, the other arm whipped around in a backhanded blow that sent him flying into a tree trunk.

By the time Naruto had regained his bearings, Sasuke was stumbling backwards from the freak’s counterattack. Naruto frowned. Since when were Sasuke’s eyes red?

The Grass ninja’s follow-up was interrupted by a spread of kunai thrown by Kiba. Shino was circling around the fight, no doubt spreading his kikai-bugs, but Hinata was darting in toward the enemy’s rear, her hands up for a Jyuuken strike.

Naruto almost shouted for her to stop, but he had to trust that she knew what she was doing. Instead, he put his hands together into the ram seal and summoned a score of kage bunshin, spread around the nearby branches. They instantly began circling as well, waiting for an opening.

Hinata almost made it, but at the last second the freaky genin pivoted and drove a back-kick into her stomach, driving her off her feet so fast she didn’t even have a chance to hit any of the tenketsu on his leg. Fortunately, one of Naruto’s clones was close enough to catch her, and pivoting, tossed her to a second clone on a higher branch right before the freak’s follow-up spin-kick drove through the first clone’s chest, making it explode.

“Kage bunshin?” the weirdo said in a voice that was really getting on Naruto’s nerves. “Maybe you aren’t as boring as you look.”

“Get out of here!” Sasuke yelled, “All of you! He’s way above our level!”

“I don’t think it will be that simple,” Shino said as he threw a pair of kunai. At first, they looked to be under thrown, but when they embedded in the wood to either side of the Grass ninja’s feet, they each had an explosive tag that was already flaring.

The explosion filled the air with smoke, but not flying body parts as Naruto had hoped. He couldn’t even smell any blood. When the smoke cleared the bough was gone, but in its place was an even larger snake, with the Grass-nin standing on top of its head.

“Oh hell no!” Kiba yelled. “You have got to be kidding me!”

Sasuke looked like he was about to explode. He kept glancing at his teammates, then shook his head and his eyes faded back into their normal black color. “Fine,” he snapped, as he pulled something out of his pouch. “You want our scroll, you can have it.”

“No!” Kiba yelled. Even Sakura looked dismayed.

“This is not worth us all getting killed like Tazuna,” Sasuke snarled.

“I suppose that goes for us as well,” Naruto said, slinging his backpack off his shoulders and rummaging around in it. He knew Hinata and Shino were staring at him, but he just ignored them for the moment. It took a little digging, since he had their scroll in the very bottom of the bag for safe-keeping. He even had to get one of his clones to step around the tree and help him for a moment.

All the while the Grass freak had this amused little smirk on his face, one that made Naruto’s knuckles itch. But now was not the time to scratch them on his way-too-pretty-to-be-a-guy face.

Meanwhile, Kiba and Sasuke had gotten into a heated argument, one that culminated in Kiba grabbing the scroll away from Sasuke and tossing it back over his shoulder to Sakura. Amazingly enough, she didn’t immediately hand it over to her crush. When Sasuke started to argue again, Kiba told him to shut up and used the index and middle fingers of his right hand to doink him on the forehead.

Sasuke went completely rigid when the slightly taller Inuzuka did this, and for a moment Naruto thought he was going to go after his teammate. Instead, he turned away with a glare.

“Fine,” Naruto announced in a loud voice. “My team was just passing by. Here’s our scroll. We can go now, right?” He carefully tossed the scroll to the Grass genin.

“That is the way of prey,” the weirdo said in response as it weighed the scroll in its hand. “When confronted by a predator, they offer up something in their place, hoping to be left alone.”

“But there is no guarantee that you will do that, is there?” Shino asked in a very chill tone. Hinata had regained her breath and moved away from his clone. She was frowning at Naruto, and that bugged him more than a little.

“No, there isn’t,” the Grass ninja agreed with a leer.

“Good,” Naruto announced brightly. “Then I won’t feel bad about this.”

With a poof, the outer seal on the Heaven scroll disappeared, revealing explosive tags wrapped around a blank scroll. They promptly exploded, enveloping the creepy shinobi in a ball of fire.

The enormous snake let out a hiss that sounded like a boiler explosion and lunged for Naruto’s branch. Naruto timed his leap for the last second and managed to vault over the snake’s head and land on its neck, chakra gluing the soles of his sandals to the undulating scales.

No sooner did he land than he was in the middle of a hurricane of fists and feet. Effeminate or not, that weirdo still hit as hard as Gai-sensei. Naruto blocked as best he could, but the blows that slipped past to clip his head were making his ears ring. Finally, a kick to the stomach knocked him loose from the snake, and the instant his feet lost contact the snake was rearing back to swallow him.

Naruto barely had time to use a substitution technique with one of his clones to keep from being swallowed. About half his clones were gone now, most of them crushed by the snake thrashing around. As he created more, he saw Kiba and Akamaru make some kind of spiraling wind attack that gouged into the snake’s belly scales. Elsewhere, Sakura was throwing kunai at the eyes of the giant reptile, without much luck.

Sasuke, surprisingly enough, had decided to fight once more. He’d thrown some kind of weird shuriken trailing wires around the snake. Not only were they starting to cut into the thick scales, but he was swinging around the snake’s body, pelting the Grass shinobi with fireballs as he swung overhead. Shino wasn’t immediately visible, but a wide section of the snake’s scales were beginning to gleam wetly with blood, making Naruto shudder as he recalled Shino mentioning carnivorous strains of kikai bugs.

The Grass freak managed to sidestep the worst of the fireballs as Sasuke flashed overhead, so Naruto sent a brace of shuriken his way to keep him off balance. A trio of his clones contributed as well, even though they were quickly dispelled. He noticed that the ninja’s left hand, which had been holding the scroll, appeared to be horribly burned, with the skin sloughing off in places, but it didn’t seem to slow him down at all.

On Sasuke’s next trip around the snake, his wires had wrapped around the thick body, pulling him low enough that he managed to put both feet into the side of the Grass-nin’s head. For once, their enemy’s eyes widened a little as it was knocked off of the snake and into free-fall. Hinata darted forward out from under cover, leaping at the freak’s back, right hand pulled back for what could well be a lethal Jyuuken strike.

Naruto leapt forward as the snake’s tail caught Kiba and Akamaru right after they’d gouged a wide trench in the armor-like scales on its underbelly. Two of his clones shot down after them, hopefully in time to break their fall.

There was a visible flash as Hinata sent a massive burst of chakra into the center of their enemy’s back. Naruto tried not to think of the mess that must have made out of the freak’s insides. The Grass shinobi arched his back, but instead of signifying death throes, it was just the prelude to him reaching back with one inhumanly flexible arm and grabbing Hinata’s shoulder. Still in free-fall, he hurled the kunoichi at the tree trunk they were falling past. The recoil allowed him to land on a branch, while Hinata struck the tree with a sickening thud. She fell limply away from the trunk, leaving a splotch of blood on the weathered bark. One of Naruto’s clones caught her, but she hung limp in the horrified bunshin’s arms.

Naruto let out a scream of rage just as the snake reared up and swallowed him.

Shino watched as Sasuke leapt after the imposter, his movements even faster than before. Not only was he moving with greater speed, he seemed to anticipate his opponent’s actions by a fraction of a second. After flipping backward to escape his opponent’s counter, the Uchicha came to rest on a higher branch for a moment, facing in Shino’s direction. The gleam of red in his eyes indicated that the class genius had managed to activate his bloodline, the Sharingan.

His first colony had managed to get several kikai onto their opponent while his attention was otherwise occupied. However, the anomalous genin didn’t even seem to notice the chakra they’d managed to drain from him. This meant that either their opponent was another jinchuuriki, which was highly unlikely, or it was a very advanced shinobi, of at least upper jonin rank.

His second colony was working its way towards where he estimated the enormous reptile’s vital organs would be located. But their rate of progress did not bode well for a timely end. As it was, without its master guiding it, it did little more than thrash about, trying to shake them off without much success.

His eyes also tracked the progress of the kage bunshin carrying his teammate Hinata. She wasn’t moving and the clone’s face seemed unusually grave. Shino frowned. He was the last member of Team Eight still in the fight, but his efforts thus far had met with limited success.

“Good, good,” the Grass shinobi murmured as he blocked another combo from the Uchiha heir. “Your skills have progressed nicely, all things considered.” The overly familiar tone of voice seemed to be calculated to induce discomfort and fear. Shino merely found it to be a childish affectation.

Finally, Sasuke began to show signs of fatigue and his attacks slowed. Shino wondered if he’d ever had to spar someone as inexhaustible as Naruto. The Grass ninja grabbed Sasuke’s arm and twisted, locking the joint. His other hand drew back for a strike as Shino soundlessly descended.

The Aburame boy felt a twinge of annoyance as their enemy jerked his head aside an instant before the blade of his kama transited the space it had been occupying. Displaying an inhuman degree of flexibility, the shinobi flipped backwards.

“Yet another insect interferes with my test,” it sneered in an insinuating tone.

“Your statement implies that is supposed to be an insult,” Shino said as he stepped forward, beginning one of his mother’s intermediate attack patterns. The Grass ninja stepped back smoothly, dodging each blow almost as soon as it was launched. He supposed one might consider this frustrating, but he did not deviate from the kata. Overextending a strike in an attempt to catch his elusive foe would only give him an opening to launch a counter-offensive. Instead, Shino stuck with the pattern, the whirling blades giving no opening to his enemy as he steadily forced the unarmed shinobi backward.

“Ah, so those annoying little creatures are yours?” He asked. “Well, it’s easy to deal with such… infestations.” With that he leapt backward and up, bringing his hands up to his mouth at the apogee of his flight and sending a dense stream of fire down at Shino.

Shino crossed his weapons in front of himself and pushed as much chakra into them as he could in an attempt to duplicate one of his mother’s more advanced techniques. The kamas glowed pale blue for a moment before they were engulfed in flames. However, his hands were not burned and the stream of fire seemed to part around him. When it was over, the wood on either side of him was smoldering, but he was untouched. He did, however, fall to one knee as the sudden expenditure of chakra had left him drained and weakened. For all that, he’d only barely repelled the fire technique.

As soon as he landed, the Grass shinobi was charging again. Shino took a deep breath as he regained his feet, but his foe was intercepted by Sasuke, who flung a double-handful of shuriken. They arced out in a seemingly random pattern, none of them coming close to their target – unless one noticed the wires trailing behind them. Before the Grass shinobi knew what was happening, he’d been bound to an adjacent tree trunk and the Uchiha fired off a massive stream of flames that raced down the wires to engulf his enemy.

Shino felt his eyebrows rise over the tops of his glasses. The katon jutsu had actually burned a hole completely through the five meter thick trunk, leaving their foe little more than a smoldering corpse.

And then the corpse darkened and slumped into a pile of mud and Shino felt something strike his back, sending him flying through the air. He held onto his weapons though, and despite acute shortness of breath was able to hook one blade into a passing branch and swing his body up. He landed carefully, then deliberately took a deep breath, wincing as tender ribs flexed. But he was still combat effective, so he waved off Naruto’s clones as they moved to help.

Most of the remaining bunshin were circling around Sasuke and the Grass shinobi. Occasionally one would see an opportunity and attack, but most of them were destroyed without landing a blow. Given the extent of Naruto’s taijutsu training, Shino found this worrisome.

When Sasuke was knocked clear again, all the clones dog-piled the Grass shinobi, only to have it use an advanced variation on the substitution technique. In this case, the enemy’s body was replaced by a log festooned with explosive tags. The ensuing conflagration destroyed most of the remaining clones.

With no immediate sign of their foe, Shino and Sasuke both headed toward Sakura’s perch, a wide bough where the last clones had deposited Hinata, as well as Kiba and Akamaru. All three were unconscious. As they circled around the still-thrashing snake, Sasuke spoke up. “Do you think we should… well, try to recover his body?”

“I don’t think that will be necessary,” Shino answered.

Sasuke turned to glare at Shino as they landed on the wide bough.

“His clones are still here,” Shino murmured. Sasuke’s eyes widened slightly and he turned to look at the snake as Shino knelt by his teammate. Hinata had a split lip, a bloody nose, and the whole side of her face was bruised. At best she’d have a mild concussion. Shino looked up at the worried clone hovering protectively over her. “She’s badly hurt,” Shino said in a flat voice. “If this battle goes on much longer she may die.” Which was the literal truth: the young Hyuuga was in no condition to defend herself.

The clone spun toward the snake, its features drawn into a rictus of fury. It had barely taken a step forward before Shino stabbed it in the back with his kamas. The clone dispersed before it could even change expressions.

“What the hell was that for?” Sakura asked, outraged. Standing this close, he could see how watery her eyes were, and wondered if she’d thought things through.

“Naruto told me something interesting at dinner last night,” was all Shino could say before the Grass shinobi dropped onto the branch beside them. The bug user barely had time to turn before a two-handed combination sent him skidding along the rough bark. But even as he tried to roll with the blow, his colonies registered a massive chakra spike nearby.

Sakura felt worse than useless, pulling out her last kunai and taking a wobbly defensive stance over her unconscious classmates. She knew when it was her turn she wouldn’t last nearly as long as Shino, who was only now coming to a halt in a small blizzard of bark chips. Sasuke and the weird grass guy were moving so fast she could only see blurs now. It was amazing that Sasuke-kun was even holding him off this long.

That was when the giant snake’s head exploded.

A sudden wave of… something… washed over her and she felt her hands trembling. In spite of herself, she found her head turning toward that sickening crunch. Surprisingly, so did the two battling not ten meters from where she stood.

A section of scaly skin at least two meters wide was missing. She could just make out a fist sticking up, coated in thick red fluid – with chunks. Before her gorge could finish rising, the whole snake’s body began to glow brightly and then exploded – just like one of Naruto’s clones.

Sakura flinched away from the explosion, just in time to see that Grass weirdo take advantage of the distraction to attack Sasuke-kun. A huge snake shot out of his sleeve and wrapped around Sasuke’s torso, trapping his arms. The massive body flexed and Sasuke dropped to his knees as the air was forced out of his lungs. Sakura was about to charge forward, hoping her sacrifice would buy Sasuke enough time to escape, when a reddish blur shot past her.

“Get away from them!” something shouted in little more than a guttural roar. Sakura felt her knees turn to water as something, some instinct, made her want to turn and run until she died of exhaustion.

Sakura blinked. Standing in front of her was a rather rumpled-looking Naruto. He was facing away from her, but the hands fisted at his sides were trembling with what had to be rage.

There was a loud crack and the Grass genin went flying backwards to slam into the tree trunk hard enough to make an impression on the wood.

The genin flexed its arms and the wood literally exploded around it. “Those eyes,” it murmured. “So that’s what happened to it.”

“Shut up, you bastard!” Naruto growled.

Sakura rubbed at her eyes, but there was nothing wrong with them. Naruto was not only wrapped up in enough chakra to see, but it was red. What the hell would make him have red chakra? Was it some weird blood limit she hadn’t heard about? Inner-Sakura, the, uhm, more assertive voice inside her head, demanded to know how Naruto, of all people could have a blood limit. Then again, Kiba said he’d heard Team Eight had been in an incredible fight on their patrol mission.

As if to prove the point, Naruto charged forward, punching and kicking in a blur of motion. He was moving even faster than before, and this time he was holding his own, at least for the moment. Snapped out of her daze, she spun toward Sasuke-kun, gripping her last kunai.

The last Uchiha in Konoha was getting red in the face as the snake continued to squeeze. It hadn’t even tried to bite him; it seemed more like it was playing with him, holding Sasuke down for its weirdo master. But it spun and snapped at her as she approached, the sharp fangs missing her by inches.

“Sa-Sakura,” Sasuke gasped. “Get… out of here. Just… go!” he said in a wheezing voice.

Sakura’s eyes widened. Did he think she’d just leave him like this? Who did he think she was? Did he think she was a coward? But his voice didn’t seem angry or disappointed, just… worried. Afraid. Not of the snake, either. But maybe… for her? On one hand, such a realization warmed her slightly, and gave her hopes for the future. On the other hand, Inner Sakura was pissed. Did he think she was that useless?

Sakura scowled, shifting the kunai so it lay under her wrist. She held out her free hand, taunting the snake. This was no different than the slapping game Ino had taught her when they were young. The python took the bait, and lunged at her free hand, even as Sasuke tried to jerk backwards to stop it. Sakura pivoted at the hips, drawing back the empty hand even as the other one shot forward.

The kunai slammed down through the top of the snake’s head with a sickening crunch. In a flash, Sasuke was free of the loosening coils. Sakura spared him a glare as he raced past her, trying not to think too hard about what she’d just done. Throwing up would rather spoil the effect.

“Thanks,” Sasuke murmured as he charged back into the fight.

As the summoned snake disappeared, Sakura scooped up her now free blade, which she decided was now her ‘lucky’ kunai. Then she spun to follow her Sasuke-kun into battle.

No matter how angry he was, no matter how much of the freaky red chakra he used, Naruto couldn’t seem to get a clean shot at this Grass bastard. The freak’s taijutsu was very different from Gai-sensei’s Goken, but it was effective nonetheless. It was hard to stay centered too – the anger that came with the chakra seemed to undermine his control at every opportunity.

But it was down to him again. Shino was down and Hinata was unconscious, maybe dying if Shino was right. Kiba was out as well and the rest of Team Seven was struggling. A hard backfist strike clipped his jaw, sending him stumbling backwards. Even as he regained his footing, the bastard was finishing his seals. So fast. And the next instant Naruto was borne aloft on hurricane winds, glancing off of one tree trunk and slamming into another one. Not bothering to use chakra this time, Naruto dug his fingertips into the bark, only slightly surprised when blunt claws found enough purchase to hold him there.

He had to be careful this didn’t go too far. There was no telling what might happen if he used too much of this. But so far, this wasn’t enough. At least, not enough to put down the bastard that hurt Hinata-chan and Shino.

Sasuke was fighting it now, dodging more than blocking, but still clearly outclassed. Naruto hit the release on his weights and launched himself forward like an arrow.

Sakura was a step or two behind Sasuke, so she saw everything. The Grass weirdo knocked Sasuke tumbling backwards, and then palmed a kunai. It drew back to throw, clearly not aiming at Sasuke, but at their unconscious comrades.

Sasuke, who was about to charge forward, hesitated for an instant. That fatal indecision gave their enemy time to do a complicated seal with his other hand. Sasuke-kun had said that Haku could do seals one-handed, but this seal was not one Sakura had ever seen before. Even as she was racing forward, her muscles locked in place and she was frozen, completely helpless.

“I think it’s time to draw this game to a close,” the weird shinobi murmured. And then its neck began to stretch, impossibly long, carrying its head forward. As it approached, Sakura could note, to her dismay, that the skin of its face was coming off as well, revealing another one beneath it. The mouth yawned wide, just like a snake’s, as the canines enlarged. It dipped toward Sasuke’s neck as it was intercepted by a green blur outlined in crimson.

Naruto didn’t know what the hell that thing was trying to do, but knocking its head off seemed like a great idea. Unfortunately, he’d slightly underestimated his own speed, so rather than having his fist impact the freak’s skull, he’d just grazed its nose. Still, he had the satisfaction of hearing an audible snap of breaking cartilage, right before something clamped down on his forearm and injected molten steel under his skin.

Sakura’s eyes weren’t good enough to see what happened, even if she could have done something. There was a crack, the head snapped back, blood streaming from its nose, and Naruto collapsed to the ground, screaming until he passed out. She could see Sasuke’s hands shake with the effort of trying to move, but he was held just as helpless as her.

The Grass weirdo, head retracted again, glared down at Naruto, and then he said something that made no sense to her. “Well, thab’s juds ab well. All I’b done id tick a fuz in their petty liddle bomb. Led the olb man deal wid it if he can.” He scowled suddenly, then reached up and grabbed his nose, ignoring the blood streaming down. With an even louder crack that turned Sakura’s stomach, the Grass shinobi wrenched it back into position. Then he looked back at Sasuke, smirking at the Uchiha’s helpless glare. “Now where were we?”

Sakura could only stare in horror as that awful head extended toward her Sasuke-kun, dipping down to bite at his neck like some creature from folk-tales.

As that freakish head withdrew back towards its body, Sakura finally found her voice. “What did you do to them?” she shrieked. Sasuke groaned and slowly collapsed, twitching violently.

“I gave Sasuke a little goodbye present,” the strange shinobi answered. He didn’t even glance toward Naruto. “Sasuke will seek me out someday. He will come to me for power.”

He smirked at her again as he began to sink down into the wood. “I haven’t had this much fun in a long time. I have so much to look forward to now.”

With that, the Grass shinobi passed from sight. Sasuke let out a final agonized cry before he fell unconscious, leaving the canopy in silence.

Shino climbed painfully to his feet. His ribs ached with every breath he took, no matter how shallow.

“Are you all right?” a voice asked hesitantly.

He turned to see Haruno Sakura, who had just moved Naruto and Sasuke’s bodies over near Kiba and Hinata, who was finally beginning to stir. Shino nodded and then asked, “What happened? I couldn’t see very clearly.”

“He… he bit them!” she replied with a shudder. “And then they collapsed.” She peered at Sasuke’s neck and then carefully pushed up Naruto’s sleeve. “It left some weird design on their skin as well.”

Shino frowned and carefully made his way over to see. “It appears to be a seal of some sort,” he observed. “But I have no idea as to its purpose.”

“It can’t be good though,” Sakura fretted.

“That is a valid assumption,” Shino agreed. “Logically, we should withdraw from the exam. We have four disabled allies and only the two of us currently conscious. I myself am injured and not fully effective.”

Sakura’s lips pushed together mulishly as she shook her head. “I… I don’t think Sasuke or Kiba would like that,” she said after a moment.

Shino nodded slightly. “For that matter, my teammates are also highly motivated to do well in the exam. While I am unsure as to the status of Naruto and Sasuke, my allies indicate that Hinata and Kiba should be awake soon.”

Sakura’s head came up with an almost audible snap. “But you said Hinata was dying.”

“I said she might die,” Shino corrected. “And if the fight continued on much longer, she may very well have been killed while she was unconscious.”

“But… you told Naruto… I mean his clone…” Sakura asked, frowning.

“My teammate doesn’t always think things through, particularly when he is anxious about a friend,” Shino explained while minutely straightening his glasses. “I surmised that information would provide sufficient motivation to… expedite his release from the summons.”

“What did he do?” Sakura finally asked. “That red chakra… is it a blood limit or something?”

“You will have to ask Naruto,” Shino said firmly. “That information is confidential, and not mine to disseminate.”

“Okay,” Sakura replied in a clearly dubious tone. “So what do we do now?”

“I will recover Naruto’s equipment,” Shino replied. “I believe he has some smelling salts in his backpack. If we can revive Kiba and Hinata, we should be able to move the others to a more defensible locale. At that point we can see if there is a change in Naruto or Sasuke’s condition.”

Sakura nodded.

Hinata couldn’t ever recall her head hurting this much before. Not even after the most rigorous family training session. One eye refused to open all the way, and the skin around it felt puffy and tight. Her mouth was foul with the taste of blood and her upper lip was caked with it. Her body ached as well, feeling like her bones had been pulled apart, ground up, and then shoved back into her abused flesh. She supposed she should be grateful to even be alive, but she hadn’t thought it was possible to hurt this much and not be dying.

All that went right out of her head when she saw who was lying on the tree limb next to her.

“N-Naruto-k-kun!” she lisped, her swollen lips making her own voice sound alien in her ears.

Shino leaned back, discarding the sachet he’d been holding under her nose, as she sat up. She ignored Sakura’s curious looks as she quickly laid her hand on her somnolent friend’s chest. The steady rise and fall of his respiration reassured her, even as her head reminded her why sitting up quickly was a bad idea.

Shino handed her a red pill and a blue pill. “I’ve recovered our packs,” he said quietly. “Your chakra is low enough that it’s advisable to take the soldier pill, and the analgesic is definitely warranted.” Farther down the bough, Hinata could see Sakura start ministering to Kiba, who in turn attended to Akamaru.

Shino returned to peering into the largest pack. “I don’t know why Naruto brought the collapsible tents, but it is a good thing that he did so.”

Naruto and Sasuke showed no signs of waking, so they were carefully bundled up into sections of tent, hoisted by their teammates. Hinata was a little shaky at first, but she insisted on helping to carry her friend.

This, of course, meant that Kiba insisted on carrying Sasuke by himself.

After a very cautious descent, they reached the forest floor. Shino dispatched a fair number of flying kikai bugs, and a few moments later declared the area safe. He led them with a sureness that had Sakura and Kiba a little confused, but he didn’t stop to explain until after they were getting settled into a surprisingly spacious cave left by a partially uprooted tree.

“Some of my allies can comprehend simple images, and transmit back to me rough impressions of what they have seen,” he said without preamble as he helped her settle Naruto down onto the soft earth. “I propose a temporary alliance, at least until our teammates have recovered. Each team will keep their own scrolls and act together for mutual defense. At the moment, both teams are weakened, and many will see us as easy prey.”

“I suppose we can help you guys out,” Kiba drawled, “right, Sakura?”

Sakura winced at the Inuzuka’s arrogant tone.

“I should probably point out,” Shino replied, straightening his glasses in a manner that Hinata had come to associate with him being irritated, “that the only person to actually strike that false genin and still be conscious at this time is Hinata.”

Hinata swallowed as all three of her classmates turned to stare at her.

“A-ano, I only hit him by surprise, I-in the back…” she explained.

“You are a ninja, correct?” Shino asked.

“Uh, yes, Shino-kun,” Hinata answered, dropping her eyes.

“Then the fact that you struck from surprise in no way diminishes your accomplishment, correct?” Shino continued.

“Yes, Shino-kun,” Hinata answered, her voice more sure this time.

“That said, the sentiment Naruto ascribed to your… taijutsu tutor… is an admirable one,” Shino concluded. “It is only appropriate that we offer assistance to fellow shinobi of the leaf. While I believe it would be more prudent to withdraw from the exam, given the circumstances, I will abide by the desire of the majority to continue. If anything, it will be a fair test of our ability to cope in adverse circumstances.”

Kiba frowned and grunted. Sakura turned to Hinata with a questioning look.

“Shino thinks Konoha shinobi should stick together,” the Hyuuga girl explained. She supposed she was just used to the way her friend spoke – he was usually laconic around strangers.

Their first night in the Forest of Death passed quietly, though it was still very tense. After a short meal of ration bars and summoned water they split the night into shifts in which two stood watch at all times. Hinata’s watch was set for the latter part of the night so she’d have time to recover.

While Kiba promptly went to sleep, curled up with his dog, Sakura and Shino used the remaining daylight to set up traps in the area surrounding their refuge.

For her part, Hinata tried to sleep, but found it difficult. Both Sasuke and Naruto began to tremble slightly as their unnatural slumber became increasingly agitated. Both appeared to be running fevers. Though wet cloths applied to their foreheads did little to help, Hinata and Sakura kept reapplying them – if only to have something to do, the Hyuuga realized.

Hinata had been through many unpleasant experiences, many of them related to her family. So it was a surprise to realize that the worst feeling she’d ever experienced in her short life was caused by Uzumaki Naruto.

It was this feeling of profound helplessness that she couldn’t stand. She supposed she’d felt something similar when her mother had died, but that had happened long enough ago that she couldn’t clearly remember that awful day. But now… she could look at Naruto-kun’s face, contorting in pain, and feel like she wanted to die. He was hurting, and she could do nothing to stop it. She tried to remember her father’s face the day her mother died, wondering if he had felt like this… but she couldn’t recall ever seeing him at all. She remembered the branch family servants who came to her room with the news, the old woman who held her as she cried, promising she’d tell no one of her lack of composure.

It was sad how she could remember that old woman’s face more clearly than her mother’s.

Hinata’s breath caught in her throat as she followed her thoughts to their logical conclusion. She didn’t just admire her teammate.

With the light failing, Shino and Sakura armed the last of the kunai traps and returned to the cave. Their task took longer than expected due to the simply ridiculous number of extra kunai and shuriken Naruto was carrying in his pack. But Shino was determined to make their lair as secure as possible, so they used most of them as ammunition for their traps.

Surprisingly, Haruno Sakura seemed to have a gift for designing and setting up traps. Her plans and layouts indicated that she possessed a grasp of tactics and spatial awareness not usually found in kunoichi of her age. This was very much at odds with the persona she’d projected at the Konoha Ninja Academy, where Shino’s memories of her were primarily those of a squealing fan-girl chasing after Sasuke along with the rest of her peers.

Perhaps she had changed, or his initial estimate of her had been as flawed as his opinion of Naruto. In either event, her stock in his estimation rose, even as the sun set.

As they returned to the cave, she displayed yet another net improvement. Hinata had finally managed to fall asleep, but had apparently done so while tending to Naruto. She was curled up on the ground next to her teammate, her head pillowed on his left shoulder. His right forearm, with its peculiar wound, was still propped up on his stomach, the sleeve pushed up to the elbow.

“Awww…” Sakura whispered. She silently made her way to the packs and retrieved an all-weather blanket that she carefully draped over the indigo-haired kunoichi. Looking up at Shino, she silently gestured that they should move back to the entrance.

Once there, Shino silently checked with his allies. The immediate vicinity was still clear of any hostile presence. He looked back when Sakura quietly cleared her throat.

“She really likes him, doesn’t she?” the pink-haired girl asked. “Hinata, I mean.”

Shino just nodded, remembering Haruno’s disparaging attitude toward Naruto that evening at Ichiraku’s.

“That’s so sweet,” Sakura whispered with a wistful smile. “He doesn’t have a clue, does he?” she asked.

“I think he has some inkling, but not explicitly, no,” Shino answered in a guarded tone.

Sakura sighed. “She seems like such a nice girl, I hope he doesn’t hurt her.”

“Uzumaki Naruto is constitutionally incapable of acting with malice aforethought,” Shino declared with what he admitted was some heat.

Sakura frowned at him, but then shook her head. “No, I suppose not. Not intentionally, anyway.”

“That’s an… unexpected admission, coming from you,” Shino replied.

Sakura actually blushed a little. “I’ve… had a few things pointed out to me. There have been times that Naruto really got on my nerves, but I haven’t always been fair towards him either.” She sighed. “I’m trying to be a better person,” she admitted.

“That is… an admirable goal,” Shino allowed.

“So…” Sakura asked, clearly wishing to change the subject, “how far away can your bugs sense trouble?”

Shino inclined his head politely and began his standard lecture on kikai bugs and their capabilities.

By sunrise, Hinata’s head had stopping aching quite so badly. Her face was still a mess though, and it even hurt to blush when she woke up with her unbruised cheek resting on Naruto-kun’s shoulder. To her disappointment, both his and Sasuke’s conditions were unchanged.

Shino said nothing when she’d relieved him at midnight, and she’d fortunately risen before Kiba. Sakura, on the other hand, gave her a smile as she headed back into the cave to rest. Despite her misgivings regarding the kunoichi’s previous behavior, Hinata felt Sakura was being sincere.

A few moments later a yawning Kiba joined her at the mouth of the cave. Shino gave her a brief summary of the traps that had been set, and she was able to double-check them using her Byakugan. Though Shino was sleeping now, he’d assured her that his colony had been instructed to wake him if his pickets encountered anything. Just how that wake-up would occur wasn’t something she really wanted to think about. In the meantime, she would also periodically use her eyes to scan for intruders that managed to elude everything else.

Kiba nodded as she explained their precautions, and then yawned again. “You two are pretty useful to have around,” he said with grudging respect. He hesitated, and then added, “My mom was pretty impressed with your team, and that’s not easy to do. I… appreciate you all helping us yesterday.”

Hinata swallowed and struggled to keep a blush away from her battered face. “We’re all Konoha shinobi,” she replied. “It’s only right that we should help each other.”

Kiba shrugged as he scratched the back of Akamaru’s head. “I don’t think the older genin teams feel that way. Maybe the rookies from our class. And that other team, is that Hyuuga your cousin or something?”

Hinata nodded, not really wanting to think about meeting Neji out here in direct competition. He seemed to resent both her and Naruto, albeit for different reasons.

After a while, they just sat in a semi-comfortable silence, using their enhanced senses to stand watch.

It wasn’t until late morning that their perimeter was breached.

When Naruto gained awareness of himself again, he was lying in what appeared to be a basement. He slowly sat up, wincing as blood began to flow into areas that had been cut off by the hard concrete beneath him. His right arm felt like it was on fire, and he could barely move the shoulder or flex his fingers.

There was no sign of Hinata or Shino, nor of Team Seven. Had they been captured? Had he? Somehow, he didn’t think they were anywhere near.

The air felt damp, like this place had been flooded and only recently had the water receded. The lights were muted, and the illumination they cast lent a gray pallor to everything. At first Naruto thought there were circulating fans that ran roughly, but soon he realized that the sound he was hearing was too irregular to be mechanical.

Turning around, there was no break in the patterns of hallways that surrounded him, but the sounds seemed to be slightly louder in one direction. With nothing better to do, he slowly walked toward the source of the noise.

As he shuffled along, he kept trying to flex the fingers of his right hand. They barely moved and the pain grew worse. Looking down at his forearm, he could see a weird black seal that looked like three tomoe in a spiral. The skin around them was angry and red, and he swore a faint ribbon of vapor appeared to be rising from the center of the design.

The further Naruto walked toward the source of the noise, the more uneasy he became. It was a sensation that was both disturbing and oddly familiar. It was a little like being around Gaara again, but not quite. If anything, it was even worse.

Finally, the hallway opened into a room with a very high ceiling. Dominating the far wall was a huge metal gate with vertical bars at least fifteen meters high. The two halves of the portal were closed, but there was no bar or lock. Instead a thin strip of paper held the massive gates together. The ofuda was adorned with a single kanji character that was, oddly enough, the symbol for ‘seal’.

As Naruto peered at the seal, that oppressive feeling spiked again and an enormous pair of red eyes appeared over a mouth full of huge teeth. The features were shrouded in a haze of red chakra and Naruto began to put the pieces together.

“Boy, come closer,” a deep voice rumbled, resonating in Naruto’s bones.

“I think I’ll just stay right here,” Naruto answered in a wary tone.

A set of gigantic claws moved out of the darkness, sliding between the bars of the gate. As one, they slammed down onto the concrete, the points scarring the unyielding floor.

“I’d like to eat you, but this gate won’t open,” the voice growled. “Damnable seal.”

That only confirmed Naruto’s suspicions. “Well I’m not real happy about having you here either, asshole!” He glared right into eyes that were bigger than his body as a lifetime’s worth of frustration and anger filled his mind with flames. “If you’d just had the decency to freaking die when the Yondaime kicked your ass, I wouldn’t have been putting up with crap from everyone as long as I can remember!”

The huge eyes blinked. Whatever reaction Naruto had been expecting, it wasn’t the rusty chuckle that echoed from behind the gate. “You didn’t mind it when you were using my chakra to save those two weaklings you run around with.”

Naruto scowled. “Well, if you know that, then you know that one of those weaklings is probably the only reason I didn’t slit my wrists afterward. Practically every crappy thing that’s happened in my life is because of you, you damned fox.” Hinata had been badly hurt getting a solid hit on that freak – he wasn’t going to let anyone call her a weakling. He just hoped she was okay, wherever she was.

“You’ve got a lot of nerve saying that,” the Kyuubi no Kitsune growled, “considering that it was your precious Yondaime that ruined both our lives with his little technique.”

Naruto bit back his first response. That was at least one lecture of Iruka-sensei’s that he’d paid close attention to. Despite all that had happened, the story of the Fourth had only strengthened his desire to become Hokage some day. “And whose village were you destroying at the time?” he asked sarcastically.

“That’s a long story, you hairless monkey,” the demon growled. “But we have more immediate problems. Look at your arm.”

Naruto glanced down at his paralyzed forearm. The seal was burning now, covered in purple and black flames, and the pain was getting worse.

“You managed to let my den get marked with another seal, you careless buffoon,” the Kyuubi growled.

“What the hell is it doing?” Naruto asked nervously. The fact that the demon actually sounded a little worried was setting off all kinds of warning bells in his mind.

“It’s trying to tap into your chakra coils. It seems to be designed to strengthen the wearer by adding its own chakra to the body’s inner coil system. I’m not sure where it’s pulling that black chakra from, but it’s bad news.”

“How is more chakra bad?” Naruto asked cautiously.

“It’s… not… normal chakra. Portions of it seem to be gravitating toward your pea-sized brain. In addition to whatever it might try to do to your alleged mind, your coils are already under stress from holding your chakra as well the fractions of my chakra that leak out of this cursed seal. There isn’t room for a third chakra in here.” The huge lips twisted into a feral sneer. “You don’t want to explode, do you?”

Naruto shook his head slowly. “So what can we do about it?”

“Well, if you hadn’t wimped out and gone unconscious, I’d suggest just cutting the arm off at the elbow,” the fox suggested. “Oh, stop making faces. I bet I could grow it back. Eventually. Anyway, due to your pitiful pain threshold, we have to do this the hard way.”

“The hard way?” Naruto asked, feeling a bit ill. If cutting off his arm wasn’t the hard way, he wasn’t sure he wanted to know what was.

“I push as much chakra as I can past this seal and hope that seal gives way before your inner coils explode,” the demon explained.

Naruto felt his mouth drop open. “That sounds like a really bad idea to me!” he protested.

“I’m not overjoyed either. If you die, I die. But as much as being inside of you is an exercise in torment,” the voice continued, “being inside of you while you are being controlled by whoever put that seal on you would be worse.”

“How do I know I can trust you?” Naruto finally asked.

“Can you afford not to?” the voice asked as the eyes narrowed. “If you fall under that seal’s influence, who do you think will be in the most danger?”

Naruto took a deep breath and let it out. The pain in his arm was growing worse by the second. “What do I do?” he asked.

“Just stand there and don’t resist,” the voice replied, the deep reverberations dropping away as the volume lowered. “I need you to act as the conduit for this,” it continued as a flood of red chakra began to seep out from under the gate, heading toward Naruto’s feet.

“And try not to die,” the Kyuubi’s voice concluded as the chakra reached Naruto and his world exploded in agony.

Hinata heard Shino stirring in the cave behind her even as her eyes picked up a trio of fast moving shapes through the canopy. Shino had roused Sakura and made it to the mouth of the cave when the first traps went off.

Amid the twangs and whooshes there were muted curses, indicating that some of the projectiles had found their mark. Finally, there was a loud yell of frustration followed by a cry of Zankūkyokuha as a copse of trees near the mouth of the cave was obliterated.

“Are you sure this is the right place?” a female voice asked in a plaintive tone. “That note might not have been from sensei.”

“Yes I’m sure, Kin,” a deeper voice answered. “I can feel the echoes of a cave from my ground waves. That’s probably where they are hiding like little rodents.”

“That’s good enough for me, Dosu,” another male voice replied. A thin man wearing a tan tunic over a grey camouflage jumpsuit stepped out into the clearing. Hinata didn’t need to see the symbol on his forehead to recognize one of the sound genin they’d encountered before the first exam.

“Yo,” he said in an arrogant drawl, “we’re here for the Uchiha.”

“Well you can’t have him!” Sakura snapped, clearly incensed by his cavalier attitude.

“We’re here to kill him,” the bulkier leader in the grey tunic, bandages, and fur mantle said as he joined his subordinate, “a few more bodies doesn’t really matter, does it Zaku?”

The skinnier sound-nin shook his head, smiling.

“Why are we even bothering to talk to these brats?” the long-haired sound kunoichi asked as she joined them.

Hinata glanced at Shino, who didn’t even open his mouth. She knew from experience that he’d have kikai bugs seeded all around the clearing. It was only a matter of time before they began draining the chakra from the sound nins.

Then Dosu stuck out his right arm and rapidly spun in a circle. “We were warned about your tricks, freak,” he snarled. “But it’s not that hard to figure out the resonance frequency of your bugs’ shells, is it?”

Kiba and Akamaru both let out low cries, Kiba grabbing at his ears as Akamaru whined and put his paws over his ears. Shino winced visibly as well and Hinata wondered how many of his allies he’d just lost. He’d have to pull the remainder inside his body as well, if he wanted to protect them.

Her feet were in motion before she even finished that thought. Her audacity appeared to have caught the sound nins off guard, and she was only a couple of steps from the leader, her hand drawn back for a Jyuuken strike, when a solid wall of air sent her flying. Hinata rolled when she struck the ground and flowed back onto her feet to see Zaku moving his open palms to point at her.

Hinata had just registered the presence of the metallic air nozzles embedded in his palms when he shouted Zankuha and a ripple of air began racing towards her. She leapt to the side as the shockwaves demolished a tree where she’d been standing. Glancing back toward the cave, she could see Shino charging out with his kamas unfolded, followed by Sakura as Kiba struggled to his feet. She hadn’t heard the ultrasonic waves the Sound leader had used to destroy Shino’s kikai bugs, but evidently Inuzuka had a wider hearing range than normal. Only now it was proving to be a liability.

Kin began throwing senbon needles at Sakura as Shino stalked toward Dosu. He couldn’t use most of his jutsus until that one was disabled. Unfortunately, that left her facing an opponent with a strong long-ranged attack.

Hinata might ordinarily have been concerned, since she was facing someone who was not a good match-up for her skills. But she had no doubt what would happen if they made it into the cave while her Naruto-kun lay helpless. Both of the unconscious boys would be dead in moments. That was not something that would happen while she had breath in her body.

So she began stalking her opponent, carefully dodging his attacks as she worked her way closer and closer. Zaku’s mounting frustration as he continued to miss her seemed to distract him from his growing peril, a realization that brought a slight smile to her cracked lips.

Remembering Kurenai-sensei’s lectures about maintaining situational awareness, she spared a glance for her teammates as she rolled away from another hurricane blast.

Sakura seemed to be having some trouble with her opponent. She’d been struck in the leg by one of the needles, but her movements suggested that she was at least a little disoriented. Hinata hoped the needles weren’t poisoned.

Shino, on the other hand, had managed to close with his foe. His weapons flashed in the morning light as they spun in his hands. Dosu was blocking with two kunai and his right forearm, which appeared to be armored, but he was unable to counterattack and his uniform was dotted here and there with blood from minor wounds. Shino-kun seemed quite intent on avenging his fallen allies.

Hinata dodged another blast, moving in even closer, when Kiba leaped out of the bushes and slammed into Zaku. The sound nin let out a grunt as they slammed into the ground with Kiba on top. The Inuzuka was moving a kunai toward the sound nin’s throat, either to take him prisoner or kill him, when the whole point became moot. Hinata didn’t even have time to shout a warning as Zaku got one of his upturned palms onto Kiba’s stomach and blasted him into the air.

She charged forward as a second blast caught Kiba in the air, tearing off a piece of his jacket and sending him tumbling toward Shino and Dosu’s battle.

Fortunately, Shino heard Kiba’s grunt of pain, and stepped back before his swinging blades accidentally eviscerated his ally.

Unfortunately, that seemed to be the opening Dosu was waiting for. The sound nin quickly swung his right arm around in front of him and Hinata could almost see the ripples coming off of it and converging on Kiba and Shino. Kiba let out a strangled cry as they converged on his head, making blood shoot out of his ears as his eardrums ruptured. Shino bent forward as the sound waves slammed into his torso with a visceral crunch. He barely retained hold of his weapons as a bright gout of blood exploded from his mouth.

Zaku watched this as well, and didn’t realize her proximity or his own peril until the last second. As Hinata made her strike, he was just raising one palm to stop her. She launched the index and middle fingers of her right hand, wreathed with a visible glow of chakra, at her foe. At the last instant she diverted her strike, sending the chakra spike lancing into the nozzle that was just being brought to bear. The results were spectacular.

The back of Zaku’s hand exploded into a spray of aerosol blood, coating his face and blinding him, even as his other hand came up and fired blindly at her. Unfortunately, as close as she was, she couldn’t completely avoid his counterstrike, and was launched back toward the cave.

Hinata struck the ground hard, knocking the wind out of her. She made it to her hands and knees in time to see Sakura catch Kin in the side of the head with a very solid punch that dropped the sound kunoichi to her knees. But the next instant a kunai thrown by Dosu buried itself in Sakura’s upper arm while another ripped through her hair, narrowly missing her skull.

But neither that nor the screamed curses of Zaku could distract Hinata from what was happening inside the cave. Landing where she did, she had a clear view of both Sasuke and Naruto. Both were wreathed in dark purple chakra that flickered and waved like some sickly fire.

Suddenly Sasuke stood up, a black silhouette amidst the purple flames, but with blotches of glowing red oozing across his skin like flowing embers. The flames around Sasuke died down a little, but glowing red marks on his skin remained, eventually fading to black.

Naruto jerked awake and screamed as the purple flames around him spiked even higher. He made it up to his hands and knees. Despite his violent trembling, Hinata could see that the seal on his arm was replaced by a jet of purple-black fire that extended nearly a foot from his skin. With her Byakugan active, she could see that his coil system was now under attack, with red chakra fighting black chakra, and blue chakra caught in the middle. His tenketsu were opening on their own and vomiting out mixed and contaminated chakra. His coils heaved and began to crack.

Naruto was dying.

“Naruto!” Hinata gasped. She didn’t think she’d even spoken aloud, but he looked up, directly into her horrified eyes.

And he smiled.

“Hinata… chan…” he groaned as he sat back and gripped his forearm with his left hand, right around the seal. He took a deep agonized breath. Then he pulled a kunai from his pouch and slammed it into his forearm, directly into the seal.

There was a loud explosion that rocked Hinata backwards. It even made Sasuke step back as his chakra flames wavered under the onslaught. He turned to look back at Naruto as the kunai was ripped from his fingers and the half-melted fragments were imbedded in the wall of the cave.

The purple-black chakra expanded outward in a shockwave that covered the clearing. It was just blind luck that Sasuke’s aura blocked Hinata from the worst of it, because she could see the others shiver and twitch as it passed over them. The tongue of flame extruding from Naruto’s forearm abruptly switched from purple to red flames as his aura became completely red. And to Hinata’s relief, his chakra coils stopped pulsating like they wanted to rupture and explode.

Sasuke nodded and stalked out of the cave, his altered skin making him look more than a little monstrous. His roving eyes stopped moving when he saw Sakura wrenching the kunai from her arm. “Sakura,” he said in an eerie voice. “Who the hell did that to you?”

Sakura’s eyes widened but she didn’t answer. Hinata was a bit distracted herself as Naruto slowly walked out of the cave. He reached out and oh so gently let his fingertips touch a fresh scrape on her cheek. “Who?” he asked in a far too calm voice. He looked over toward Zaku, who was wrapping a bandage around his wounded hand.

Sakura seemed to remember that they were still in a fight, because she quickly turned to check on Dosu and Zaku. Sasuke’s eyes narrowed as he seemed to recognize the crumpled form of his teammate at Dosu’s feet.

Both Naruto and Sasuke seemed to disappear as Zaku fired a massive blast with his uninjured hand. Dosu was just starting to swing his right arm around when Sasuke appeared behind him. The number one student of his class reached over, grabbed each side of the sound-nin’s head and gave a sharp twist. When he let go, Dosu dropped to the ground like a puppet with its strings cut, blood pouring from the corpse’s nose and mouth. Zaku was pivoting for another blast when Naruto appeared beside him, grabbed his wrist in a chakra-wreathed fist, and crushed it utterly.

Sasuke glanced over at Naruto, and then began to stalk toward the remaining sound ninja, his face impassive and his tread as implacable as an executioner’s.

Sakura seemed to realize what he planned because she lurched forward at the last second and wrapped her arms around Sasuke, pleading with him to stop. “Sasuke!” she finally whispered, “what’s wrong with you?”

“I… I feel pretty strong right now. He gave that to me. Now I can truly be an avenger.” Sasuke glanced down at a smear of blood on Sakura’s leg. “Now it’s her turn.”

“You are not the Sasuke I know!” Sakura said in a tearful voice. “Just… just stop this. Please, Sasuke?”

Kin had finally recovered at this point, and looked like she’d rather be semiconscious again. She was visibly cowering until Sasuke finally grunted. “All right, Sakura,” he quietly acquiesced. But when he looked back at Kin his voice was hard again. “Get your teammates and go. Now.” The black marks slowly began to fade from his skin.

Naruto turned to glare at the now-disarmed Zaku. “You’d better help her,” he added with a glare.

It was only after they left that anyone noticed that, accidentally or intentionally, they’d left behind their scroll.

16

Mortal Combat

On his way to the hospital, Naruto cursed sulphurously when a clone’s memories suddenly surged into his mind. The clone was cutting through the hot springs carrying a bag of carryout from the dango shop when it was dispersed. Hinata had hesitantly asked if they could try something besides ramen the previous day, causing Naruto to smack himself on the forehead. He tended to get into a routine with his improvised lunch arrangements and forgot that not everyone is as crazy about his favorite food.

Of course, Hinata immediately thought he was upset at her instead of himself.

Naruto shook his head. It had taken the rest of his afternoon visit to convince her that he wasn’t angry with her. This was complicated by a growing sense of rage he felt toward her so-called family. Now that he had a rough idea of what life was like in the Hyuuga Clan, it was easier for him to see how it had twisted his friend.

Now he was doubly angry. His clone had seen a white-haired old man crouched down in front of the fence that screened the women’s bathing area. The creepy old pervert was emitting a high-pitched giggle that made Naruto’s skin crawl, even in memory. Disgusted, the clone demanded to know what he was doing there.

No sooner had the words left the ersatz Naruto’s mouth than there was a loud pop and the old pervert was now facing him, sitting on top of a massive orange toad. The toad’s mouth cracked open and an enormously long tongue shot out and wrapped itself around the clone’s waist.

“You keeping making so much noise, you’re going to get me caught,” the white-haired old man said in a dismissive tone. There was a glimpse of a horned forehead protector holding back the white mane. Ninja? Wearing wooden geta on his feet? “Why don’t you cool off?” the strange shinobi asked and the disgustingly slimy tongue flexed and whipped the clone off its feet and into the aqueduct that fed into the bath house.

Unfortunately, the impact with the water was hard enough to disperse the clone. Its last memory was flinging the bag of dango away from the canal.

Naruto scowled and immediately summoned ten more clones. Without a word, they took off for the hot springs to reclaim the dango… and keep an eye out for a white-haired older man in olive robes and a red over-jacket.

When he was still two blocks from the hospital, his mood became even more disgusted. His clones didn’t find anything near the hot springs, aside from a lot of angry looking women. Of course, one of them assumed the green-clad boys were there to peep as well, and they’d been attacked and dispersed before they could ask a single question.

Naruto saw a bakery right across the street from where he was standing, but he knew the owners hated him on sight. Even if they deigned to serve him, he didn’t want Hinata eating anything they knew was being sold to ‘the demon boy’. He sighed and ducked into an alley. One quick henge later, he looked like a blond version of Kiba, without the facial tattoos. He strode out of the alley and crossed the street toward the bakery. Ordinarily, he wouldn’t want to support their stupid business in any way, but this was for Hinata.

Naruto was just leaving the hospital when one of the chuunin that assisted the Hokage caught up to him.

“Naruto-san, the Hokage would like to see you as soon as possible,” the young man said in an oddly respectful tone.

Naruto frowned. It was almost time for his next session with Gai-sensei. Well, there wasn’t anything he could do about it. He created another clone and instructed it to find Gai-sensei and tell him Naruto had been summoned to the Hokage’s office.

Naruto turned back to the chuunin, who looked slightly disconcerted, and simply said “Let’s go.”

The chuunin set a brisk pace, but Naruto wished they could get there sooner. He had no idea what jii-san wanted, but the way this day had gone so far, it probably wasn’t good.

At least Hinata had liked the sweet bean buns.

Sakura stared after Naruto and the chuunin as they hurried down the street. Ino had to elbow her twice to get her attention, which almost sparked an argument. The word “Ino-pig” was about to leave her lips when she caught herself. Rebuilding a relationship with her former best friend was more work than she’d imagined. It was a little disturbing how ingrained some of her more… aggressive… reactions had become. It was one thing to realize that you weren’t a very nice person, but doing something about it was quite another.

Instead, she made an effort to smile at her old friend. Ino returned it, a little tentatively. “Was that Naruto?” the blond asked.

Sakura nodded. “I think so,” she answered. Ino frowned. She seemed a little ambivalent where their former classmate was concerned. Not that Sakura had much room to talk.

Things had been simpler at the Academy. Uzumaki Naruto was the class clown and an incessant prankster. He was really irritating, but it was also… reassuring… in a way. You could always predict what he’d do in a given situation. It was always “ramen” this or “Hokage” that. He was… safe.

Sakura had seen another side of him during the exams. His advice to Lee was something that still stung in her memory, mostly because it was true. Then the terrifying fight against that Grass ninja, when Naruto’s team jumped in without hesitation. Even worse was the attack by the Sound genin team, and the terrifying auras Naruto and Sasuke had adopted when they woke up.

However, the biggest shock of all was during the preliminary matches. She wanted to cringe when Sasuke brought up Hinata’s defeat. Even if it was a valid tactic, it dishonored someone that had fought to defend him when he was unconscious. But she hadn’t even had time to make a face before Naruto had decisively ended the match. Where was the class clown now?

Sasuke refused to talk about the match, even after the bandage was removed from his jaw. But when a disappointed-looking Kakashi-sensei announced they were starting extra training sessions, Sasuke threw himself into the lessons with a disturbing intensity.

“I heard he goes to visit her every day,” Ino said in a faint voice.

“Who?” Sakura asked, jolted out of her reverie.

“One of the ladies visiting the shop complained that she’s seen him at the hospital every day this week,” Ino clarified. “He must be visiting Hinata.”

That was rather… nice, Sakura concluded. She wondered if Sasuke would visit her in the hospital if she had been injured. She shook her head. Not if he had the option of training.

Sakura made an effort to change the subject and turned to Ino, asking her if Chouji or Shikamaru were nervous about their upcoming matches.

Listening to her old friend rant about her teammates was a balm to uneasy nerves. It was good to have her back.

Yuuhi Kurenai had just finished summarizing her notes when the messenger from the Hokage arrived. She received the message from the young chuunin with a nod and opened it. It was a polite request for her to report to the Hokage’s tower at her earliest convenience. On an impulse, she decided to take her notes with her. She had little doubt the Hidden Sand jinchuuriki would come up in their discussion and she might need to reference the reports she’d gathered. She knew the Sand jinchuuriki had been under close surveillance since she’d made her original report, but he or his jonin-sensei must have sensed the watchers. They’d done nothing suspicious, but they were still shinobi – the lack of suspicious activity was itself cause for concern.

Kurenai stretched her shoulders and twisted her back to loosen it up as she began walking to the center of the village. She’d been at this for days, but the safety of Naruto and Shino demanded no less.

It was unfortunate that she’d been forced to miss watching Gaara’s fight with Rock Lee. From Maito Gai’s description of the match, the Suna Genin had incredibly formidable defenses, even though he’d been unable to match Lee’s speed for most of the battle. More disturbing were reports from Mitarashi Anko concerning the crushed bodies she’d discovered in the aptly-named Forest of Death. The cause of death was massive blunt trauma, though the masses of sand filling the victims’ noses and throats would have killed them almost as quickly. Only a few grains remained, but the ruptures and distention of the oral and nasal cavities suggested they had once been packed full of sand. All the evidence suggested this was the handiwork of Sabaku no Gaara.

The fact that the genin was a killer was not lost on Kurenai. While a few deaths were considered unavoidable in the constant skirmishing during the second exam, the fact remained that this Gaara person seemed to have no compunctions regarding the taking of human life. Moreover, given the defenses Gai described, it was more than likely that Gaara’s victims had no way of even hurting the Sand genin. The overall psychological profile she’d managed to develop was just as grim.

The political implications of the Kazekage entering such a dangerous predator into Konoha’s chuunin exam were just as ugly. However, that was the Hokage’s job to evaluate. Hers was to get him the most accurate information possible.

Kurenai had just gone over her data on Gaara when Naruto arrived.

“Hokage-sama, Sensei,” Naruto greeted them with a polite bow, before quietly sitting in the other chair. Kurenai raised an eyebrow, wondering if she was being set up for another prank. Then she noticed out of the corner of her eye the old man’s expression of stark disbelief. Maybe the joke wasn’t on her this time.

“Ah, Naruto,” the Hokage said after a moment. “I read your sensei’s report regarding the events that occurred during the second exam. You said that you actually… spoke to it?”

Naruto nodded soberly, and Kurenai was inwardly pleased that he was taking this seriously. “It didn’t like the idea of someone placing another seal on me. He said it could have effects on my mind, and he didn’t want his vessel being controlled by someone else. Also, the seal’s chakra was interfering with both my chakra and the fox’s chakra.” Naruto paused, scratching his head. “He was really a jerk about it, but I think he was actually worried.”

The Sandaime puffed on his pipe while he digested this. Kurenai was a little disconcerted at the idea of the Kyuubi being worried about anything. It was like hearing about a typhoon that had its feelings hurt. “And you were able to remove Orochimaru’s seal by forcing your chakra into it?”

Naruto nodded. “Mine, but mostly the fox’s chakra. It hurt, right up until the stupid thing exploded,” her student explained, unconsciously clutching his right forearm. “It’s sort of like when you get a really infected pimple, so you squeeze the skin around it until it pops. It hurts the worst right before it explodes all over-”

“Yes, thank you Naruto!” Kurenai said quickly. She’d had her share of blemishes when she was younger, and had no desire to be reminded of all the gory details. No matter how apt a metaphor it might be.

She glanced quickly toward the Hokage, but the old man was merely nodding thoughtfully. “As the seal has worked constantly since you were a baby, the steady flow of chakra no doubt enlarged your coils, reinforcing them. That’s why the pressure didn’t rupture them.” He nodded. “Naruto, since then, have you noticed any changes with respect to the seal or… your prisoner?”

Naruto shrugged, looking a little uncomfortable. “Not really. Sometimes I feel the red chakra a little easier when I’m mad at something, but I think that started before the Chuunin Exam.”

The Hokage nodded gravely. “That doesn’t sound too bad, Naruto, provided you keep your temper under control. I know you didn’t ask for this responsibility, but you need to make sure there are not any… accidents.”

Kurenai knew the Hokage was definitely hinting about the upcoming finals, but hoped he didn’t press the point. Hyuuga Neji’s behavior during his match with Hinata was just short of criminal, and her student’s desire to return the favor was not something she disagreed with. On the other hand, if Naruto did get out of hand… some might seek to use that against him. Still, better to not belabor the point, or else Naruto might think they were more interested in protecting the Hyuuga prodigy.

Fortunately, the Hokage was satisfied with Naruto’s quick nod. “I’ve also asked a former student of mine to return to Konoha. With all the people looking for him, I actually expected him before now. Apparently he was delayed. In any event, Jiraiya is an expert on seals, and he helped the Fourth develop some of the techniques that went into the seal placed on you, Naruto. He is probably the person most qualified to make sure the seal hasn’t been damaged in any way.” Kurenai’s eyebrows lifted when she realized who the Hokage was referring to.

There was a knock at the door, and one of the chuunin guards stuck his head inside. “Jiraiya is here, Hokage-sama,” he said in a quietly reverent tone. From what little Kurenai had heard about the Hokage’s legendary students, known throughout the land as the Sannin, it was more than merited.

After a nod from the Hokage, the door opened all the way and a tall, broad-shouldered man strode into the room. He wore dull green robes over a mesh shirt she could see glimpses of at the neck and wrists. On top of everything else he wore an oversized red vest with a yellow circle over each breast. Archaic wooden geta clacked on the floor, but his stride exhibited the steadiness that spoke of long experience wearing them.

The white hair suggested age, but his face was for the most part unlined. Kurenai estimated him to be in his fifties – a most dangerous age for shinobi. Without the energy of youth, some shinobi were content to slow down at that age, to take things easier. The more serious ones refused to concede anything to the passage of years, possibly even intensifying their training regimen. While maybe not as resilient as they once were, they stayed every bit as strong, and their accumulated experience made them far deadlier. Yuuhi Kurenai did not need to guess into which category this man had fallen. She almost unconsciously straightened her spine. This was obviously a man worthy of respect.

The fact that he was casually munching on a stick of dango only reinforced this impression. Not many would be comfortable acting so casual in the Hokage’s office. Though she understood that Naruto was an exception to that rule…

As if on cue, she heard her genin erupt in sputters of outrage.

“You no-good bastard thief!” Naruto shouted, jumping up from his chair.

“Naruto!” Kurenai snapped, too shocked at his reaction to do much more than gape.

“He’s still eating the evidence!” Naruto snarled, pointing a finger in the man’s face as he consumed the last of the sweet treat. “I bought that for Hinata-chan!” he added angrily, as if that made it even more contemptible. Kurenai frowned.

Jiraiya cocked his head and peered at Kurenai through hooded eyes. “Isn’t he a little young for a girlfriend?” he asked.

Naruto’s shout of protest was ignored with a wave of the Sannin’s hand. “I just kept it from going to waste,” Jiraiya replied casually, picking at his teeth with the dango stick. “Your clone shouldn’t have been so rude. Are you normally too lazy to run your own errands?” he asked curiously.

Naruto was red in the face, fists clenched, and emitting more than a small amount of killing intent. Kurenai was about to say something when she watched him visibly gather himself, opening his fists and closing his eyes until his complexion was back to normal. When he opened his eyes again, their normal blue tint seemed more like winter ice than summer skies.

“My clone just wanted to know why you were peeping into the women’s baths,” Naruto replied in an icy tone.

Kurenai spun toward Jiraiya, vaguely aware that there was now a kunai in her hand. “Is this true?” she asked in a deceptively mild voice. Out of the corner of her eye, she saw the Hokage massaging his forehead with a pained expression.

“Of course not!” Jiraiya blustered. “I was doing research!”

“Research on what?” Kurenai asked calmly.

“Er, spying techniques. That’s part of my cover, you know. No one takes a drunken old lecher seriously, so I can gather a lot of information with no one noticing.” By the end of his explanation, he was clearly on a roll, chest puffed out and chin up. “I’m willing to make any sacrifice necessary to serve Konoha, for I am Myouboku Mountain’s Monk of the Toad Spirits, also known as the Toad Hermit!” With that he struck a dramatic pose that made Kurenai roll her eyes. This was the Hokage’s expert?

“Jiraiya has sent back quite a bit of information,” the Hokage said in a pained voice. It didn’t escape Kurenai’s attention that he hadn’t commented on the rest of his former student’s claims. “I expected you at least a week ago,” the Hokage continued, directing his attention toward Jiraiya now. “What delayed you?”

“Well,” Jiraiya began, grimacing as he stretched his neck until it cracked, “someone had the brilliant idea to send this kid out to the border with Earth country. I heard a few rumors as I was coming back and decided to chase them down. A renegade faction in Iwakagure was putting out word they wanted to hire missing-nins for an assassination within Konoha. Normally, that would require a bank full of ryou, but since the target was only a genin, some of the more desperate mercenaries were getting interested.”

The Hokage scowled fiercely. “This is getting completely out of hand,” he said, “has something been done about them?”

Jiraiya nodded smugly. “I had a few words with some contacts I maintain in the Tsuchikage’s office, and they leaked the information to the right people. Iwagakure doesn’t want a war with Konoha, at least not this year.”

Almost in spite of herself, Kurenai felt a bit of gratitude toward the Sannin. The last thing Naruto needed right now was more people that wanted him dead.

“That’s good, as long as no hint of your involvement gets out,” the Hokage said in a worried tone. “How reliable are these contacts of yours?”

“Very,” Jiraiya answered, “they know I’m using them to some extent, but exposing this faction furthered their own interests as well. Besides, they are big fans of my work.”

“Ah,” the Hokage replied in a careful tone. “That’s useful, I suppose.”

“Fans?” Kurenai asked curiously as she slid the kunai back into its concealed sheath.

“Of my great literary works,” Jiraiya responded in a grandiose manner.

“Hmph,” Naruto grunted. “If it was written by you, it’s probably porn.”

“Naruto!” Kurenai snapped. Disreputable or not, this Jiraiya had done them no small service. It wouldn’t be prudent to alienate him.

On the other hand, as Jiraiya began to harangue Naruto about respecting his elders, Kurenai did notice an odd expression flicker across the Hokage’s face. It was an odd mixture of guilt and amusement. “My apologies, Jiraiya-sama,” she said in a formal tone. “My student is, as you can see, still upset. I am, however, fairly well read and I am curious to see if I may have read one of your books. What are their titles?”

“I’m about to publish Icha-Icha Paradise, volume seven!” Jiraiya announced proudly, ignoring the frantic waving of the Hokage’s hands.

“The books with the… orange covers?” Kurenai asked, slipping the kunai back into her hand.

“Why yes,” Jiraiya answered slyly. “I can get you an advance copy, if you like.”

“Naruto,” Kurenai said through slightly clenched teeth. “Would you mind waiting in the hallway for a moment?”

“No, Sensei,” Naruto said quickly and scuttled out of the room. A distant portion of her mind wondered why he had gone so pale. Maybe he was even more disgusted than she was.

“Good idea,” Jiraiya said with a leer that turned her stomach. “Some things shouldn’t be discussed around brats, at least not until they are older.”

Kurenai turned to glare at the older man. Sannin or not, she’d wondered about the source of Kakashi’s disgusting books for a while now. “I’m not sure what conversational topics you are referring to, but there are things I do not want a boy of that age exposed to. Among them is my opinion of the garbage you write.”

Jiraiya’s mouth dropped open. He turned shocked eyes toward the Hokage, but out of the corner of her eye, Kurenai saw the old man looking down as he fiddled with his pipe.

“It’s bad enough to even have those thoughts, to treat women as mere sex objects, but to publish them so others can revel in your perversity? Do you know how many times I’ve had to sit through jonin meetings and listen to Hatake Kakashi, an otherwise skilled shinobi of the leaf, reading one of your books and giggling like an adolescent schoolgirl? Half of the people I deal with don’t take me seriously as a jonin because of the sexist ideas that infest our society, and here you are spreading the infection.”

Kurenai took a deep breath. This was an issue that had annoyed her for as long as she could remember, but this immature idiot was still a high ranking shinobi who could help her student. Stabbing him, while highly satisfying, would not be prudent. “Uzumaki Naruto,” she said in a cold voice, “has put up with a lot of crap in his life, little of it deserved. This village hates him for incredibly stupid reasons, yet he has persevered and exceeded even my expectations. If you do anything to damage that, or corrupt him in any way, you will answer to me, and Sannin or not, I will find a way to make you pay. Is that understood?”

Jiraiya’s face went stony during her tirade, and Kurenai braced herself for an explosion of wounded male pride. Instead, he just cocked his head and cracked a lop-sided grin. “Little brat really got to you, didn’t he?” he asked.

Things were a little calmer when Naruto was summoned back into the Hokage’s office. While it was a relief to feel the tension was mostly gone, he was a little disappointed to find the old pervert unharmed.

He didn’t even want to think of what Kurenai-sensei would do to him if she caught him peeking into the women’s baths. He wasn’t even sure she realized she was holding a kunai in her hand, but the fact that the hand in question was at waist level made quite an impression on him.

He was slightly self-conscious when the toad hermit told him to take off his jacket and t-shirt. If Kurenai-sensei and Hokage-sama weren’t there, he might even have bolted. Who knew what kind of sick stuff the old pervert might be into?

It didn’t help that this Jiraiya guy couldn’t keep from making comments once he was naked from the waist up.

“Damn, don’t they feed kids here anymore?” he asked with a smirk.

“It might help if he ate something besides ramen,” Kurenai observed coolly. Naruto knew she was probably still irritated at this Jiraiya person, but now she was taking it out on him. Naruto’s irritation spiked even higher when Jiraiya reached out and squeezed his bicep.

“Wiry, but he’s still got some good muscle tone,” the old man said speculatively.

“In addition to his normal missions and team training, he’s been working with a taijutsu specialist,” Kurenai observed. “Very few shinobi train as hard as he does.” Naruto willed his cheeks not to redden. It still felt good to hear his sensei acknowledge all his hard work.

“That’s good,” Jiraiya replied with a nod. “But taijutsu is only part of being a shinobi.”

“Taijutsu was an area that had been especially neglected by his instructors at the Academy,” Kurenai shot back. “Improving that also improves the performance of his clones, which he is highly skilled with. I’ve also introduced them to basic jutsu of different types. However, given his situation, Naruto has experienced some unique challenges with respect to ninjutsu.”

Naruto frowned. “Neh, sensei, I haven’t blown up a tree in ages!” It wouldn’t hurt to remind them that he was right here after all.

“Nonetheless, you almost did yourself serious injury with a very basic technique,” Kurenai replied.

“Oh, I’ve got to hear this,” Jiraiya said with a grin.

Naruto scowled as Kurenai explained his little mishap with the raiton jutsu. While she didn’t go out of her way to make him sound stupid, the smiles and chuckles from Jiraiya and the Hokage were getting on his nerves.

But the old creep looked thoughtful when she explained how Naruto had to consciously withhold chakra to keep from overloading his jutsu. “Things may be farther along than I anticipated. Okay, brat, I want you to mold some chakra. Don’t do anything with it, just mold it.”

Naruto did as he was told, but he almost lost his focus when Jiraiya leaned forward to stare at his stomach. Naruto looked down and saw an elaborate eight-lobed seal had become visible around his navel.

“Keep it steady,” Jiraiya ordered as his eyes narrowed.

After a while, the old pervert straightened up and told Naruto he could relax. “It looks like everything is intact. None of the elements appear to be breaking down, but it’s advanced a little farther than I expected.”

“Advanced?” Kurenai asked quickly.

“The seal was designed to let the Kyuubi’s chakra leak out and slowly mix with Naruto’s,” Jiraiya explained. “Done gradually enough, this would allow his body to adjust and absorb the chakra into his own reserves. As he grew, the constant pressure enlarged his coils, even as they were reinforced to handle the extra load. Now from what I can see, these passages were designed to slowly expand as Naruto aged, to increase the rate at which he can access this chakra. Otherwise, the Kyuubi could have flooded him too quickly when he was younger, and either damaged his coils or tried to influence him.”

Naruto swallowed.

“The passages are dilated more than I expected to see at his age. On the other hand, from what I can see his coils are also better developed, so it’s still under control. You’d need to get a Hyuuga or someone to seriously check out his coils, but I think the seal is adapting to Naruto’s own development,” the old man said with a grin. “That has to be my student’s finest work,” he added, the pride in his voice unmistakable.

“You taught the Fourth?” Naruto demanded. The Fourth Hokage, savior of Konoha, was taught by a pervert?

“I’ll have Hinata do an evaluation when she’s released from the hospital,” Kurenai said, her expression unreadable.

“She’s a Hyuuga?” Jiraiya asked. Then he winked at Naruto. “Not bad, kid.”

“She’s not my girlfriend,” Naruto said quickly, remembering Jiraiya’s earlier remark. “She’s my teammate.”

The Hokage cleared his throat. “Well, it’s good to hear that we don’t have anything to worry about,” he said. “And it looks like Naruto will continue to grow stronger if he keeps this up. Though he may always have some issues with respect to having too much chakra.”

Naruto shrugged, but an idea had taken root in the back of his mind. Time for some payback. “I think I already know all the jutsu I need. Taijutsu is much more useful anyway.”

That earned him a sharp look from Kurenai, but the old hermit simply exploded. “Is that what you think, you little brat? I can show you things that will make your hair stand on end, permanently!”

“I think that’s an excellent idea,” the Hokage said quickly. “Given his reserves, Naruto could use some assistance learning more advanced jutsu than is normally taught to genin.”

Jiraiya’s eyes bulged in their sockets. “Hey! He already has a sensei!” he objected.

“Kurenai is a genjutsu specialist, an area in which I understand that Naruto’s attributes mean he is especially challenged.” The Hokage replied, lighting his pipe again.

“It requires a certain delicacy to the chakra manipulations, and his control is still not up to that level,” Kurenai explained with an apologetic look toward Naruto. “He is, however, amazingly talented as dispelling genjutsu.”

“Not to mention that Kurenai also has a third genin that Naruto could possibly fight in the finals,” the Hokage added. “It would be somewhat awkward, if she were to spend significantly more time with one student than the other.”

Naruto could smell a con job a mile away. “Don’t worry about it,” he said dismissively. “I’d rather spend more time with Gai-sensei if he’ll let me. He’s a really good teacher and I know I’ll learn more useful things than I could with this pervert.”

Jiraiya rounded on Naruto, his face the picture of outrage. “Is that so?” he demanded. “Put your clothes back on and follow me.”

After Naruto followed Jiraiya out of the office, Kurenai turned to the Hokage. “That was very neat,” she observed.

The old man chuckled. “Sannin or not, I’ve known him since he was a boy. Naruto did most of the work though. You’ve really done wonders with him.”

Kurenai allowed herself a slight smile. “I can’t take too much credit. He’s always been exceedingly clever.” But then she thought of Hinata and the smile bled off of her face. “I think he’s going to need it though.”

“Is there something you’d like to report?” the Hokage asked in a delicate tone.

“Officially?” Kurenai replied. “No. Unofficially, I think Naruto has had some things confirmed that I’ve been suspecting. It will be… challenging for him to deal with this knowledge, since the wrongdoer is far too politically connected to answer for his crimes. But that’s just the way things are, isn’t it? Better he learn that sooner than later.” Her bitterness was unmistakable.

She felt a flash of guilt when the Hokage winced. “I can still open an inquiry,” he offered, “but-”

“But with no new evidence, the outcome will be useless,” Kurenai admitted. “Worse, some will see this as politically motivated and use that against you.”

“And if they discover that you were the instigator of the investigation…” the Hokage added, letting his voice trail off.

Kurenai frowned. “Yes, that would be enough justification to demand she be transferred to another jonin. I think he’d do that just to spite both of us.”

“If you can think of another way to address this, please let me know,” Sarutobi added before taking a thoughtful puff on his pipe.

“I don’t think there is,” Kurenai said in a pained voice. “And that’s the lesson Naruto has to learn from all of this. But I don’t think it’s one he will accept.”

By the time they quit later that evening, Naruto had to admit the old pervert knew his jutsu. He proved this by ordering Naruto to show him a technique he knew, and then had him stand back.

After Naruto demonstrated Doton: Wana, causing a training log to sink a couple of feet into the ground, the toad hermit made a series of seals and exclaimed “Doton: Yomi Numa!” Instantly, the ground fell away in front of the toad hermit, the hole filling with water. The so-called “Swamp of the Underworld” engulfed half the training ground, undermining trees, submerging equipment, and generally creating havoc.

Naruto found himself drooling. He’d never seen anything so… beautiful. He imagined using that on an unwary pursuit team chasing his friends and shivered.

“What were the seals for that one again?” he asked in a reverent tone.

In the end, they worked out a compromised schedule. Naruto continued working with Gai and Lee in the morning, had lunch with Hinata-chan at the hospital while she was still being treated, and then spent the afternoons and early evenings with the toad hermit.

Jiraiya preferred that division, since he said he ‘wasn’t a morning person’. Since Naruto always saw him heading off toward Konoha’s red lantern district after their training sessions, he had a pretty good idea of why.

Naruto was a little hesitant to tell Gai-sensei that he wouldn’t be working with them in the afternoons anymore, but the minute Jiraiya’s name left his mouth, Gai was most enthusiastic about the change. Naruto could only assume Gai knew the toad hermit, or at least of his reputation, which made Naruto begin to wonder about the old man. Maybe he wasn’t as flaky as he acted, sort of like Gai-sensei at the hospital.

In any event, he made the most of this more limited training time, fighting Rock Lee head on, rather than trying to always outlast him. It was mostly pretty painful, but he did cherish the few times he managed to knock his friend on his butt.

A couple of days into this new routine, Kurenai invited him and Shino over for dinner at her house. Naruto arrived at the small homestead, somewhat curious as to her purpose. He hoped it wasn’t to talk about Hinata – the things she’d told him were said in confidence, and it wouldn’t feel right to repeat them, even to Shino and Kurenai.

Shino was just walking up to the front door when Naruto arrived. Superficially, the Aburame genin looked the same as always. However, Gai had been coaching him and Lee on how to evaluate an opponent’s body language. Shino’s stride seemed tighter, more controlled, and his center of gravity never deviated as he walked. Naruto didn’t doubt that Shino’s mother had really been working on his weapon skills.

Shino acknowledged Naruto’s wave with a barely perceptible nod before Naruto knocked on the door.

Their sensei opened the door and showed them into her home. Naruto muttered the traditional pleasantries that Hinata had drilled him on as they walked to the Aburame household, but Kurenai merely waved them off. He looked around curiously. The house was… comfortable… he supposed was the best word to describe it. The furniture was simple, but well-maintained, and everything was arranged in an orderly fashion. There were a few pictures on the walls, mostly of an older couple he guessed were her parents. The only picture of his sensei was a group shot that he guessed was her old team, along with a burly man who had to be Kobaru-sensei.

Kurenai showed him and Shino into the dining room and gestured for them to sit down. Naruto was surprised to see the table piled with papers and scrolls. A few cardboard containers were piled haphazardly on a side table, but they did smell good.

“I picked up some take-out dinners from Moritake’s,” Kurenai explained as she passed them each a box and sat down. “I figured we could eat while I go over my findings.”

Naruto carefully set aside his dinner and curiously opened the top folder on the pile in front of him. Inside was a stack of papers, topped with a picture of Hyuuga Neji.

“…and that pretty much sums up all the competitors in the Chuunin Examination finals, with two exceptions,” Kurenai said as she concluded her presentation.

“Naruto and myself,” Shino replied.

“Yes,” Kurenai agreed. She was pleasantly surprised at how attentive her audience was. There was something to be said for mortal peril with respect to sharpening one’s focus. “I assume the two of you know each other fairly well, so that would be wasted effort. Furthermore, these reports contain a fair amount of speculation and guesswork on my part, based on the available data.”

“And you do not wish to inadvertently compromise anything either of us has told you in confidence,” Shino added. Naruto nodded. No doubt his recent conversations with Hinata had made him especially sensitive to such concerns.

“That is correct,” Kurenai confirmed.

Naruto shrugged. “I won’t do anything to kill your bugs, Shino.”

“It would be inappropriate for me to expect you to hold back, Naruto,” Shino replied, straightening his dark glasses.

Naruto grinned. “You told me they can’t really drain my chakra too well. They keep getting full and falling off.”

“I can utilize them to consume flesh as well as chakra,” Shino informed him. “The former, however is not usually necessary, and the utilization of anthropophagous techniques against nominal allies is contraindicated for a rank progression match.”

Naruto made a face. “Are you trying to get the tent to yourself, next time we go camping?”

Kurenai cleared her throat very loudly. “I want both of you to do you best,” she told them, “but I also do not want to see either of you inflicting permanent injuries on each other. Is that understood?”

Naruto nodded. “I’m saving all that for Neji,” he declared with a wide grin.

Shino adjusted his glasses again. The repeated gesture betrayed his agitation to anyone who knew him well. Kurenai wondered if she should ask him how he felt about the match-ups for the final. He wasn’t visibly distressed that Naruto would get to fight Neji first, but sometimes she wondered. After a moment, Shino spoke again, “If I am over-matched in one of my fights, I will endeavor to drain as much of their chakra before I am defeated. This should help you if you face them afterward.”

Naruto scratched his head. “Thanks,” he said after a moment. “If I, er, get into the same situation, I’ll try to hit their legs if I can and slow them down for your bugs to catch.”

Kurenai sighed. “I suppose no one can blame you two for that,” she said. Then she began gathering up the notes she’d gone through. “Both of you take your copies home with you. I’d be very careful about letting anyone else see them, but you should make a point of memorizing all the pertinent details.”

Shino had already organized his reports neatly into the file, but Naruto had let his papers spread out. He hurriedly began shuffling the papers back together. “Ah, sensei,” he said after a moment as he got them all together, “I almost forgot I needed to ask you something.”

“What is it Naruto?” Kurenai asked as she stood up and stretched. After little rest the last few nights, she would have no trouble sleeping tonight.

“The old pervert was showing me some new moves, and something called summoning technique,” Naruto explained. “He said I could learn it, but first I had to sign a special contract.” He shrugged. “You said I should be careful about signing any sort of contract and to talk to you before I did.”

Kurenai nodded, even as she sighed. Technically, it would be advantageous for him not to bring this up in front of Shino, but he apparently wasn’t capable of regarding his teammates as potential enemies. “I’ve heard of summoning contracts before,” she admitted. “I understand they can be useful, but are very chakra-intensive. That’s why they aren’t really covered at the Academy. Normally only a jonin can use one effectively. Also, this is something you might want to think over. Normally, I understand that these contracts usually contain an exclusivity clause that would prevent you from signing a contract with a different type of animal in the future.”

Naruto frowned and looked thoughtful.

“I presume that Jiraiya has the contract for toads?” Kurenai asked.

Naruto nodded, and they both jumped as Shino dropped his folder on the floor. Shino quickly bent over and began gathering his papers, shoving them haphazardly into the folder. When he straightened up, Kurenai thought she noticed a slight tremor in his hands. “Are you all right?” she asked.

Shino nodded. Then he turned to Naruto. “That would be a very formidable technique. That being the case, I will no doubt be forced to forfeit the match if we meet in the finals.”

“Forfeit?” Naruto asked, clearly dismayed. “But why?”

“Toads are incredibly voracious insectivores,” Shino explained, “capable of consuming a significant portion of their own body mass in a single night. If I attempted to use my kikai jutsu around them, I would stand to lose significant portions of my colonies in short order. Even if I were to defeat you, I would be effectively crippled in the process.”

“Oh,” Naruto said.

“However, you should not let that be your sole decision criterion,” Shino concluded. “As this should remain between you and Kurenai-sensei, I will bid you both good evening.”

With that, Shino left, and Kurenai wondered if it was her imagination or he was walking a little faster than usual. She shook her head and turned back to Naruto. “If you’d like some more information, I’ll see what I can find at the library.”

Naruto shook his head. “No way am I signing that now,” he declared.

Kurenai merely raised an eyebrow and awaited his explanation.

“The old pervert was showing off when he demonstrated the technique,” Naruto began. “Some of those toads are really big. I wouldn’t dare try using them when we’re on a mission – one of them might eat Shino, just to get all his bugs.”

Kurenai blinked. “I see,” she said. That was definitely a novel reason not to learn a new jutsu. She only hoped Naruto didn’t later regret his thoughtfulness.

The day of the Chuunin Examination Final Matches dawned bright and sunny. Naruto stood in a line with the other competitors as the Hokage made a speech from the kage’s elevated platform welcoming all the spectators.

Things had gone well the last couple of weeks. Though disappointed about the contract, Jiraiya had still shown him some cool jutsu. Gai and Lee had his taijutsu at a level he’d barely imagined being capable of.

Best of all, Hinata wasn’t in the damn hospital anymore.

After three weeks of convalescence, she was released with a long list of exercises she needed to perform. Though the rupture was healed, these exercises were vital to ensure the pulmonary tissues healed without excessive scarring or loss of elasticity.

More importantly, since the injury was sustained in the course of her normal duties, Kurenai-sensei directed Hinata to stay at her home until she’d fully recovered. This allowed the jonin to supervise Hinata’s rehabilitation and make sure she was fully recovered before returning to active duty. At least, that was the official explanation.

Naruto couldn’t deny the palpable relief he felt when Hinata told him about Kurenai’s offer, but the joy on his friend’s face ignited a spark of anger as well. It wasn’t right that she should feel this way, that she’d rather train forever and never see her family again.

Almost against his will, he felt his eyes cutting over toward Neji, standing beside him. The Hyuuga prodigy’s face seemed almost inhumanly composed. Naruto knew he’d have to do something about that.

After the Hokage was finished, Hayate walked out in front of them, looking as sickly as ever. He coughed once before speaking. “All right, as most of you know, the rule for these matches is that there aren’t really any rules. You fight until you are dead, knocked out, or surrender.” Another cough. “But if I decide the match is over, it’s over. Understood?” Naruto wondered if it was his imagination or Hayate’s glare seemed to fix itself on Neji and Gaara more than the rest of them.

“Okay, the first match is Uzumaki Naruto and Hyuuga Neji,” Hayate continued. “I want the rest of you to go back to the waiting area until your matches are called.”

The other six genin slowly filed off the field. Most of them were expressionless, but Shino and Naruto managed to share a quick nod before the Aburame boy left. The unspoken message was clear to Naruto. Kick Neji’s ass.

Umino Iruka made his way gingerly through the stands as the competitors were gathered on the field. He had no desire to trip and bump into some visiting dignitary. An international incident would not look good on his next performance review at the Konoha Ninja Academy.

Normally, he would sit with the academy instructors or the other chuunin and jonin attending the finals. This year found him sitting in more rarefied areas, wearing a fine kimono purchased with some of his recent winnings. Sartorial finery wasn’t really his thing, but it was necessary for him to fit in and get close to his targets.

It was odd to apply the things he taught to something that most definitely wasn’t a mission.

Almost reflexively his fingers brushed across the heavy purse belted to his waist. He didn’t normally carry this much money around and it made him a little nervous. Not only did it contain his winnings from the preliminary round, but Ichiraku Teuchi, Yuuhi Kurenai, and a couple of others had added their money to his. He’d even approached Maito Gai at the end of one of his training sessions. He made sure Naruto wasn’t around before mentioning the betting, as he didn’t want to put any more pressure on the boy, but he felt he owed Gai an opportunity to profit as well. Gai frowned, thinking for well over a minute, before he regretfully declined. While he appreciated the offer, it didn’t feel right to be betting against one of his own students, no matter what had happened before. Iruka didn’t press the issue, understanding the man’s awkwardness. But that didn’t stop Rock Lee from catching up with Iruka later that day and pressing on him a squirrel-shaped wallet stuffed with ryou.

Listening carefully, Iruka’s sharp ears located the amused murmurs, the dismissive whispers that guided him to his targets. He glanced around as he took a seat, apparently chosen at random. The rich finery and ostentatiously displayed wealth indicated some were no doubt members of the village council. There were a few lined faces with white eyes that he assumed were Hyuuga elders. The two youngest-looking Hyuugas there were Hiashi and his daughter, Hanabi. The latter seemed to look right through Iruka, not recognizing him out of his uniform.

Perfect.

Smoothing down his kimono with a fussy gesture, Iruka said, in a highly accented voice. “Well, this match looks interesting. Would anyone care to place a wager or two on the outcome?”

Naruto turned to face his opponent, who gazed back with a slightly superior expression. “You look like you want to say something,” Neji said in a cold voice.

Naruto leaned forward slightly and grinned. Kurenai-sensei told him once that his canine teeth were a little larger than normal, and displaying them to best effect could have an unsettling effect on others. “Only that I’ve been looking forward to this for a month,” he snarled.

Neji didn’t bat an eye. “Given our relative capacities, that is a foolish desire.”

“Foolish or not,” Naruto said, “I will defeat you.” He tensed a little as he saw Neji’s Byakugan activate.

“You may honestly believe you have a chance against me,” Neji said. “But I will also see your face when you realize the truth of your situation.”

“You’re not the first person to think that,” Naruto scoffed, “and I doubt you will be the last. Wherever he is, your father must be very disappointed.”

That last barb sailed right through Hyuuga Neji’s icy composure. The veins around his eyes bulged so far Naruto wondered if they might pop. “For that, I will kill you,” Neji snapped.

Naruto shrugged. “Hey, at least you have some memories of yours. And I don’t take my grief out on someone who shares it. Fool.” The last word was pure Shino speaking, but Naruto couldn’t quite get the same contemptuous tone his teammate could.

“Are you two here to fight or talk?” Hayate interrupted, sounding annoyed.

“My apologies, Hayate-san,” Naruto said lightly. “I just wanted Neji-kun to understand exactly why I’m going to beat him like a drum.” With that, he formed the familiar ram seal and cried out “Kage Bunshin no Jutsu!”

A dozen clones surrounded Neji and immediately began to charge at the Hyuuga. He spun and dodged, avoiding all the attacks and exploding clones left and right.

“His Jyuuken is pretty good, isn’t it?” Naruto asked Hayate in a conversational tone.

Hayate just turned to stare at him.

Naruto frowned. Maybe he thought this was a distraction so he could cheat. Then Naruto remembered there were no rules anyway. He shrugged. “He’s not as graceful as Hinata-chan, but his strikes have more power behind them.” He sighed as the last of the clones was dispatched. “But Jyuuken isn’t everything, is it?”

With that, Naruto sprang away from Hayate, hurling a brace of kunai. Neji dodged them with unerring precision, moving his body just enough to make them miss.

Neji responded with his own volley of kunai. Naruto dodged all but one of them.

That one he caught and threw back with a mocking smile.

Neji moved in, closing the distance. “At least you recognize your limitations,” he said with a sneer. “Everyone is born with a certain degree of talent, and that does not change. Struggling against your fate is futile. You do not have the ability to defeat me, so you do well to keep your distance.”

“Is that what the Hyuuga genius thinks?” Naruto snarled as he charged.

Hinata let out a gasp as she saw Naruto abruptly switch tactics. Kurenai-sensei wasn’t sure she was up to watching the finals, but Hinata insisted she was fine. To prove the point, she even performed the prescribed daily breathing exercises three times yesterday to show she was fit. The idea of not watching Naruto fight was… was simply unacceptable.

However, watching the match was… surprisingly difficult for her. Of course, she wanted Naruto to win, but she also didn’t want to see Neji killed. So much had been taken from her cousin… it didn’t seem right that he lose everything else. But she couldn’t ask Naruto to hold back either. Not when she didn’t think Neji would hesitate to hurt her teammate.

In a way, it was a relief when Naruto insisted she explain about the Hyuuga clan. Not only did it give her a warm glow when he insisted there was nothing wrong with her, but it also allowed her to explain about Neji and his resentment of the main family. He’d lost his father to protect her father. Showing anger toward her father simply wasn’t safe, not with the seal on Neji’s forehead, waiting to be activated. So she was the logical target for his rage.

Kurenai, fortunately, hadn’t heard her outburst. Sensei’s attention was solely focused on the match, which shamed Hinata a little. She knew Kurenai was too disciplined to let random thoughts distract her from things. That was an example she should work harder to meet.

“You are just as foolish as I thought,” Neji said as he ducked under Naruto’s kick and countered with a palm-strike loaded with chakra. “Or are you anxious to meet your fate?”

Naruto executed a spinning block he perfected sparring with Hinata. His left palm slammed into Neji’s forearm, well behind the chakra spike, turning the strike aside. “There is no fate but what we make,” he replied with a tight grin. Continuing the motion, Naruto spun completely around and his right heel only missed Neji’s ribs because the Hyuuga genius leapt backward. “I learned that one sparring with Hinata,” Naruto informed him with a grin.

“You haven’t seen the true power of Jyuuken, sparring with that weakling,” Neji sneered.

Naruto’s fragile hold on his temper cracked with an audible snap.

“She’s not a weakling, motherfucker!” Naruto screamed and charged. His fist grazed Neji’s jaw right before a Jyuuken strike speared through his shoulder.

“Dammit,” Naruto growled as he somersaulted backwards. Ignoring the burning agony in his shoulder, he straightened his back at the right moment to launch himself backwards into the air.

Neji’s follow-up blow struck the uncaring ground, rather than Naruto’s spine.

Naruto was done playing with this idiot. He hit the weight-release catches and arched his back. As his rotation slowed, Naruto abruptly bent at the waist, snapping his arms and legs together and launching the weights like missiles. The momentum they imparted sent his much-lighter body flying backward like it had been shot from a cannon. He stuck to the wall using chakra and looked down at the arena floor.

Only one of the chakra-enhanced masses struck the target, much to Naruto’s disappointment. But that one was enough to send Neji rolling across the arena. The rest had cratered rather impressively into the ground, kicking up a cloud of dust that had Hayate coughing again.

Neji climbed to his feet, not looking as battered as Naruto might have hoped. Of course, if he wasn’t pretty damn good, he never would have beaten Hinata-chan. “More tricks?” the Hyuuga called out angrily. “Is that what you learned from my cousin?” he sneered. “Useless tricks like this?”

Naruto jumped down to the arena floor. “If it was useless, then how did you get knocked on your ass?” he asked. He bounced lightly on the balls of his feet. He hadn’t taken his weights off in a long time. It felt good. Really good. Time to up the ante. “Here’s some more tricks,” he called out as he threw a wide spread of kunai, each one with an explosive tag attached.

Neji’s eyes of course picked up the tags. Dodging multiple explosions would be damn near impossible. Instead, he raised his arms to shoulder level and began to spin. As he turned, chakra began to stream from his body, expanding outward even as it made him turn faster and faster.

Neither Hinata nor Kurenai knew for sure if Neji could perform the Hakkeshou Kaiten, or Heavenly Spin technique, an all-around defense against attacks. But if he didn’t know it already, there was a good chance Hiashi might have taught him in the month of preparation. If nothing else, it would make a strong impression on the rest of the village, Kurenai reasoned in her notes.

Looks like she was right, Naruto thought as he summoned a horde of clones. He sent them against Neji in fours and fives. They exploded as soon as they touched the sphere of spinning chakra that surrounded him, but the noise and puffs of smoke were definitely a distraction.

Naruto kneeled at the back of the crowd, gathering his chakra. “Doton: Yomi Numa!” he called out as he slapped his palm against the ground. He must have been a little over-excited, Naruto guessed, because the ground crumbled away even faster than he expected.

Most of the remaining clones charged forward as their footing disappeared. The pops as they exploded were almost deafening, but they served their purpose. Naruto watched with growing satisfaction as the Kaiten began to sink into the softening ground, slowly at first and then faster and faster as the Heavenly Spin sent mud flying in every direction and Hyuuga Neji’s technique screwed himself into the ground.

By the time Neji realized what was happening and stopped, he was already ten feet down. Worse, no longer supported by his chakra emissions, the walls of liquefied mud that surrounded him collapsed. He was abruptly engulfed.

Naruto couldn’t help but laugh, falling to one knee as he was overcome by the humor of what just happened. So he was caught completely off-guard when a Neji-shaped mass of mud erupted from the instant swamp and speared him between the eyes with a Jyuuken strike. The green-clad genin stiffened as his frontal lobes were shredded, destroying most of his higher brain functions.

Then he exploded into a cloud of vapor.

Neji spun around as a piece of debris disappeared, leaving Uzumaki Naruto standing in its place. Naruto’s fist dug into Neji’s stomach, blowing him backward off his feet. “Your eyes can see through genjutsu,” Naruto told him as he stalked toward the Hyuuga prodigy, who was now covered in mud, struggling to his knees, missing both his forehead protector and his silly-ass hat. Neji glared as he clutched his stomach. “But I showed you what you expected to see. What use are those fancy eyes if you won’t use them?” Naruto asked.

“I can see that you’ve come within range of my divination,” Neji snapped, surging to his feet with greater speed than he’d shown a moment ago. “Divination Field: Sixty-Four Strikes!”

Naruto had glimpsed Hinata do something like this once, but she couldn’t really explain it or even replicate it when they sparred. Now Naruto got a much better view of it than he wanted. The Hyuuga’s hands moved with blinding speed. “Two strikes!” and two sharp pains registered in Naruto’s mind. “Four strikes!” and Naruto now felt four, all on his torso. “Eight strikes!” and he realized that Neji was hitting his tenketsu points with unerring precision. “Sixteen strikes!” It looked like he was trying to close all of them. “Thirty-two strikes!” the muddy shinobi shouted as his hands stabbed Naruto like knives, inflicting immense pain even as they deadened everything they touched. “Sixty-four strikes!” and Naruto flew backwards from the storm of chakra strikes, landing in a heap on the ground.

Neji settled back into a ready stance, ignoring the slowly-drying mud that dripped from his arms. “I have closed all the tenketsu on your body,” he announced, “and thus your fate is sealed. This fight is over.”

Naruto grunted and got his knees under him.

“Mortifying, isn’t it?” Neji asked in a contemptuous tone. “You are on your knees before a power you cannot defeat, discovering just how truly powerless you really are. Your conviction that working hard will change things is only an illusion. Both for you and my cousin.”

Up in the stands, the sudden quiet that had fallen after the fight’s surprising conclusion made Neji’s words audible to Hinata. She was already dismayed by the mastery of advanced Jyuuken technique Neji had demonstrated, and his cruel words only made her feel worse. Now Naruto would know the bitter sting of defeat. Would it change him? Would he blame her?

Just thinking those thoughts made something twist, deep in her stomach. This… this wasn’t right.

She leaned forward, fingers digging into the flesh above her knees, willing Naruto to get up. To win.

“Is that what you think?” Naruto gasped out as he painfully climbed to his feet.

He was rewarded with the barest flicker of doubt within the white eyes of the Hyuuga genius. “Don’t you realize this is futile?” Neji asked. “You’re just going to get hurt worse if you continue.”

“Do you think I can just walk away from this after what you did?” Naruto demanded.

“After what I did?” Neji shot back. “Do you know what they did to me?” Neji’s normally restrained voice grew rough with uncontrolled emotion. He swiped the mud from his forehead. “This seal controls my fate, just as it did my father’s. He died in place of the clan leader to keep the peace with Kumo.”

“I know about that,” Naruto replied, narrowing his eyes. “Hinata’s father killed the man who kidnapped her, but is it her fault that happened? Maybe her father should have disabled him instead of killing him. Maybe it would have been better if we went to war with Kumo if they are going to do things like that. But the only thing Hinata has to do with your father or your seal is being born.”

Naruto straightened and took a deep breath. “But you refuse to see the truth of that. So I’m going to have to beat it into you.” He let out a harsh kiai as he surged his chakra.

Uzumaki Naruto was used to re-opening his tenketsu. Doing that was a normal consequence of sparring with Hinata. But he’d never had to open all of them at once. In doing this, he discovered two things.

One, it hurt like hell. Normally, he was used to a small twinge in his chakra coils from the back pressure. This felt more like someone rammed a utility pole through them.

The second was that pushing out that much chakra at once, when it was suddenly released by the points opening, was pretty noticeable. Hayate, who’d been edging closer, obviously wondering if he needed to stop the fight, was bowled over. Neji, who was standing a lot closer, went airborne.

Of course, the Hyuuga managed to control his descent, landing lightly on his feet. But when he turned to face Naruto, his expression was clearly shocked. “That’s impossible,” he whispered. Fortunately, Naruto could read lips.

“Just as impossible as fighting against fate,” Naruto said as he closed in again, “Just as impossible as fighting a Jyuuken user at close quarters.”

Iruka inhaled sharply as he watched Naruto do the impossible. No one could counter the effects of Jyuuken. Avoiding the attacks was the only possible defense. At least, up until now.

From the choked gasps and sputtering that erupted around him, he didn’t think he was alone in that opinion.

“Is it—?” one man asked behind him.

“No, it’s not. We’d be able to feel it,” a voice answered.

“That’s good,” a third one said.

“No it’s not,” the second voice replied. “That brat has still trumped our greatest weapon. We can’t let him live with that knowledge.”

Iruka’s head spun around so fast he was sure he’d pulled a muscle, but the voices had already cut off. Behind him, he saw a mix of council elders and older Hyuugas, some of whom were now glaring at him with a mixture of confusion and hostility.

“Neji has not been defeated,” Hyuuga Hiashi said, drawing their attention away from the disguised chuunin. Iruka quickly turned back to the match.

Naruto was now intensely grateful for every sparring session with Hinata. It took everything he’d learned, everything they’d practiced together to keep up with Hyuuga Neji.

But that was the point. He was keeping up.

The Hyuuga genius couldn’t seem to hit him squarely, only managing glancing blows every now and then. Of course, the chakra enhancing those blows made them hurt like hell. But Naruto just gritted his teeth and bore it, and slowly the pain would fade.

Then Neji made a sweet little hesitating juke that drew Naruto’s attention to the wrong side for a moment. In that instant, the feint turned into a full on Jyuuken strike aimed at Naruto’s heart.

Desperate, Naruto copied one of Hinata’s moves, and bent back sharply at the waist. The powerful jyuuken strike passed over his now horizontal torso, the chakra spike making the skin of his face tingle.

In that instant of surprise as Neji realized his strike had missed, Naruto’s hands shot up and clamped around Neji’s wrist. His feet left the ground and an instant later slammed squarely into Neji’s ribcage. As he heard the air rush out of the Hyuuga’s lungs in a startled exhalation, Naruto wrenched at the arm he held with all his strength.

There was a sickening pop as he wrenched Neji’s shoulder out of its socket.

Naruto let go almost immediately and rolled to his feet. Neji fell to his knees, his right arm twisted at an odd angle. With his good hand, he hurled a brace of shuriken at Naruto.

Naruto dodged all but one of the missiles, and used a kunai to deflect that one skyward.

Neji let out a groan as he pulled on his arm, and finally wrenched it back into the socket. The surge of pain almost made him pass out. He blinked and glared at Naruto, who suddenly poofed, only to be replaced by a shuriken.

He looked left and right, slowly mustering the chakra to reactivate his Byakugan. He’d already expended much more of his reserves than he expected to, but nothing about this fight had gone as he expected.

He was distracted by motion below him. Why was his shadow growing? His instincts screamed at him to move, so he threw himself to the side as something green slammed into the ground where he’d been kneeling.

When the debris settled, there was a small crater, with Uzumaki Naruto on one knee at the bottom of it. His right fist was touching the ground, in the exact center of the crater.

He looked up and met Neji’s eyes. For an instant, Naruto’s eyes flashed purple as he exploded forward.

Naruto didn’t let up for an instant as he pummeled Neji. His fist snapped the Hyuuga’s head back, but Naruto was already dropping to the ground to do a foot-sweep. Neji’s feet were knocked out from under him so hard he was horizontal in mid-air when a hammer-fist strike to his solar plexus slammed him to the ground and the air burst from his lungs.

Neji was gasping for breath as Naruto dragged him to his feet, a handful of Neji’s grimy tunic in his left hand. His head lolled loosely on its socket.

Out of the corner of his eye, he saw Hayate opening his mouth to stop the match. He drew back his right hand, the fingers curled into claws and red chakra surging around it like hungry flames. He ripped it across Neji’s face as Hayate shouted for him to stop.

Blood flew across the dirt as Neji slammed to the ground and didn’t move.

The match was over.

22

Endings and Beginnings

“Standing out in the rain, getting soaking wet, was the last thing you needed in your condition,” Tsunade said with a frustrated sigh.

“It was necessary,” her old sensei replied. “We cannot afford to show any weakness until your position is secure.”

She ground her teeth, but didn’t let her concentration falter as she laid a hand, glowing with green healing chakra, on the old man’s back. The jutsu was designed to boost his immune system, even as it reduced the inflammation in his lungs. He still wasn’t fully recovered from the hypothermia and loss of his arm, and after the memorial service, he’d come down with a cough. It was mild enough at the moment, but she wasn’t about to take any chances. Her sensei was an old man, and he’d abused his body one too many times after coming out of retirement. From an objective point of view, retiring was the only logical course of action, and as a physician she applauded his good sense.

If only it hadn’t meant saddling her with his job. Damn, she needed a drink.

After a minute, she released her jutsu and stepped back. The old man straightened and took a deep breath. He smiled. “You haven’t lost any of your skills,” he said.

“Flattery might get you somewhere with Shizune, but not me,” Tsunade replied. “I artificially boosted your immune system, but it’s only temporary. If you don’t take care of yourself, you’ll be a lot sicker when it wears off. That means no strenuous activities, lots of clear fluids, and a minimum of twelve hours of sleep every night.”

“I don’t think I’ve ever had that much sleep in a night since I was a chuunin.”

“Get used to it, old man,” she snapped. “You aren’t a teenager anymore, and your body needs time and rest to recover.”

“I suppose that means we need to move up your assumption of the office then,” he said quietly.

Tsunade didn’t like it, but she nodded anyway. As much as she didn’t really want the responsibility, it didn’t change the facts of her prognosis.

Naruto stood, hands clenched into shaking fists, staring at the gate.

“Go ahead and open it,” Ero-sennin grumbled behind him.

After a moment, he bowed to the inevitable and opened the gate. A gravel path led to Sensei’s… what used to be Sensei’s house. He still felt a little numb as he walked, his sandals making almost no noise. The gravel was tightly packed, and endless hours of practice made it a habit to move without disturbing the ground more than necessary.

Yet another thing she’d taught him. Something else he’d never have a chance to thank her for.

Naruto took in a deep breath through his nose, and held it for a moment before letting it slowly puff out his cheeks as he exhaled. This was a lot harder than he imagined, and he didn’t think for an instant it would be easy. The Hokage acted as the official executor for the wills of any Konoha shinobi that did not specifically assign one. He was a little surprised when Jiraiya showed up at his apartment with a sealed scroll, but he knew Oji-sama was still recovering – not to mention buried in paperwork.

Then the old pervert really knocked things askew when he bluntly told Naruto he’d asked for the chore. “I’m going to make sure you don’t do anything stupid while you are still getting your act together,” he’d said. Naruto bristled a bit at that, but went silent when he learned that Sensei had left him her house. Her home.

His first impulse was to say he didn’t want it. He wanted no profit from her death. But before he even opened his mouth, he knew that was one of those stupid things Ero-sennin was talking about. Just his luck he’d have gotten someone assigned to the will who wanted revenge on the fox, and would have found some way to cheat him. So he’d held his tongue, and gave the white-haired old perv as respectful a nod as he could manage.

The keys were loud in the lock as Jiraiya opened the front door. The air inside was so still. Naruto knew it was his imagination. The house hadn’t stood empty that long at all. But, nonetheless, he felt like an intruder here. His stomach grew leaden as Jiraiya spread the papers on the table in the kitchen.

Showing an unexpectedly sensitive side, he turned away to fuss with the tea… and let Naruto read Kurenai’s words with no audience.

If you are reading this, then something has happened to me. Hopefully, whatever happened to me did not harm your teammates… but if that is the case, then you may alter my last instructions to you accordingly. Your teammates will do the same with the packets that are to be delivered into their hands.

Her words were surprisingly formal. But that actually helped. It was like a mission briefing. No emotion, just information. And the mission. He felt his jaw set in a determined line. If she had one last mission for him, then Uzumaki Naruto would make damn sure it was a success.

I have no blood heirs, and am the last of my line. As such, I have free rein with respect to the disposal of my material assets. My home, the land, and all associated assets will pass into the possession of Uzumaki Naruto, upon the condition that this home always remain a safe haven for his squadmates, Hyuuga Hinata and Aburame Shino, and their heirs. When you became a team, I gave you a charge, perhaps unfairly, to look out for your teammates. That is because I recognized your potential, your strength… the Will of Fire that the Hokage speaks so highly of. I can only say in my defense that I was proven correct to believe in you, Naruto. My last request is that you continue to do so. I will leave you most of my material assets to make this possible.

I freely admit that in writing this document, I have laid a very heavy burden on someone who is just getting ready to test for Chuunin. However, I am also making similar requests of the others. Together, the three of you have become a remarkable team, one I am humbled to have had a part in creating. Stay true to each other, and I will rest content, knowing that the legacy I leave to Konoha will be greater than I could ever have imagined.

Naruto swallowed the lump that had formed in his throat. She was… proud… of him, and his team. So proud. Her legacy… to Konoha? That’s how she saw Team Eight?

Naruto stared through a window into the approaching twilight as the smell of brewing tea filled the kitchen.

Naruto slowly moved into his new home. He wasn’t reluctant to leave the apartment – he just didn’t know what to do with Sensei’s things. Fortunately, Hinata volunteered to help him pack her things away without even being asked. Whether it was her own thoughtfulness, or Sensei thinking ahead one last time, it didn’t matter – he was grateful.

Shino helped with the garden out back. Naruto enjoyed gardening himself – Mr. Ukko was thriving far better on the back porch than he ever had in his pot at the apartment. But Shino was an Aburame – and they cheated. As his colonies swept the yard for inimical insects, Shino mentioned that most of Konoha’s farmers paid a small retainer to his clan to keep their harvests pest-free. As he watched his friend’s kikai bugs march off to battle, Naruto could believe it.

Eventually, though, his teammates returned to their homes, and Jiraiya went to do whatever it was he did at night. The quiet inside his former sensei’s home was palpable, leaving Naruto to fidget nervously. He couldn’t help feeling like an intruder – or worse, a thief. He repeated Kurenai-sensei’s words in his mind, trying to focus on the last mission she’d laid upon him. Finally, he sat at the hearth in the kitchen, heating water for tea. He wasn’t really thirsty – it was more in the way of needing something to do.

As he shifted to put the kettle over the fire, Naruto felt one of the hearth stones shift slightly under his weight. Frowning, he stood up, wondering if the mortar needed to be patched. Pulling at the stone, he was surprised when it shifted slightly to the side and abruptly came entirely loose from the hearth.

Frowning, Naruto laid the stone to one side and inspected the hollow beneath it. Inside was a tightly wound scroll. He swallowed as he unrolled the first few inches and saw it was addressed to him.

Naruto,

Please try to read this when you are alone. The information on this scroll is potentially dangerous, especially if certain parties were aware you knew it. If you are reading this, I am more than likely dead. If that is not the case, please return this scroll to its hiding place and ask me about it the next time we are alone.

If I am no longer available, then I will gift you with all that I know, and let you make what use of it that you will. As you will soon discover, this is not a pleasant gift. The truth never is, which is why so many would hide it given the chance.

We’ve spoken before of looking “underneath the underneath”. There are times that is very, very hard to do – especially if it means confronting uncomfortable truths about one’s home. By the time you finish reading this, you may wish to burn this scroll and forget it ever existed. I would not blame you. But I would not rest easy in the afterlife if I died without making provisions for you to have everything you might possibly need to keep yourself and your teammates safe.

Most of this deals with a cautionary tale from my own past, and a great deal of guesswork as to how things happened the way they did. If I had concrete proof of everything I suspect, I would have gone to the Hokage with it long ago. Unfortunately, some charges cannot be made without iron-clad evidence. Do not blame Hokage-sama for this – it is for the good of the village.

The focus of this sorry tale is my genin squad under Kobaru-sensei. My teammates were Inuzuka Nomaru and Fukuda Mattai. Nomaru was a member of the Inuzuka clan, and embodied their best… and worst traits. He was brave, loyal, brash, and a little conceited. Still, he was a good friend, and I’d like to think that, if he’d had a chance to mature a little more, he would have been a credit to his clan.

Mattai was raised in a farming village outside Konoha, but while bringing their harvest to Konoha, his family was killed in a bandit attack. A chuunin patrol chasing down the bandits arrived in time to save Mattai and brought the orphaned boy back with them. He applied to join the Ninja Academy and was accepted after they discovered he had the potential to channel chakra. He was a couple of years older than I and the rest of his classmates, but he was very focused and quickly caught up to the rest of us in his studies.

He was a little unusual looking. His eyes were almost as pale as a Hyuuga’s, but his deeply tanned complexion and messy black hair betrayed his “peasant” origins. A few children raised in various clans sneered a little at the ‘country bumpkin’, but Mattai ignored them. If anything, the taunts made him work even harder.

I’m proud to say that Nomaru and I never had any part of that.

As he trained, Mattai displayed a true talent for Taijutsu, and was one of the best in our class by the graduation exams. In time, the three of us were assigned to Kobaru-sensei and began taking D-ranked missions. Mattai’s work ethic and unrelenting good cheer made the insufferable tasks all the more bearable. In time, I came to consider him my best friend, with Nomaru a close second.

In time, we eventually progressed to C-ranked missions and began performing reconnaissance missions outside the village. Our team, with an Inuzuka’s nose, my talent for Genjutsu, and Mattai’s ability to move stealthily and disable enemies quietly with Taijutsu, were eventually groomed as a scouting team. As we grew older, Nomaru began dating a village girl and I started wondering if my feelings toward Mattai might lead to more than just friendship.

It was a couple of years after you were born that we first ran into serious trouble. The attack of the Kyuubi left Konoha’s ranks depleted for years, and Iwakagure began pressing our borders, confident now that the Yellow Flash was no longer around. We were patrolling the border, not unlike the first mission of Team Eight – only with Iwakagure clearly spoiling for a fight.

Our team ran into a heavy ambush. The opponents were either extremely competent bandits bribed by the Iwa ninjas, or simply Iwa shinobi out of their uniforms. It was clearly an attempt to make us ‘disappear’ while on our mission, and perhaps torture some information out of us regarding Konoha’s forces in the region.

We were trying to fight free, but it was heavy going. Nomaru was wounded early in the struggle, and Kobaru-sensei was half-carrying him as we tried to disengage. The enemy was using a lot of smoke grenades, which suggested they were really Iwakagure shinobi – most Iwa ninjas mastered the ability to locate their enemies from the vibrations of footsteps in the earth.

We were surrounded by billowing smoke, with enemies leaping out of the murk, trying to kill us, then leaping back. Some nights, I still dream about that fight. As we were about to break into the clear, I saw the smoke part and a bandit with a spear leaped out to spit Mattai like a game bird. I was glancing back at him as this happened, and I suppose something in my expression gave it away. The instant before the blow landed, Mattai’s eyes turned fully white and the veins all around them began to bulge outward. He twisted forward at the waist to evade the spear-point, even as his right hand reached behind him and grabbed the spear shaft just past the blade. He yanked the spear forward as he spun and slammed his left fist directly into the surprised bandit’s jaw, dropping him to the ground. We eventually made it back to Konoha, though Mattai suffered from headaches most of the way.

Needless to say, after our report, there was a lot of interest in a genin that suddenly manifested a working Byakugan. The Hyuuga clan demanded an investigation of how their bloodline had been spread outside the clan. Some of this was understandable, as there had recently been an attempt to kidnap the clan head’s daughter. However, Mattai had no idea where it had come from, and his parents had both been killed while traveling to Konoha. After several ‘interviews’ with the Hokage’s office, Mattai was cleared of any wrongdoing.

At this point, the Hyuugas ‘graciously’ offered Mattai a position within the branch family.

However, Hiashi had not made a very favorable impression on Mattai when he first demanded to know how ‘some peasant’ had acquired their precious Byakugan. Also, it was whispered throughout the village that the clan leader’s own twin brother, and member of the branch family, had been sacrificed the previous year to placate Kumo’s demands for the life of Hiashi. Either fact was enough to make Mattai politely decline the ‘honor’ he had been offered. I myself was pleased with his decision – for reasons I wasn’t quite ready to admit to myself.

Later, Kobaru-sensei told us that a motion had been filed within the council to either forcibly remove Mattai from active duty, or require him to receive the Branch Family seal - “for the good of Konoha”. The measure was voted down by the rivals of the Hyuuga’s, including the Uchiha and other clans. The Hokage himself would not support the motion, citing that Mattai was not a Hyuuga, and in no way answered to the clan. Forcing a non-clan shinobi to join a clan or submit to their will was not a precedent he wanted to set.

So after a couple of months of recovery and doing D-missions while the politics played out, we were finally cleared to leave Konoha again. Tensions with Iwa had eased after a series of escalating skirmishes depleted their border guards without any measurable gain. Therefore, a simple courier job was an ideal mission to test Nomaru’s recovery and allow us to work the rust from our skills.

We never saw the ambush coming - one moment we were traveling along a mountain path, the next moment it seemed like the entire world blew up in our faces. From the lack of warning, I think the path was mined with explosive tags.

The initial explosion left us scattered and wounded. I had fallen back slightly to adjust my sandal. That loose strap saved my life. Unfortunately, it also meant I had a clear view as half a dozen kunai trailing ninja wire wrapped around Kobaru-sensei. Half-stunned as he was, I don’t think he even saw the explosive tags attached to the wire before they detonated, tearing Sensei to pieces.

That same combined explosion hurled me backwards off the path, knocking me out. But as I flew backwards, I clearly saw Nomaru decapitated by a large sword, and Mattai…

Mattai had volunteered to take point that day, hoping to gauge the effectiveness of his altered eyes. The explosion hurled him forward, straight into the blades of a trio of swordsmen that erupted from the ground. All three blades ripping out through his back was the last thing I saw before the darkness took me.

I awoke hours later at the bottom of a ravine, filthy, bruised, and quite obviously concussed. The explosion seemed to have thrown me halfway down the mountain, and that mad tumble is probably the only reason I survived. It took me hours to find the path and make it back to the ambush site. It wasn’t until I saw for myself that I accepted that my teammates were all dead.

My memories of staggering back to Konoha were rather disjointed, owning to both my head injuries and my grief. At first, there was a lot of suspicion about what happened to my team. However, the majority of the suspicion was aimed at myself for being the sole survivor.

It was a long time before the Torture and Interrogation Unit cleared me of any wrongdoing. In the process, I came to know my principal interviewer well enough to share my suspicions regarding the attack.

Make no mistake, this was no ordinary ambush. Overwhelming force was used to intercept a courier packet of limited value. Furthermore, the precise nature of the ambush revealed a detailed knowledge of both our route and my team’s composition. Finally, more men were detailed to kill a single genin than his jonin-sensei. These circumstances suggested a foul betrayal at the highest levels of Konoha’s government. The courier mission was funded by the Village Council – an ordinary update typical of those sent to the Daimyo. The list of people with sufficient knowledge to have set us up was as short as it was disturbingly distinguished.

Privately, the man I confided in agreed with my assessment. However, he also concluded that I lacked sufficient proof to make any accusation stick. Worse, if I revealed my suspicions, it would likely only be a matter of time before I too suffered a tragic accident and was killed in action. So I held my tongue and kept my ears open, seeking the other pieces to the puzzle, hoping against hope to someday have justice for my slain comrades. Justice for a friend who might have become more some day.

But justice for the slain is not why I have told you of my suspicions, Naruto. My debts are not yours, and I would not see you spend your life addressing those wrongs – if that was all that this was about.

Ever since I returned to active duty, I kept my eyes and ears open for any hints of conspiracies or treacheries within the Leaf. Recently, those efforts have finally borne fruit. You are aware that we have noticed a pattern of villagers seeking to circumvent the Hokage’s law regarding your prisoner. What you may not be aware of is that some of this seems to stem from a faction within the Village Council that seeks to isolate you and place you at odds with the rest of Konoha. This is in direct opposition to the Hokage’s directives regarding how you are to be treated. At best this is an attempt to undermine his authority – at worst, it is blatant treason. If you were not the type of person I am honored to call a student, they would have turned you against Konoha long ago.

Of course, a group willing to commit one treachery likely has committed others – such as murdering a genin to spite the Hokage for ruling against their demands.

I recently shared my observations, scant as they are, with one other. Umino Iruka is an eminently sensible man, and clearly has your best interests at heart. He has been assisting my investigation, and will continue if something happens to me. Please confide in him if you learn anything that you think might help.

Aside from seeking justice for yourself, the other reason I wish to tell you of my past is as a cautionary tale. The forces that arranged Mattai’s death are quite formidable. Even with your incredible progress, it will be years before you can do much to confront or confound their schemes. Worse, you, and more importantly your teammates, are likely more vulnerable in some ways.

I suspect that the chief architect of Mattai’s death was the same man that was stymied in his attempts to force Mattai to join the Hyuuga Branch Family and be branded with the caged bird seal – Hyuuga Hiashi, Hinata’s father.

I do not know the man well, but nothing I have learned suggests he possesses any scruples that would have stopped him. His thirst for the Hyuuga to maintain a monopoly on their bloodline is boundless. On several occasions he has displayed a degree of ruthlessness that makes me think the worst of him.

At one point, Naruto, you asked me if there was something… wrong… with Hinata’s family. At the time, I was bound by promises of confidentiality, and furthermore had no desire to break Hinata’s trust. But with my death, I can do no more for her, and so I will answer your question. Yes, Hinata’s home-life is at best abusive. I will milk her convalescence for every day that I can keep her from returning to that poisonous environment. The way Hiashi treats his daughter is monstrous, and I would like nothing better than to see him rot in hell for that alone.

As best I can tell, her missions with Team Eight, and especially her training with you, are the sole bright spots in her existence. Please look out for her, Naruto. I know you are devoted to both your teammates, but Shino has a supportive family and a girl I would be proud to call daughter has nothing. If you are reading this, then I am dead, and can do nothing further to help her. It is not fair of me to do this, to lay this geas upon you, but desperation makes tyrants of us all. My only solace is that I can see how you care for her, even if you do not realize it yourself. You may not be able to recognize it because of how you have been treated all your life (and I damn the Council once again for that), but she is just as clearly devoted to you. She loves you, Naruto, like she loves no one else in this life. Treasure that, and treasure her. Please.

Protect her from her father. Protect yourself from all the forces arrayed against you. These are nigh unto impossible tasks. But you do have a few allies. The Hokage cannot show overt favoritism, but he has displayed a willingness to assist you when he can. I’ve already mentioned Iruka. Your oafish Godfather, while he has done things I disapprove of, does have his reasons. He will help you, within his own limitations. Finally, your teammates will give emotional support, even if they are unable to help in more tangible ways. I would give anything for five minutes with my lost friends. I only hope to see them again some day.

Again, I apologize for the burdens my death has forced me to shift onto your shoulders. I am comforted by the knowledge that the future Hokage of Konoha will have the strength to do what I was unable to manage. You convinced me of your destiny the first time we talked at Moritake’s, Naruto. But know that I am already proud to have had you as a student, and as a friend. I am sure that you will become one of the greatest Hokages.

-Kurenai

Tsunade’s inauguration as the Godaime Hokage was a relatively subdued affair. The village was still repairing damage from the aborted invasion, and the guest of honor didn’t exactly feel like celebrating the assumption of a job she didn’t really want. To Tsunade, becoming Hokage meant dealing with a series of headaches… such as the clan leader raising his voice in her office.

“I understand your concerns, Hiashi, but the bargain was struck before I ever agreed to return to Konoha,” she began in what she hoped was a placating tone. Obnoxious as he was, the fool wielded a lot of influence with the council and the Daimyo. “Furthermore, her duties will now facilitate plans I and my predecessor have devised to improve medic-nin training.”

“While my heir is needed to fulfill certain duties within the clan,” Hiashi began smoothly after making a visible effort to calm himself, “I doubt she would be of much use in such a… sensitive capacity. You would do far better to utilize someone with natural ability in that area.”

“I think you misunderstand me, Hiashi-sama,” Tsunade replied with a smile. The old fool had stepped right into her trap. “That’s precisely what I don’t want. I have been away from Konoha for many years, and I understand that the… quality… of the Academy graduates may have changed over the years. Hinata’s efforts to learn medical jutsu, no matter how fruitless, will give me a yardstick with which to calibrate the training times for the actual program. If I used someone who actually possessed any talent, it would skew all of the results. No, Hinata’s ‘all-around mediocrity’, as you have described it, is exactly what I need.”

“I… see,” Hiashi said after a long pause. It was clear that he really didn’t. It was also clear that he didn’t want to admit that fact. “And after she fails the program?” he asked.

“That won’t be allowed,” Tsunade answered in a firm tone. “I’ll work her into the ground if I have to, but I will get my full six months of service. If nothing else, it will teach her to bargain with greater care in the future.”

“I suppose it might,” Hiashi allowed in a slightly approving tone. “I have already expressed my displeasure with her actions, but I will leave it to you to demonstrate the true foolishness of her offer.”

“As you wish, Hiashi-sama,” Tsunade agreed. She didn’t quite simper – not even this fool was egotistical enough to fall for that.

No sooner had he left than the side door to Tsunade’s tower quarters opened and a scowling Shizune strode in. Anticipating many late nights working, Tsunade had asked her apprentice to unpack there, rather than airing out the Senju clan residence. She raised an eyebrow at her senior apprentice’s thunderous expression… right up until she saw Hinata shuffling in behind her, eyes downcast.

“Oh hell,” she groaned internally. Their voices must have carried through the door. From what Jiraiya had passed on, she was sure the girl’s hopes had been crushed.

Might as well brazen it out, she decided. “Now that the idiot is gone,” she began, “I can tell you my real expectations. I am going to work you hard, and you are going to be an incredible Medic-nin, understand me?”

Now the girl looked confused, but that was at least an improvement. And Shizune didn’t look at her like she’d crawled out from under a rock anymore. “I told your father what he wanted to hear in order to get him out of my office. Killing a clan leader in my first week as Hokage sets a bad precedent,” she announced breezily. “Your chakra control is almost as good as mine when I was your age, and you have at least twice the stamina I did. What the hell kind of training did Hiashi have you doing?”

“Ah,” Hinata began, looking like her head was spinning from having her expectations flipped around, “I, uh, believe most of that was from training with N-Naruto.”

“Really?” Tsunade asked, smirking, “and what kind of training is that?”

Hinata blushed suddenly, and Tsunade felt a twinge of guilt. This kid was really too easy to wind up. “Mostly Taijutsu sparring. S-some chakra control exercises too. We also w-work with Gai-sama and his student Rock Lee.”

Tsunade vaguely remembered hearing Maito Gai’s name some years ago. Something about a genin who passed his Jonin-sensei’s personal test by the simple expedient of wearing him out to the point of acute exhaustion. “Well, whatever you’re doing you should continue if you can.”

The shy Hyuuga’s expression immediately brightened at that. “You’ll spend the afternoons working with Shizune at first, and assisting her with her rounds at the hospital,” the Hokage continued. “At some point, provided you are progressing adequately, you will be assigned to other teams or to ad hoc groups for support. This will give you experience working with a variety of personalities and skill-sets.”

“What about Team Eight?” Hyuuga Hinata asked with a frown.

Tsunade sighed. “Officially, it was dissolved with the death of Yuuhi Kurenai. However, all three of you are performing at or near Chuunin level already, so it doesn’t make a lot of sense to re-assign you to genin teams that have lost a member. You would unbalance them, and they’d just have to replace you again when you were promoted.” She paused. “I’ll be working out individual solutions for your teammates, just as I have for you. Understood?”

“Hai, Hokage-sama.”

“I appreciate your and your wife’s flexibility on this issue, Shibi,” Tsunade said with a smile.

“Your request was only logical,” the Aburame replied in even tones. “Shino’s personal development is best served by specialized instruction, but his professional advancement is best served by working with a group. And what better group than individuals he is already accustomed to working with?”

“I agree, but with the scheduling issues he may not be able to complete missions with them as frequently as before. It might also be good to get him used to working with some of the other genin teams.”

“Your point is well taken, but financially, he is not as dependent as others upon his mission income.” A pause. “He has also invested a good portion of his earnings, with an eye toward long-term returns.”

“That’s… prudent,” Tsunade nodded, slightly taken aback. How much had those brats made on missions already? “But from what I understand, very typical for Shino.”

“We are pleased with his development as well,” Shibi agreed.

“Look Tsunade, I’ll get right to the point,” Jiraiya began. “I want Naruto as my apprentice.”

“Okay.”

“I know I haven’t been here for him growing up like I should have been,” the old lecher admitted with a grimace, “but I’d heard some ugly rumors that needed chasing down, and I thought the Old Man had things under control. Well, now I know better, and I can’t leave him alone.”

“Okay.”

“I’ve got a lot of things I can teach him, things he needs to learn,” Jiraiya continued, clearly not listening yet. “His father’s jutsu, for one thing. And maybe how to get a handle on the Fox’s chakra without hurting himself.”

“Okay,” Tsunade replied, her teeth starting to grind.

“I know you don’t think much of my sense of responsibility,” Jiraiya plowed on, “but he’s my Godson. And I made a promise to his Jonin-sensei as well. I-”

“DAMMIT JIRAIYA, I SAID YES! NOW SHUT UP BEFORE I KILL YOU!” Tsunade yelled.

The Toad Hermit was gone before the Chuunin guard even got the door open.

Naruto looked up from his instant ramen. “Could you repeat that again, please?” he asked in a subdued voice.

Jiraiya frowned as he leaned back from the kitchen table. “I said, the Hokage has assigned you as my apprentice.”

“Exactly what does that mean?”

Jiraiya’s frown deepened. Most genin would give their left arm to train under someone as awesome as the Toad Hermit. Why would his godson act like it’s a punishment detail? “It means, you will be getting one-on-one instruction with me. I have a lot to teach you, things I doubt you’ve even heard of. We’ll be doing some missions together, and I’ll show you what it takes to develop and maintain the biggest covert intelligence network in the elemental countries.”

“Missions?” Naruto asked, “but what about Team Eight?”

Jiraiya let out a sigh. “Naruto, Team Eight officially ceased to exist when… you know.”

Naruto scowled. Jiraiya noticed a muscle twitching along his jawline… just like Minato, on the rare occasion when his former student got really angry.

“That’s the official rule,” Jiraiya continued. “You can’t have a genin team without a jonin-sensei. Unofficially, you three are as much genin as I am a celibate monk. Anyone reading your files knows how well you three work together, so you’ll probably be called together for missions on a regular basis.”

Jiriaya took a sip of his tea as Naruto subsided a little. He hadn’t promised, not explicitly, but he wasn’t comfortable drinking what he really wanted to… not in front of the kid. She may have had a stick up her ass, but he didn’t want to dishonor what was effectively a last request. Too much bad karma, especially for someone in his line of work. “You know, if the exam hadn’t been interrupted, you and maybe Shino would have made Chuunin for sure – and your genin team would have been split up. That said, most Chuunin have mission profiles they are better at, and people they are used to working with. That’s why you tend to see the same shinobi working together from time to time, no matter what their rank is.”

Naruto looked thoughtful. “So… this kind of thing would have happened anyway. But we’ll still end up working together a lot. That’s why she asked me to promise…”

“Promise?” Jiraiya asked.

Naruto looked down at his steaming cup. “To look after my teammates.”

Jiraiya squelched a flash of irritation. Kurenai really had no business laying that kind of burden on a genin. He wondered if she’d done it for other reasons. Maybe to focus someone who was a hell-raiser in the Academy, according to his files. He’d never know. “She knew how the system works, Naruto. I’m sure she meant when you all were on missions together. Anyway, it looks like you’ve got everything here squared away, so we’re going on a training trip in two days. Pack for an extended mission with resupply en route.”

“Extended mission?” Naruto asked. “How long?”

“About six months,” Jiraiya said. “I need to introduce you to my contacts, so we’ll be moving around a lot at first. I also have some advanced jutsu for you to work on…”

“Six months?” Naruto exclaimed. “But… I can’t…”

“If this has anything to do with the Hyuuga girl,” Jiraiya continued, “You wouldn’t be seeing much of her anyway.”

“What do you mean?”

“Remember that six months of service she owes the Hokage?” Jiraiya asked. “She still owes it, and Tsunade’s going to get her money’s worth. Between making her learn medical jutsu and working at the hospital… well, she’s going to work her so hard that she’ll be sleeping on a cot in Shizune’s room at the tower.”

Naruto scowled at first, then his face cleared as he made the connection. Jiraiya couldn’t fault the kid’s reasoning ability, but his poker face needed a lot of work. “I see,” the blond said after a moment. “And Shino?”

“He’ll be working with his mother and father on their techniques, when he’s not doing missions. Tsunade said something about socializing him, so I think he may tag along with some of the other teams on missions to get him used to working with more than just you and the Hyuuga.”

“Two days from now?” Naruto asked. His expression indicated acceptance, if not agreement. That would have to do.

Jiraiya nodded.

Naruto sighed. “All right. That will give me time to say goodbye.”

Naruto wasn’t specifically looking for Iruka-sensei when he ran across him in the business district, but he had been going around and making his goodbyes to the few people that would actually miss him. Ikitaro the tailor even sold him some spare fabric he could use to patch his uniforms if he managed to damage the tough fabric in the field.

He was about to call out to his old Academy instructor when he noticed the slightly furtive air about the chuunin as he hurriedly made his way down the street, rifling through a stack of papers.

Naruto paused, wondering if this had something to do with what Kurenai had mentioned in her letter. He hoped not – especially if it was supposed to be secret. Fortunately, Iruka wasn’t dumb either.

He was, however, very distracted, and didn’t notice Naruto tailing him through the crowded streets of the district. The little lessons he’d picked up from Kurenai-sensei were second nature by now. Don’t make eye contact. Don’t maintain a constant distance. Do vary your course so it only roughly parallels the target. It was too bad he didn’t have anyone else to switch off with to better avoid detection. Fortunately, detection wasn’t an issue. Normally, Iruka-sensei was more on the ball than this, so Naruto knew he had to be pretty worked up over something.

This was a good thing, because Naruto completely broke his tradecraft when he saw Iruka duck into a store… that sold fancy ladies' underwear.

Naruto immediately checked himself for signs of a genjutsu – even pulsing his chakra for a bare instant at the lowest power he could manage. No resistance. Shaking his head in disbelief, Naruto ducked into an alleyway and henged into the form of an attractive younger woman, who then sauntered up to the shop and lingered near the doorway as she inspected the display models in the window.

He felt vaguely perverted staring at the lacy bits of fabric on display. None of it looked even remotely comfortable, and he didn’t even want to think of what Jiraiya would say if he could see him now. But for the most part, his attention was focused on his hearing, and the faint voices drifting from within.

An older female voice was winding up the end of a formal greeting to… Iruka-sama? What the hell?

“I, uh, received a flyer in the mail, regarding the… you-know,” Iruka began hesitantly.

“Oh yes, Iruka-sama, do not worry, we will have workmen here tomorrow to replace the sign.” Naruto glanced up at the sign over the door. Pandora’s Secret. “I have completed all of the other paperwork, including renewing the business licenses with the new name.” There was a rustle of paper. “I will have everything taken care of for our grand re-opening next week.”

“No! I mean, I think you misunderstood, Hotako-san, I meant that it was supposed to remain a secr-”

“I’ve already mailed flyers to all our regular customers,” the old lady continued, giving no sign of having heard Iruka at all. Maybe she was hard of hearing?

“Oh no,” Iruka gasped.

“Oh, it’s all right, Iruka-sama,” she consoled the chuunin, “none of those I’ve talked to seemed at all upset. This has been Pandora’s Secret for over twenty years now, it was time for a change. And the new name… it’s just a little hint of naughty, you know, it makes the older women smile and the younger women blush. You should make sure you are here for the grand re-opening sale, Iruka-sama. A nice young man like yourself, it’s a crime you don’t have a girlfriend or three… maybe that’s why when you lowered the rent you wanted the shop to become Iruka’s Secret?” she asked in a sly tone.

“No!” Iruka burst out, “I meant it was supposed to stay a secret… I… Oh, uh, nevermind, Hotako-san, I, uh, need to get to my appointment. I’ll see you later!”

“Oh, I need to get a picture! For the sign, you know…”

Naruto had to step quickly to the side to avoid being bowled over by the fleeing chuunin. Feeling merciful, Naruto followed the fleeing shinobi for half a block before calling out his name.

Iruka froze in place as Naruto dropped the henge. The chuunin had an embarrassed smile on his face as he turned around.

Naruto didn’t say anything. He just raised an eyebrow. The fact that Kurenai-sensei would do the same thing when she caught him doing something foolish gave him a pang, but thankfully the pain was starting to dull. He’d like to think she’d appreciate how he was handling this.

“This is all your fault, you know,” Iruka blurted out.

Naruto just looked at him silently.

Iruka sighed. “I probably should explain,” he finally said. “You want to go to Ichiraku’s?” he asked.

Naruto nodded happily.

“My treat,” Iruka added.

Naruto froze as a chill went down his spine. Something was wrong.

Of course, all things are relative, especially when you are wrapped around several warm servings of miso ramen.

“Wait,” Naruto interjected, “I knew you made a lot of money betting on the finals. Did you invest in an underwear store? And you called me a pervert for Sexy no Jutsu when I was your student!”

Iruka sputtered. “It wasn’t like that at all! We just… ah… well, nearly bankrupted several of the Hyuuga Elders.”

Naruto’s eyebrows went up. “They bet that much?” he asked.

“We got very, very good odds,” Iruka explained with some satisfaction. “And they definitely didn’t want it to get around that they couldn’t pay their debts. So some of the compensation came in the form of assets.”

“Assets?” Naruto asked.

“Liens, debts owed by third parties, and the deeds to various properties around Konoha,” Iruka explained.

“Ah, so that’s why you now own a panty store?” Naruto asked in a loud voice, making Iruka cringe visibly.

“Hush, Naruto,” the chuunin snapped, “or I won’t pay for your ramen.”

Naruto grinned. “Okay, okay,” he agreed in a quieter voice, “but if you are so embarrassed, why did you have that old lady change the name?”

“I didn’t,” Iruka protested, “I saw how she was getting overcharged a little on her rent, especially compared to the other shops on that block, so we renegotiated.”

“Ayame and I don’t have time to worry about other businesses,” Teuchi added as he refilled Iruka’s bowl. “Iruka-san was nice enough to take on most of the non-liquid assets as part of his share.”

Iruka looked down. “It’s only fair,” he protested. “I’m the one that didn’t think to stipulate cash only when they settled up.”

Teuchi waved that off with a ladle. “From what I understand, that would have just made you look suspicious in their eyes.”

“Besides,” Ayame added as she carried a stack of dirty bowls to the sink, where a short girl with long, curly brown hair was up to her arms in soapy water. “Shinobi acquiring a business get a small tax break on the purchase.” When they’d arrived at Ichiraku’s, Naruto had learned that business had increased so much since the invasion that Teuchi had to hire Ayame’s friend, Aldraia, to help part-time with the cleaning.

Iruka shrugged. “The law is supposed to make it easier for ninja to retire when they get too old for active duty or if they are permanently injured.”

“So you gave her a break on the rent if she named the store after you?” Naruto asked, getting back to his original question.

“No, no,” Iruka protested. “I just asked her to let it be our little secret. I didn’t think her rent was fair, but I didn’t want every business owner trying to renegotiate their lease. But I don’t think she understood me. Her store was originally named Pandora’s Secret and instead of leaving me out of it, she renamed it to Iruka’s Secret.” His shoulders slumped as Ayame doubled over in peals of laughter.

Naruto smiled as he looked away. He had just the picture to make a copy of for Hotako-san.

The former Team Eight met at Moritake’s the night before Naruto and Jiraiya were to depart. Surprisingly, Naruto had suggested the more up-scale restaurant, having bid goodbye to Ichiraku’s the day before. The owner was quiet when the genin entered, but he accompanied the server that brought their food, carrying a small bottle of sake. The bottle of high-quality rice wine contained just enough for four saucers and a toast to absent friends. One saucer was left, untouched, in front of an empty chair. Naruto was a little startled when the retired shinobi poured out the fourth serving, but his silent nod was all it took for him to make the connection.

Naruto barely noticed the taste.

The conversation over their food was awkward and stilted. There was a lot that needed to be said, but no one seemed to be able to find the words. Finally, Shino broke the silence that had descended.

“I find myself surprised at how uncomfortable this meeting has become,” he observed. “Prior to graduating from the Academy, I would not have considered this interaction strained, since it served little true purpose. However, since joining Team Eight, my standards for social interaction have risen accordingly.”

Naruto shrugged. “In other words, you’ve gotten used to dealing with us.”

“That is factually correct,” Shino allowed, “but insufficient. I have… raised my expectations for what would constitute a satisfactory interaction, and I find the current situation less than acceptable. This is especially true given the company in which I find myself.”

“We are usually… more comfortable… around each other,” Hinata agreed.

“It’s hard to find something to talk about,” Naruto admitted, “at least without bringing up…”

“Kurenai-sensei’s death,” Shino finished for him.

“Yeah,” Naruto replied as Hinata frowned a little.

Shino nodded. “I am of two minds regarding this issue. On the one hand, I feel privileged to have known her. On the other, I find her absence most disturbing. I expected to go through the normal grieving process and arrive at a nominal psychological equilibrium. Instead, I find myself snapping back to earlier stages at seemingly random times. It is most vexing.”

“I’m doing the same thing, Shino,” Hinata added quietly. “This… happened… after my mother died. I think it’s normal to be this way.”

“It doesn’t help that they are splitting us up,” Naruto groused.

“The Hokage’s reasoning is sound,” Shino replied. “Our development would best be served by individual instruction at this point.”

“Maybe I don’t care about that!” Naruto snarled. “I don’t want to follow some path like a puppet. I want to be packing up for another extended recon patrol. I want to look forward to Hinata’s deer skewers. I want to get bored and spar with you after we set up camp for the night. I want to meet new people that don’t… look at me. I want…”

“You want to sit around the fire and listen to one of Kurenai-sensei’s stories and try to pick out the hidden lesson,” Shino finished for him.

Naruto closed his eyes as they prickled with hot, un-shed tears. He just nodded, not trusting his voice.

The silence dragged on until Hinata softly cleared her throat. “M-maybe when you return from your trip, Naruto, we can request a patrol mission together. We would need practice working together again, right?”

“It would be wise if we were allowed an opportunity to incorporate any newly acquired skills into our teamwork,” Shino agreed. “And we will likely have stories of our individual tasks to share.”

Naruto opened his eyes and smiled at Hinata. “I think that’s a great idea.”

When told about Naruto’s new assignment, Gai-sensei had requested they meet briefly before Naruto left with the toad hermit. Naruto was used to getting up at the crack of dawn, and Jiraiya most decidedly was not – so it wasn’t really any imposition at all.

On the other hand, given the green-clad jonin’s eccentricities, Naruto was bracing himself for a battle royale to “test the fires of his youth before he left on his youthful training trip”.

The fact that those very words sprang to mind with no effort worried Naruto more than he cared to admit.

Instead of seeing Lee, or maybe even Tenten warming up, Naruto found Maito Gai alone in the clearing. His mood was unusually somber, which also put Naruto on edge.

“Thank you for coming,” Gai said in a formal-sounding tone that was at odds with his usual diction. “There is something I wish to discuss with you.”

Naruto nodded slowly.

“Immediately after the Chuunin examinations,” Gai began, “I asked your teacher about your training. I noticed you using a technique, Swamp of the Underworld, to great effect in your victory over Neji.”

Naruto felt rather uncomfortable now. He and Neji had not spoken since that confrontation at Ichiraku’s, but Hinata had hinted that her relations with her cousin had changed in a major way. That didn’t mean he was comfortable discussing the fight with the boy’s sensei – especially with how viciously it seemed to end.

But Gai continued on heedlessly. “It was not hard to realize you had learned that from Jiraiya-sama, but I was curious regarding any other techniques you might have acquired. Jiraiya is best known as Konoha’s Toad Summoner, and I was curious if he had taught you that as well.”

Naruto frowned in confusion.

“Since the exams were concluded, she confided in me that you had declined to sign the Toad Contract, due to concerns regarding how they might… interact… with your teammate, Aburame-san,” Gai continued. “Is this still a concern?”

Naruto nodded slowly. Jiraiya hadn’t brought it up again, but Naruto still felt it was a possible issue if he ever took missions with Shino again in the future.

“I see,” Gai replied, smiling a little. “That brings me to my current situation. Certain contracts have non-youthful requirements. For example, in Konoha, the Toads are well known for requiring a prospective summoner to share a drink with the Boss Toad, Gamabunta. This is quite the spectacle as you can imagine.”

Naruto’s mouth dropped open a little. For Maito Gai to consider it to be… He shuddered.

“I hold the Turtle Contract, as the Chief Summoner,” Gai continued, not noticing. “One of my youthful duties, as outlined in the contract, is to make sure that each generation includes at least one Chief Summoner with the ability to summon their leader. The turtles have legends of the end of the world, and the role they will play in it, so they must always be capable of coming here to prevent it.” The last was said with a more normal Gai gusto to it, snapping Naruto out of his shock.

“I have worked extensively with my youthful students,” Gai admitted sadly, “but none of them show a strong desire to master the summoning arts. Lee is, of course, dedicated to taijutsu and becoming a Genius of Hard Work™. Neji is focused on perfecting the Hyuuga Way of the Gentle Fist, and Tenten is walking the path of the marksman, and dedicating herself to weapons mastery. Therefore,” he concluded, “I will have to seek elsewhere to find a fitting Chief Summoner in the next generation of Shinobi.”

Naruto blinked.

“You have nearly equaled Lee’s fires of youth when it comes to your dedication to training,” Gai continued, “and you have the chakra reserves necessary to someday summon the Friend of All Children.” Gai abruptly held up his hand as Naruto opened his mouth to speak. “I have also made inquiries regarding the other issue. Most of the turtles are herbivores, and the ones that do eat insects do not do so in quite the… reflexive… way the toads do. There should not be an issue, and I myself have worked with Aburame shinobi in the past with no… un-youthful… issues.”

Naruto blinked. The normally overenthusiastic jonin had really thought everything through. He also realized the great honor he’d been offered, especially after Kurenai had made him apologize profusely to Jiraiya – even if Naruto wouldn’t change his mind. “I would be honored to sign the Turtle Contract, Gai-sensei. What other requirements should I be aware of?” he asked delicately.

He just hoped green leotards weren’t part of the deal.

Naruto practiced the seals in his mind as he waited for Jiraiya next to the gate. The sequence wasn’t particularly long for summoning. It was more the chakra flow and how it was modulated that determined who you pulled.

There was also a lot of memorization to connect chakra signatures with names and abilities. Such details were far too sensitive to be committed to paper, so Gai-sensei verbally gave him a list of the basic tier to memorize, and suggested he summon the higher ones individually and meet with each one. They could tell him about their immediate superiors, and this would also help fix them in his mind, as well as let him get used to their individual quirks. It seemed that almost every summon creature was an individual, no matter the contract. Just some contracts had more individual variation than others.

Of course, the Turtles were as individualistic as they could get – especially since they were, by nature, usually solitary. On the other hand, almost all of the snakes were cold-blooded jerks, at least according to Jiraiya.

It wasn’t too long before the white-haired shinobi ambled up to the gate, but he wasn’t alone. Shino stepped forward first, clasping Naruto’s hand firmly. “I will await your return,” was all he said. Naruto nodded.

Hinata was a little hesitant, but inside Naruto was proud of how she straightened up and squarely met his eyes. He thought about when Kurenai had written about his teammate and swallowed. Without a pause he stepped forward and hugged the girl, closing his eyes as he squeezed and pressed his face into the side of her neck. He inhaled a little, to remember the faint smell of sweat, kunai oil, and medicinal herbs coming from her jacket. “Stay strong,” he whispered into her ear, his lips unmoving.

She was frozen, seemingly in shock, but his words must have registered because she locked her arms around his shoulders with surprising force, almost squeezing the breath out of him. She held on for a moment before she released him, stepping back self-consciously.

Naruto smiled at them both as he stepped back as well. No more needed to be said.

“All right, Naruto,” Jiraiya demanded in a rough voice. Naruto was pretty sure he had a hangover. “We got a long way to go before it gets dark.”

Naruto nodded. With a last wave to the rest of Team Eight, he joined Jiraiya and slipped through the village gate.

24

Reunions and Revelations

Hinata looked up from the scroll she was reading. The muscles along her spine protested as she straightened up. She’d lost track of time again and she was only halfway through Tsunade-sama’s notes on chakra-stimulated nerve regeneration. Her new teacher was re-writing the book on what could and could not be done. With what she was reading now, many injuries thought to be career-ending could become mere inconveniences. She slowly stretched as she made a note of her place in the huge scroll.

The door opened and Shizune-senpai stuck her head in. “Still at it?” she asked. “You need to take a break, Hinata,” she chided in a kindly tone.

“My apologies,” Hinata said quickly. “I lost track of time. This work with regenerating nerve cells… it’s amazing!”

Shizune smiled. “Yes, a little too amazing, sometimes.”

“I’m sorry,” Hinata said quickly, “I don’t understand.”

Shizune motioned for Hinata to follow her, and spoke as they left the classroom. “These more advanced techniques are highly effective, but they require extremely good chakra control, not to mention large reserves to sustain them. Tsunade’s best work gave birth to techniques that only she and a handful of other people will ever be able to use. That’s great for special cases, but for the overall population the impact will be minimal.”

“I’ve heard her talk about the lack of qualified medic-nins,” Hinata replied.

“That’s part of it,” Shizune agreed. “There is also an element of… well, you know the saying about how it’s easier to destroy than to create?”

Hinata nodded.

“Well, it’s also a lot easier to destroy than to repair,” Shizune declared with a grimace. “Most shinobi can spend much less time training with their elemental affinity and see a lot more progress. If Tsunade had taken her natural chakra reserves and control, and spent all that time working on lightning jutsu, she could easily have humbled the best lightning users in Kumo. That’s one reason there aren’t more combat medic-nins… most active-duty shinobi concentrate on things that increase their combat effectiveness.”

Hinata frowned. “But if treatment is delayed until after the patient is evacuated, the prognosis is usually so much worse!”

“That’s true,” Shizune agreed, “which is why we’re starting this program. Tsunade thinks the improved treatment outcomes are worth the extra training required. But some would argue that having more combat-oriented ninja is the better strategy.”

Hinata thought about this for a moment as they made their way down the hall. “Who do you think is right?” she asked after a moment. One thing she admired about Shizune-senpai was that while she was utterly loyal to Tsunade, she wasn’t afraid to disagree with her mentor.

Shizune smiled. “I think that combat medics may not be needed as much in peace-time, or when there is only light skirmishing. Injuries may occur, but they are not as common, and highly skilled shinobi focused on offensive techniques can eliminate their enemies quickly enough to avoid injury. However, in war-time or extended operations in hostile terrain, mistakes are more common, and injuries will occur with greater frequency. Highly skilled shinobi can suffer mortal or career-ending injuries, but the availability of highly skilled, immediate medical care can often reverse that. I think, in the long run, Tsunade’s plan will save far more resources than it costs Konoha.”

Hinata nodded as she digested this train of thought, but Shizune wasn’t done.

“So,” she continued, “from a resource use perspective, it’s more effective when the need is most dire. But that doesn’t even address what Konoha stands for. You’ve heard the Third Hokage talk about the Will of Fire before, right?”

Hinata nodded. The old Hokage made a point of addressing each Academy class in their first year.

“That idea was really introduced to Konoha through the Senju clan, Tsunade-sama’s ancestors. They saw the village as being like one big family, and everyone should love the village they fight to protect. But that idea goes both ways. If we are like one family, then that means that we should value the lives of individual shinobi, no matter their skill. If that means reducing our overall firepower to prevent unneccesary deaths, then that it a price we should be willing to pay.”

Hinata thought about her own family for a moment. For once, it didn’t bring a sudden stab of shame. “I’m not sure everyone sees it that way,” she said quietly.

Shizune laughed. “They’re wrong, or at least the Hokage thinks they are wrong, and her opinion carries a lot more weight now. Of course, it helps that Sarutobi-sama is helping her manage the council.”

Hinata nodded. She hadn’t seen much of the former Hokage recently, but when he came in for his medical follow-ups he seemed much more relaxed than Hinata remembered. Despite losing an arm, the shadows under his eyes were lighter and he moved like a weight had been removed from his shoulders. Hinata was glad that his retirement seemed to be good for him, but she wondered just how heavy a burden it was to be Hokage. Tsunade herself seemed perpetually grumpy, and Hinata hoped that Naruto didn’t ever come to regret his life’s ambition.

The two kunoichi were quiet as they made their way out of the building. Shizune squinted at the bright afternoon light and fished a scrap of paper out of her sleeve. “Well, here is what we will need from the apothecary for next week. Can you pick it up while you are running errands?”

Hinata nodded. “Of course, Shizune-senpai.” This would also give her a chance to visit Kurenai-sensei’s house and water Naruto’s plants.

Shizune smiled. “Oh, and a question came up. There is another chuunin exam scheduled in a little over a month, not too long after Naruto is due to return. We are thinking about sending your team, but Tsunade reviewed everyone’s file and there is a potential complication. This exam is to be held in Kumogakure.”

Hinata froze in place for a moment. “I think that my father would raise some objections to that, even if I had my eyes sealed against theft.”

Shizune coughed. “Sealed? No, wait Hinata, let me start over. Normally, we wouldn’t send a team, let alone several, to a Kumo exam. They’re pretty suspicious of other villages, even in peace time, and you saw all too well how an exam can serve as cover for an invasion. We haven’t been invited in the past.”

Hinata nodded. Konoha was only just now repairing the last visible reminders of the Sound and Sand invasion.

“Well, this year it’s different. The Raikage himself has extended invitations to Konoha and Suna to send teams to their exam.” Shizune lowered her voice a little, eyeing the foot traffic passing them on the the street. “We think it’s because the invasion went so poorly.”

“Poorly?”

Shizune nodded. “With the forces at hand, and striking with surprise, Konoha still fared pretty well. Sarutobi-sama being forced to retire was the worst thing to happen, but with Tsunade’s assumption of the office, Konoha still has a strong Hokage. We think the Raikage is curious, especially since rumors state that some of the exam contestants played a key role, yet none of them were promoted.”

Hinata suppressed a sigh. She knew she wasn’t included in that number, but from things she had overheard, she knew the village council cancelled the examination while the Third was incapacitated. Otherwise, she was sure her teammates would have been promoted. While it did mean she would have another chance to test with them, she didn’t wish to benefit from their misfortune. What made it worse was that she was fairly certain her father had a hand in that injustice. She had the impression that very little happened on the council without his input. “So you think he wants to get a look at our shinobi to see if the rumors are true?”

Shizune nodded. “Yes, enough so that the Raikage is willing to personally guarantee the safety of our candidates travelling to and from the exam.” Shizune put her hand on Hinata’s shoulder. “He has specifically repudiated the clan he said was behind the attempt to kidnap you years ago.”

Hinata resisted the urge to wring her hands. That was quite a concession, she had to admit. If anything was attempted, the Raikage would suffer a huge loss of face. Wars were started over less. “What does Hokage-sama think?” she asked quietly.

“She thinks that, with those guarantees, this is an opportunity for Konoha to make an impression on potential allies, enemies, and clients.”

Hinata nodded. She remembered the Third Hokage explaining the true purpose behind the chuunin examinations before the preliminary round. “So she is accepting the Raikage’s invitation?” she asked.

Shizune nodded. “She is, but remember that participation in the exams is strictly voluntary. You do not have to go if you don’t want to,” she explained. “In fact, given your history, I would not blame you at all if you decided to wait for the next one.”

Hinata shook her head. “If Shino and Naruto-kun are ready for the exam, I will go with them,” she said quickly.

Shino found himself gaining new respect for his missing teammate’s mental fortitude. This happened, not coincidentally, every time he was attached to Team Gai for a mission.

While he had entered a cautious détente with Hyuuga Neji, and Tenten was a pleasure to train with, the third member of Team Gai, along with their sensei, was another matter entirely. While he could not deny Maito Gai’s proficiency in taijutsu and overall skill as a shinobi, the sheer amount of noise the man generated was ridiculous. When you added the third member of their team to the mix, it was even worse.

This, of course, made him question his own sanity when he found himself attending their so-called morning warm-up sessions. Maito Gai had requested that Tenten join him and Lee in the mornings, as he wanted to increase her training tempo. Tenten, who was not pleased with her showing in the previous chuunin examination, reluctantly agreed. She mentioned this to Shino after one of their practice spars, and added that he had been invited as well. Apparently, her jonin-sensei was aware of their training together and approved. Unfortunately, morning was when his mother Misato was usually available for training. While he had learned much of her signature two-kama preying mantis style, she still had more advanced techniques to teach him. When he explained this to Tenten, she accepted his decline without rancor, which he appreciated.

He apparently made an error of some sort when he mentioned this to his parents at dinner that evening. His father said nothing, but a minute wince was visible to Shino’s trained eye. His mother, however, quickly informed him that she would soon not be available for morning training. This was likely to be for a while, so he might as well attend the morning sessions. When Shino questioned the reasons for this unavailability, his parents’ reactions suggested that this was not a line of inquiry that should be pursued if he wished to avoid severe cognitive dissonance.

Not even the most stoic Aburame son wished to learn details regarding maternal fertility schedules. Hopefully, a younger sibling might provide a useful distratction at some point in the future.

Tenten seemed unusually pleased when he informed her of his schedule change, and that he would be able to join her after all. The reason for this became all too clear during the first session he attended. She did not want to be the only sane person there.

Maito Gai and Rock Lee’s proclivities were already known to Shino. What was less apparent was the degree to which Hinata had internalized those philosophies. When she mentioned sparring for a couple of hours, Shino thought that meant taking turns, with time to cool down between and analyze how each match had gone. Like sane people. He did not realize “sparring for a couple of hours” meant fighting continuously for one hundred and twenty minutes, going all out the entire time. The only time he saw either her or Lee even pause was when they were knocked down or half stunned from a glancing blow.

As he squared off with Tenten, he realized that she desperately wanted someone else there with more than a minimal degree of sanity. By the end of Gai-sensei’s ridiculously difficult cool down exercises, Shino began to understand how Naruto’s taijutsu had evolved so quickly.

By the time Naruto was comfortable pulling up one tail’s worth of chakra and manifesting a weak chakra cloak, Jiraiya was antsy to head back to Konoha. He’d been exchanging messages with Tsunade, so he was aware of the Raikage’s offer. It made him a little uneasy when a potential enemy offered something you wanted to do anyway.

Jiraiya could understand why the man might want to get a look at potential future competition. However, the leader of Kumogakure might not anticipate how this could blow up in his face. Other people, including Kumo’s favored clients, would be attending as well. Jiraiya had always been a little leery of his sensei’s vision of the chuunin exams as a proxy for outright warfare. But if ever there was a chance to put this theory to the test, it was now. A strong show of force by Konoha’s genin could make their enemies reconsider future plans. Jiriaya smiled when he remembered debriefing the Sand genin Temari after the invasion. She was convinced by that point that her father had been insane to even consider attacking Konoha. Fostering that belief in Kumo and their allies was, in his opinion, worth a little risk.

Now he and his apprentice were practicing one of Jiraiya’s specialties: how to travel quickly without anyone noticing. Any idiot can leap from tree to tree in order to cover ground quickly. That also means any idiot can detect them, or find the traces. There was a whole science dedicated to examining the scuff marks left on various kinds of bark by sandals. That sort of thing wasn’t Jiraiya’s specialty. He preferred infiltration and social engineering, but as a Konoha spymaster, he kept up on what his opposition might be up to.

Joining a suitably equipped merchant caravan under a well-rehearsed identity allowed you to avoid all sorts of attention. Picking the right one, in other words fairly prosperous and transporting perishable goods, meant you would be moving quickly by civilian standards with no one questioning why. It also gave him an excuse to drill Naruto on altering his distinctive appearance without resorting to Henge no Jutsu. He’d been pleased to note during the search for Tsunade that Naruto’s former sensei had at least trained her students in the basics. But this was one area where small mistakes could lead to grave consequences, so Jiraiya wasn’t about to pass up the opportunity to drill Naruto on his disguise skills.

When the time came to part ways from the caravan, Naruto also showed that Kurenai’s efforts to get him to think had not been wasted. He suggested that he leave behind a couple of over-charged shadow clones, disguised as himself and Jiraiya in their travelling identities. That way, if someone was tracking their movements, especially after the fact, they would have no way of knowing exactly when they did leave. At the rate the caravan was heading for Wave Country, even half a day would really throw off a potential tracker.

Jiraiya was a little dubious at first. He wasn’t sure the clones would last long enough to be worth it. He tried not to notice how smug Naruto was, a full twenty-four hours later, when he informed him that the clones had finally slipped away into the woods near the caravan’s campsite and dispelled themselves. Instead, Jiraiya just grunted and picked up the pace. Their six months was almost over, and back in Konoha there was a large bottle of sake with his name on it.

Tsunade squeezed the bridge of her nose as Hyuuga Hiashi left her office. The leader of the Hyuuga clan had not been pleased to learn of the invitation to Kumo’s chuunin exam, but in the end the Raikage’s guarantees had been enough to make him relent. In truth, he seemed unusually interested in that aspect, and her more suspicious side wondered if he was planning something underhanded.

She sighed and opened her bottom desk drawer. Of course he was planning something underhanded, that was a given. But she didn’t think he’d try anything aimed at making the Raikage publicly lose face. There was too much at stake, and the consequences if someone leaked the plot too severe. At the least, the Raikage would demand his life, and Tsunade would gladly give it to her fellow kage. She extracted the bottle of sake and took a sip, savoring the burn as she contemplated sending the arrogant clan leader to the gallows with a song in her heart. It wasn’t terribly professional, but the Hyuuga had made a habit of subtly reminding her of how unqualified she was to lead.

She was just glad Hiruzen’s retirement gave him the time to run interference for her with the council. Her lips twisted, even as she took another sip. It still felt strange, calling her old sensei by his given name, but he had insisted once she became Hokage. They were of equal rank now, and shared an understanding of how heavy that hat could really be. Retired or not, The Professor continued to teach.

She’d been more than happy to send her predecessor’s advisors, Homura and Koharu, off to their own retirements “with the gratitude of Konoha”. Most of their status derived from long service and being Hiruzen’s teammates back at the dawn of time. Danzo, however, was too well entrenched. He was allied with, or had dirt on, a goodly portion of the Village Council and was reputed to have contacts in the court of the Fire Daimyo. How much of that was rumor, she didn’t know, but it was enough to make her handle him with care.

Being a wandering alcoholic was so much easier than sorting out all this political crap.

Still, there were compensations. She now had the power to push through a comprehensive medic-nin training program. Hyuuga Hinata had the potential to be, dare she say it, a medical prodigy. Imagining the look on Hiashi’s face if she announced that got her through several very dull meetings.

The progress reports from Maito Gai and Aburame Shibi, along with Jiraiya’s messenger toads, were equally encouraging. Accepting the Raikage’s offer was a risk, but a calculated one. Tsunade took a third, smaller sip and sighed as she re-sealed the bottle and placed it back in the drawer. She paused and extracted a thick file folder. Yuuhi Kurenai submitted such detailed reports that she wondered if the woman wasn’t exhibiting some kind of compulsive behavior. She opened the folder to the piece of paper she’d left sticking out to mark her place and sighed. If the jonin were still alive today, Tsunade would be torn between leaving her with her team and reassigning her to take command of the Academy.

She was betting a lot on the former Team Eight, but she liked the odds.

There was a knock at the door and Tsunade looked up. The list of people allowed to do that by the chuunin guards was very small. “Come in,” she said.

Sarutobi Hiruzen walked in, trailed by his ever-present shadow. For a man who’d lost an arm and nearly died a few months ago, he was looking surprisingly healthy. He attributed it to enjoying his retirement, but Tsunade wasn’t taking any chances. That was why she’d agreed to Haku’s request to be assigned as the Sandaime’s assistant. Part of his unspoken orders was to monitor the old man’s health and make sure he was taking care of himself. Sentimentality aside, the village still needed his wisdom and political acumen. More, Tsunade needed him. She shuddered to think how many headaches the council would be without him acting as a buffer and advisor.

The old man had a faint smile on his face as he sat down in the chair beside her desk. Haku, as always, stood behind his right shoulder. Watching his back and protecting his weak side. Tsunade wondered if the ridiculously pretty young man realized he was doing it automatically. Hiruzen fumbled in his robes for a moment before frowning. The only argument she’d won with him was to get him to stop smoking. The risks after recovering from pneumonia, coupled with his age, were too great. It probably helped that his estranged son, Asuma, had also given up smoking cigarettes for some reason, and that gave the two something in common to complain about. Now that the father was no longer Hokage, the two would sometimes be seen together playing shogi. As someone that had lost her own family, Tsunade had bitter feelings toward anyone who squandered opportunities she no longer had. She pursed her lips. “You’re looking well,” she observed.

“I’m feeling well, all things considered,” the old man said. “I haven’t seriously coughed, aside from when I first wake up, in over two weeks.”

Tsunade nodded. “We can schedule another scan next week then. I’d like to make sure all the pulmonary scarring is gone. But you didn’t come here, voluntarily, to discuss your health.”

The Professor smiled. “No, I was wondering what you thought about the Raikage’s proposal.”

Tsunade sighed. “I don’t suppose I should even ask how you already know about that.”

“People talk, even in a Hidden Village,” he replied. “Hiashi did not look happy as he was leaving the tower, so I assume you are going ahead with this?”

“Hiashi is never happy,” Tsunade observed sourly. “But the Raikage’s guarantees seem solid. He really wants to get a look at my cards.”

Hiruzen nodded. “And not just him,” he added. “If Suna sends Baki’s team, his brother will get a chance to meet or at least observe two people of personal interest.”

Tsunade nodded. He hadn’t spelled it out in front of Haku, no matter how trustworthy the boy was. But she knew the Raikage’s adopted brother was the jinchuuriki of the eight-tails and mentor to the jinchuuriki of the two-tails. Rumor had it that Killer B both exerted an unusual degree of control over his bijuu and was extremely loyal to his brother, the Raikage. “I hadn’t considered that,” she admitted. “Do you think it will be a problem?”

“I think,” Hiruzen answered, “that there will still be more to gain than to lose. I don’t think we have any reason to be concerned about loyalties.”

“And Suna?” Tsunade pressed. If Konoha sent even one team, Suna likely would as well.

“That’s an interesting situation,” her predecessor observed with a small smile. “You may want to give Naruto some official recognition for asking Jiraiya to take a look at young Gaara’s seal. The difference after he repaired it is quite remarkable. I have even heard that young Gaara has decided to adopt Naruto’s grand ambition for his own.”

“He wants to become the Kazekage?” Tsunade asked, a little incredulous.

“As his father was before him,” Hiruzen reminded her. “His siblings are also making it publicly known that he was previously suffering from a damaged seal. There haven’t been any incidents since he returned, so people are slowly coming to accept this.”

Tsunade leaned back in her chair. “You’re awfully well informed,” she observed.

Hiruzen smiled. “People know I’m your advisor,” he said, “and they are used to me having the highest clearance. Please don’t take it as a slight directed toward you.”

“I’m not,” she assured him. “I just wonder how many others enjoy such access.”

“Homura and Koharu are officially, and unofficially, retired now,” Hiruzen said with a sigh. “They knew this was likely, since they never really got on well with you or Jiraiya. But they still supported either of you as the strongest candidates to lead Konoha.”

“I know, and I never doubted their patriotism,” Tsunade assured him. “But you haven’t included Shimura Danzo in that category.”

Hiruzen shook his head. “He has always done what he thought best, damn the consequences.” He paused. “That’s one reason I came to see you. I think participating in this chuunin examination is a good idea, but I don’t think you should leave the village unattended right now.”

“What do you mean?” she asked. “Wouldn’t that be a huge sign of disrespect if the village kage doesn’t attend?”

“Not as long as a Hokage attends,” he replied. “I could say I asked a personal favor since I know most of the genin involved, and missed the chance to see them advance.”

Tsunade mulled this over. “This has some possibilities,” she conceded. “I was worried what they might get up to while I was away.”

“Aside from that, you definitely don’t want to let the paperwork build up,” Hiruzen reminded her, earning him a very dirty look.

Naruto could barely restrain himself as he fidgeted next to Jiraiya. They stood in a slow-moving line queued up to a large gate. Part of him wanted to leap on top of that gate and shout that he was back. Two things stopped him from doing this.

One, people would think he was an idiot, and might attack him since he was dressed as a nondescript traveler. No sense giving the chuunin gate guards something to be nervous about. The second was that Jiraiya offered to handle the initial report and debriefing solo… If, and only if, Naruto could avoid breaking cover the rest of the way home. Just his luck the old degenerate would count such an action as a failure.

Naruto wasn’t dumb. He knew Jiraiya wanted to discuss some things privately with the Hokage. But he had things he’d rather do than cool his heels in the hallway while they did that. Hot showers, Ichiraku Ramen, and finding his friends were all on his list, in no particular order.

Besides, the stuff concealing his whisker-shaped birth marks was staring to itch!

So he fidgeted quietly, looking around like any young man visiting a hidden village for the first time might do. Finally, their turn came and Jiraiya shuffled closer to one of the chuunin manning the checkpoint and briefly showed him something Naruto couldn’t see. Whatever was concealed by Jiraiya’s bulk got the guard’s attention in a hurry. He wasn’t screaming, so Naruto assumed he hadn’t been flashed. What the guard did do was escort them through the gate with no more questions.

As they passed through, Naruto looked around again, relaxing a little. It was gratifying that he couldn’t see a single trace of the botched invasion anymore. Most of the major damage was repaired before he left, but now he couldn’t see anything to indicate the battle had even occurred. Even the repaired sections of wall had been weathered to match the rest. He smiled and cleared his throat.

“Yeah, kid, I heard you,” Jiraiya drawled lazily. “You managed not to foul it up too badly, so I guess you can go.”

Naruto made a hurt face. “So mean!” he huffed. “I guess Clothahump-sama was right about you after all…”

“What did that ambulatory soup bowl say-” Jiraiya’s howl of outrage was cut off when he realized he was addressing the rapidly receding backside of his apprentice. Instead, he chuckled and shook his head as he turned and strolled toward the Hokage’s tower.

Naruto scratched at his cheek as he weighed his options. He really need to stow his travelling pack and disguise, and his face itch was getting worse, so he decided to go home first. Then he could hit Ichiraku’s and keep an eye out for his team. If that didn’t work, he was sure he could ask at the Aburames’. He smiled when he remembered the first clan to openly support him. It made him wonder if his parents would have been anything like Shibi and Misato. His mother teased Shino a lot, but it was always playful, and anyone could see that she adored both him and her husband. Naruto couldn’t help but envy the taller boy, just a little bit. Fortunately, he could also sense that Shino was aware of just how lucky he was.

His mood was already a little melancholy by the time he reached the residential district, and the sight of the Yuuhi homestead added a pang of sorrow. He was quiet as he fished out his keys and let himself into the silent abode. The house was still, but not as dusty as he feared. He hoped Hinata was able to stay here if Tsunade gave her a break. Of course, that didn’t sound too likely from Jiraiya’s words. He was relieved to see Mr. Ukko and the other house plants were doing well, thriving even.

Naruto smiled as he unpacked and stowed his equipment. He knew that if he asked Hinata to look after his plants, they’d be fine. If it also got her used to coming around when she otherwise felt she would be intruding, all the better. Kurenai-sensei meant for this to be a haven for her as well.

He thought again about his sensei’s last letter as he ran a shower as hot as he could stand. Sensei’s words regarding Hinata’s feelings haunted him. She… loved him? Really? Every time he contemplated that, his stomach dropped towards his feet. It was such a… big thing. He had no idea how to even think about it. Did he love her back? He didn’t know. Couldn’t know. He’d never had anyone love him before, at least not that he was aware of. He knew Kurenai-sensei cared about him. She cared about all of her genin. Could you love more than one person? Or was it just really strong like? He loved Ichiraku’s ramen, but he wouldn’t trade someone’s life for it. Well, maybe Orochimaru’s.

Why the hell didn’t they teach people about this in the Academy? Why hadn’t Kurenai?

But even as he rinsed the shampoo away, ignoring the tears of frustration, he realized he already knew the answer. Normal kids, ones with parents and families, didn’t need to be taught this stuff. Their families taught them. He growled and smacked his head against the tiles in frustration. This all came back to the Kyuubi and the way he’d been isolated all his life. Well, he wasn’t going to let that get him down. He’d just have to get the answers himself.

After all, he’d kept Iruka’s Secret a secret, so his former instructor owed him one. Or two.

Cheering up at actually having a plan of action, Naruto finished rinsing off. He dried off and took great pleasure in dressing in a clean uniform. But as he exited the bedroom, he stopped. The front door was standing slightly open, and there was someone laying on the floor of the foyer. He edged cautiously forward and his heart gave a lurch when he realized it was Hinata.

In a flash, he was kneeling beside the fallen kunoichi and scooping her up. There was no sign of blood or injury. He had her deposited on the couch before she began to stir. He gently shook her shoulder, but flinched back when her eyes snapped open.

“N-Naruto-kun?” she gasped.

“Er, yeah. I’m back,” he announced lamely. “Jiraiya is reporting to the Hokage, so I came here for a shower before I went looking for everyone. Looks like you found me first!” he added. “Um. What happened though?”

Hinata’s face flushed red. “Oh. I was c-coming to water the plants when I thought I heard someone, so I activated…” her voice trailed off and if anything her face went even darker.

“Oh. Oh!” Naruto said, looking left and right, anywhere but at his mortified friend. “I noticed you did a really good job. Mr. Ukko has never looked better!” he babbled. “Want to get some ramen?” he added after a moment. “My treat? You can tell me what everyone has been up to…”

Hinata nodded quickly.

But before they left, Naruto had a small task. Hinata watched as he quickly prepared a pot of green tea and brought it to the study. Hinata trailed behind him, mystified, carrying a tray and a single cup at his request. They placed their burdens on the small table next to an overstuffed chair and a set of overflowing bookshelves.

Then Naruto knelt and with his palm on the floor, molded a shockingly immense amount of chakra. “Kuchiyose no Jutsu,” he called out as mist burst forth from under his hand. When the mist cleared, they were joined by a short, stooped figure.

“Clothahump?” Naruto asked. “I’d like you to meet Hyuuga Hinata, my friend and teammate.”

“Ah,” the old turtle rasped. “I have heard so much about you. It is a rare pleasure to finally make your acquaintance.”

Hinata bowed deeply, her face coloring again. “I am honored to meet you.”

“Such a polite young lady,” Clothahump murmured approvingly. He looked around, rheumy eyes peering thorough the enormous tortoiseshell spectacles. “Is this your home, Naruto?”

“It is,” Naruto confirmed. “We are back in Konoha now. This is the house that was left to me by Kurenai-sensei. When we discussed her… her love of books, you said you wished you could have read some of them. So I thought…”

Clothahump smiled, looking over at the bookshelves and the steaming pot of tea. “Bless you, my boy! This is a rare treat. I haven’t had any new reading material since Jon-Tom’s last visit.”

Naruto squirmed, a little uncomfortable at the praise. Then he glanced at Hinata, and her approving smile made him feel… smart. Like Kurenai-sensei used to do. He smiled back.

Teuchi was really happy to see Naruto had returned. So happy, in fact, that he left his broth unattended to come out from behind the counter and hug the embarrassed genin.

“It’s so good to see you back!” the ramen chef beamed. “I have a bunch of new ideas I want you to try out!” He coughed a little when Ayame elbowed him. “Once you’ve gotten settled in, of course,” he added.

Naruto laughed out loud. “You’re right. I’m so happy to be back here, you could serve mop water and I’d think it was great.” He paused. “You have no idea what passes for ramen in some of the places I’ve been,” he added with a shudder. “I even had it at this one place where they served it ice cold. I thought I was in hell.”

“That’s an abomination!” Teuchi agreed.

“Jiraiya called it Hiyashi Chuka,” Naruto added, “but I just called it nasty. They said it wasn’t supposed to be warm. I mean, what is the point? I don’t care if it’s hot outside, Ramen is supposed to be hot!”

“Some people will never understand,” Teuchi added in a solemn tone. “Sounds like you need a Naruto Protein Special, on the house!” he added.

“A Naruto Protein Special?” Naruto asked, his eyes going wide.

Ayame smiled. “Hinata had some suggestions a couple of months ago, so we incorporated them into a new dish.” She winked. “The name was her idea.”

Naruto turned toward his teammate. “Hinata?”

The Hyuuga was turning decidedly pink again, but her voice was steady. “Tsunade-sensei and Shizune-senpai had me reviewing the basics of nutritional theory,” she explained. “I realized that while you do need carbohydrates, you were not getting enough protein and other nutrients with your preferred diet. This is especially true when you are training. I explained my findings to Ayame and we came up with some extra toppings to address this, while also reducing the overall sodium content. Once we worked this out, we brought it to Shizune-senpai and she approved it as being a healthy meal-substitute for active-duty Konoha shinobi.”

“That means we get to put a little stamp next to it on the menu,” Ayame added. “And word got around. It costs a little more because of the ingredients, but our ninja customers are more than happy to pay a small premium. And civilians who want to eat healthier ramen have picked up on this as well. It’s one of our best-selling items now.”

Naruto turned back to Hinata, eyes wide and mouth opening and closing soundlessly.

“Naruto?” Hinata asked in a tremulous voice. “Is it all right that we named it after you?” All the confidence she’d exhibited when discussing the nutritional content of the new dish was gone. In fact, she looked almost on the verge of tears and Ayame was starting to scowl.

“All right?” Naruto asked. “All right? Hinata, you got a new type of ramen named in my honor! You absolutely rock!”

Hinata let out a sigh of relief, but added a sudden squeak when Naruto hugged her hard enough to lift her off her feet.

“Best. Homecoming. Ever,” he whispered in the shivering girl’s ear, still grinning like a loon.

Naruto was just finishing his Protein Special when Hinata sat up with a smile. A moment later, a familiar voice rang out.

“Naruto! You have returned! Have you been fanning the Flames of your Youth?”

Naruto slurped down the last of the broth. “Hai! Gai-sensei!” he called out after wiping his mouth. As he turned on the stool, Team Gai, along with Shino, stepped up to the counter.

“We can take a break now,” Maito Gai announced. “Five Naruto Protein Specials for my most excellent team and their excellent addition!” he boomed as he stepped up to the counter. The rest of his team shuffled after him at different speeds. Rock Lee was only half a step behind his sensei, and brimming with energy as usual. Neji, Tenten, and Shino all looked rather the worse for wear. Tenten let out a low moan as she finally sat down, and began kneading her right thigh muscles with one hand, wincing. Neji had bruises visible on his unbandaged arm and Shino leaned forward resting his elbows on the bar, back sagging in obvious exhaustion.

“Tough mission?” Naruto asked sympathetically.

“Tora,” the genin announced with a groan.

Naruto’s eyes bugged out. “The Fire Lady’s cat?” he asked incredulously. Sometimes it was a pain to retrieve the furball, but… “Seriously?”

“Gai-sensei comes up with the best ways to make a mission challenging!” Lee crowed proudly.

The look Tenten gave her teammate should have shaved years off his life.

Naruto ordered a miso ramen as he listened to their story. He shuddered several times at their collective tale of woe. Gai was silent, concentrating on his food as they talked. But when they finished, he spoke up. “Naruto,” he asked, “have you been keeping up with your taijutsu training while you were on your trip?”

Naruto nodded solemnly, glad that he’d anticipated this question. “I took Kabuto’s naginata away from him last week. He says that I will be ready to spar with The Four soon.”

Gai’s eyes widened for a moment, then he gave an enormous grin and a thumbs up. “You are truly exploding with youth! I look forward to you rejoining us in the mornings!”

Neji slumped as Hinata patted him sympathetically on the shoulder. Tenten groaned aloud and thumped her forehead against Shino’s arm.

Shino merely sighed and adjusted his sunglasses. “Physical discomfort aside, it is pleasant to see you safely returned from your training sabbatical.”

Naruto grinned. He’d missed Shino too.

Umino Iruka had already heard that Naruto had returned to Konoha. Konohamaru was bursting with the news from his grandfather that his “eternal rival” had finally returned to the village. But he himself was ambivalent about running into his former student. Of course, it would be great to see him again, and he wanted to hear all about his training trip. On the other hand, he was well aware that Naruto had kept quiet about Iruka’s embarrassing acquisition. The news hadn’t broken until a good three months after the boy had left. Someone noticed something on the tax receipts, and it was forwarded up the line, culminating in the single most embarrassing meeting with a Hokage of the young chuunin’s career.

Fortunately, Tsunade-sama possessed a sense of humor, and was willing to let him explain how the whole thing came about. Of course, it didn’t help that she was clearly struggling to keep a straight face by the time he finished. She just asked him to let her in on the action next time. But the damage was already done. Yugao wouldn’t even acknowledge his existence for the better part of a month, until Hayate-senpai explained that Iruka hadn’t really done anything wrong. Worse were the reactions of his former students. Yamanaka Ino found the whole thing hilarious, and never missed an opportunity to bring it up. Inuzuka Kiba had entirely the wrong idea, and worse, his older sister had taken to eyeing Iruka in a very unsettling manner.

But no matter how things turned out, Iruka had to admit that Naruto had kept his mouth shut. And as a former prankster, Iruka knew sitting on something so juicy meant that he owed Naruto a favor. And the most unpredictable ninja he knew just had six months to think about it.

Iruka knew nothing good could come of this.

So he was resigned to his fate when he saw Naruto waiting for him after classes had let out for the day. “Good to see you back, Naruto,” he said brightly. Obligations or not, the blond terror still held a place in his heart. Even if he was likely to end up defacing the Hokage monument before the day was out.

“Want to get some ramen?’ Naruto asked, “My treat?”

Iruka had faced death before on missions, so he suppressed the sudden spasm of fear with a stoicism borne of hard experience. “Sure… what’s the occasion?” he asked nonchalantly as they left the Academy grounds.

“Well, I’m back… and Kurenai-sensei said I shouldn’t take advantage of people’s generosity, so I figure I owe you more than a few bowls…”

Iruka frowned. He reached out and carefully laid a hand on Naruto’s shoulder. “You know, while what she said may be generally true, she was wrong.”

Naruto’s head snapped around in surprise. It took no small amount of will for Iruka not to react. “Yuuhi Kurenai was an excellent jonin,” he said slowly, “and a great sensei. But she had her own ideas about things, and I don’t think she was always right about everything. I wasn’t just being generous, Naruto. If I offered to buy you ramen, it was solely for the pleasure of your company.” He took a deep breath, noting Naruto’s expression growing troubled. “I’m not saying you should question everything she said, but you should keep an open mind and make your own decisions. All right?”

Naruto nodded as they continued walking. “I guess that’s part of why I wanted to talk to you,” he said after a moment. “I need some advice about something, sensei.”

Iruka was touched. Maybe this wouldn’t be so bad after all. “Naruto, I’m always here for you,” he said quietly.

Naruto nodded. “What is love? How do you know if you love someone? And what if one person loves someone that doesn’t love them back?”

Iruka stumbled. He realized that defacing the monument wouldn’t have been so bad after all.

Iruka picked at his pork ramen as he considered Naruto’s dilemma. Part of him couldn’t help being irritated at Yuuhi Kurenai and the problem she’d dropped in his lap. From what he’d gathered, she’d ‘spilled the beans’ to Naruto in some form of posthumous letter to be opened in case she died. He was familiar with the concept of ‘dead-mail’ – his own will contained a few sealed personal messages. One was even addressed to the young genin sitting next to him.

But Iruka wondered why she would leave such a message without laying any ground work for its comprehension. Maybe she’d planned to do so, but hadn’t the time. However, such an oversight didn’t really mesh with the unflinching realist that he remembered. It wasn’t that she was a pessimist so much as she didn’t believe things would work out in the end if she didn’t make them. What would make her break the news to an unprepared Naruto? Everyone else who knew of Hinata’s crush was willing to let it develop on its own schedule, to let her develop the courage to tell Naruto on her own.

Looking at it that way made Iruka wonder what she knew that he did not. He sighed. Waiting wasn’t going to make this any easier.

“Love is one of the strongest emotions people can feel,” he began in a low voice. “It happens when you care about someone so much that their well-being and happiness is more important to you than your own. It’s a powerful force in people’s lives. It can inspire someone to incredible heroics. It has also been the root of some of the most depraved evil ever committed.”

Iruka realized that he’d fallen into his lecturing cadence, but for once Naruto seemed totally focused on his words. “As for how you know, it comes down to the definition I gave you. If you had to make a decision that would make you miserable, but would lead to her happiness, would you do it?”

“I… I think so,” Naruto mumbled.

“You need to know, Naruto,” Iruka reminded him gently. “Say… her family was relocating to Suna. Would you tell her to go with them, or ask her to stay in Konoha, even if you knew she would miss them?”

“I don’t think she’d want to go with them,” Naruto replied. The certainty in his voice resounded with other things the chuunin had heard, or guessed. It was leading him to some unpleasant places.

“Assume she gets along with them better,” Iruka suggested, “and you know she would miss her sister horribly if they were parted.”

Naruto stared off into space, his miso ramen cooling. “Suna is an ally again, so it’s not likely we’d ever have to fight,” he said slowly. Iruka was impressed that he’d considered that for a hypothetical exercise. “I guess I could send a message to Gaara… ask him if he and his brother and sister could watch out for her,” he said slowly. Naruto’s face was slowly crumpling into a study in misery, and Iruka was ashamed to realize he was a little shocked. “I guess I’d tell her to go be with her family,” the boy concluded.

Iruka looked down at his food. He honestly hadn’t thought Naruto capable of that depth of feeling. Clearly his former student was growing up faster than he’d realized. “Well, it’s a good thing that’s not the case,” he reminded his friend. “Because if that’s true, then you do have some deep feelings for her. But there’s all kinds of love, Naruto.”

“There’s different kinds?” the genin asked, clearly dismayed.

Iruka nodded and took a bite of his cooling ramen. “Don’t you think a mother can love her child? Do you think that’s the same kind of love she feels for her husband?”

Naruto shook his head. “No, but this is more complicated than I thought.”

“That’s all right, Naruto,” Iruka assured him, “I think you’ve already done the hard part. You do remember the special seminar you attended with the other boys in your class?”

Naruto nodded, visibly shuddering.

“Good,” Iruka said quickly. He gave a small grin. “If I told the Hokage you’d forgotten, she would likely send you to refresher training… I wonder if that’s something she’d assign to her junior apprentice?”

Naruto’s face turned crimson and he shot Iruka a look of pure betrayal.

“All right,” Iruka replied calmly, “so you do know she’s a girl. Do you find her attractive?”

Naruto slowly nodded, still silent.

Iruka frowned. “What do you find most physically attractive about her? Take your time, and don’t be crude,” he warned.

Naruto’s face molded into a thoughtful frown. Finally he said, “I like the way she moves,” in little more than an embarrassed whisper.

“The way she moves?” Iruka asked.

“Yeah… she’s… when she walks, it’s like she’s barely touching the ground,” Naruto said, “and when we spar, she’s so graceful, it’s like she’s dancing and nothing can touch her… and then she lays a fingertip on you and BOOM, you’ve been Jyuuken-ed across the clearing.” His words sped up as he warmed to the topic and found his voice. “It’s like that with everything she does. She can stick hunks of deer on a skewer when she’s cooking, but when she does it she’s so delicate and so precise.” He lowered his voice. “Sometimes I think I could watch her all day long.”

Iruka swallowed. He’d started this conversation worried that Naruto had never really noticed Hinata. Shows how much he knew.

“But it’s not just physical,” Naruto continued. “It’s like… she’s graceful in everything. She doesn’t want her friends to fight, so she’s always playing peacemaker. She didn’t want me to be embarrassed when we met Shino’s parents, so she showed me exactly how to act. She doesn’t want anyone to hurt, so she’s always carrying around this balm she makes for when we train. And now she’s training to be a medic-nin, because she’s… she’s always trying to ease the path for others. She’s amazing,” he concluded.

There was silence as they both looked away, then ate some more of their dinner.

Finally, Iruka broke the silence. “Naruto?”

“Yes?”

“Feelings may change over time, but I think it’s safe to say that you love her.”

“Oh. Good. Thank you, sensei.”

Iruka nodded and patted his friend on the back. He couldn’t really call him a boy anymore, could he?

Naruto finished his ramen first, of course. He nodded to Iruka in a distracted manner before leaving enough money for both their meals and slipping away into the evening foot traffic.

Iruka jumped a little when Teuchi retrieved Naruto’s bowl for the wash. “I heard everything with the burners turned off,” he said, “Nice talk.”

Iruka shrugged, a little embarrassed in spite of himself.

“As the father of a very pretty girl,” Teuchi said with some authority, “I wish every boy she meets had someone give them the talk you just did.”

Iruka didn’t even try to stop the pleased flush that rose up his neck.

Shino wasn’t surprised to see his teammate lingering near the boundary of the Aburame complex. He knew that Naruto was not on the mission rotation since his return, ostensibly so he could refamiliarize himself with Konoha and any changes that may have occurred in his absence. It was also entirely possible that his new teacher was in need of prolonged downtime after a sustained interval of intensive instruction.

If that meant Naruto had the opportunity to greet former comrades while Jiraiya went on a bender, he was not one to judge. His mother was more than up to the task.

However, he had already spoken to Naruto at length the evening of his first day back. He had also witnessed a green blur that answered to the name “Naruto” during Gai’s morning training sessions. Those facts left him unsure as to why his teammate would seek him out at this point in time.

“Naruto,” he greeted his teammate.

“Hey Shino,” the blond replied in an unusually subdued tone. “Can we talk a minute?”

“I was assigned to team Ten today,” Shino said, “so I am not in immediate need of sustenance or rest.” His temporary teammates complained bitterly about Asuma becoming a ‘slave driver’ after the chuunin exams. Shino, having experienced the Madness of Gai, begged to differ.

Naruto nodded, but Shino doubted he had fully processed the words. Something of serious import seemed to be occupying his comrade’s mind.

“I… I’ve been doing some thinking,” Naruto began.

“An admirable occupation,” Shino remarked in what he hoped was an encouraging manner.

“About Hinata,” Naruto clarified and Shino went very still. “I… I’m pretty sure I like her.”

“Like?” Shino asked. “What is not to like? She is a skilled kunoichi with an extremely pleasant demeanor. Her training in medical ninjutsu will make her an extremely valuable comrade to have.”

“No, no,” Naruto interrupted, waving his hands, “Not like that. I mean, yes, she’s awesome, and I know she’s been working hard and-”

“Then how do you mean it?” Shino asked, interrupting him back.

“I… I’m pretty sure I love her,” Naruto said, looking down. Shino wondered if he was expecting some sort of approbation.

“I see. How do you intend to make use of this… revelation?”

“I’m not sure,” Naruto admitted, “I’m… you’re not mad?”

“Why would I be angry?” Shino asked.

“Well, I didn’t know if maybe you liked her too,” Naruto explained, shrugging his shoulders defensively.

“While I hold our teammate in high esteem, and value her contributions to the group as a whole, I am not given toward fruitless pursuits,” Shino replied.

“Fruitless?” Naruto asked, clearly confused.

“Are you aware of her feelings toward you?” Shino asked carefully.

Naruto blushed and nodded.

“I was aware of her preference from the start,” Shino said. “As such, while I valued the friendship that developed, I knew that desiring anything more from her would be a hopeless endeavor.”

“You knew?” Naruto asked.

“Naruto, I am fairly certain that everyone in our Academy class knew,” he clarified.

“You all knew?” Naruto gasped. “Why didn’t anyone tell me?”

“Most did not feel it was their place,” Shino explained. “Or they hoped Hinata would overcome her shyness enough to be able to tell you herself. Her feelings seemed to be fairly obvious, so many took it as proof that you were extremely clueless or simply did not care. I have since concluded it was more the former than the latter.”

Naruto sighed. “Shino, I grew up alone. I had to have Iruka-sensei explain to me, just now, how to tell if I liked her that way.”

Shino paused as he considered this. “That is not something I had fully realized the ramifications of, relevant to this situation. I can only offer that myself, like many others, hesitated to intervene because we feared to make an already uncomfortable situation worse.”

Naruto cocked his head. “You were worried about Hinata getting hurt? I guess I can understand that. So are we cool?”

Shino nodded, and felt the tension in his shoulders relax. He had not even registered tensing up during this conversation, which he found odd. “What are your plans going forward?” he asked.

“Well, I need to talk to Hinata,” Naruto said. “Things have been messed up long enough because no one was talking. That needs to stop.”

Shino nodded. “I think she will be pleased at this course of action.”

Tsunade leaned back in her chair as all of the active Jonin-sensei filed into the conference room. They were quiet, for the most part, so word had probably spread that this was going to be a serious meeting. When they were all in, the door shut. Tsunade stood as Jiraiya activated the room’s security seals.

“Jonin,” she began, “we have a rare opportunity before us. The Raikage has extended a personal invitation for Konoha to attend the Kumo chuunin exams in two weeks. His offer is phrased as an offer to foster good relations after our own examinations were disrupted, but we think his primary objective is first-hand observation of our new crop of genin.”

“Then why give him a peek?” Kakashi drawled, not looking up from his book. His legendary tardiness was in steep decline after the last chuunin exam, and Tsunade knew when to pick her battles. At least his bad habits weren’t interfering with training his team anymore. Her reports indicated the last Uchiha was also training on his own at an almost obsessive pace, but he wasn’t completely leaving his teammates in the dust anymore.

“Deterrence,” Tsunade replied with a smirk, “and marketing. Kumo’s best clients will be watching the finals. If our genin can make a strong showing, we can set the tone for interactions between Konoha and Kumo for the next decade.”

“Won’t the Raikage know this?” Asuma asked, frowning. “I’ve heard he’s kind of a musclehead, but I’ve never heard him described as stupid.”

“Our best psychological assessment,” Nara Shikaku replied, “indicates that’s he’s more comfortable with known threats. He’d rather hand us a potential advantage if it reduces the chance of us blindsiding him in the future.”

“That said,” Tsunade continued, “we need to make the most of this opportunity. I want every jonin-sensei to think long and hard. Do not nominate your team as a learning experience for them. Your teams did well in the last exam, but we want to make a show of strength. I only want teams that you honestly think can dominate the opposition.”

“My brats are ready,” Kakashi said. “We’d have to lock them up if they found out they weren’t going.”

“I think Team Asuma will sit this one out,” Sarutobi Asuma said. “They’re not all quite where I’d like them to be. I think Shikamaru is ready for the responsibility, but his tactical acumen won’t play that well for a crowd of civilians. Shinobi would see too much.”

Tsunade nodded, ignoring the small sigh of relief she heard from Shikaku’s direction.

Maito Gai was next. “Team Gai is more than ready to demonstrate the Power of Youth!”

Jiraiya cleared his throat, garnering the attention of many in the room. “And I will nominate Team Jir-… ah, the hell with it. I nominate Team 8.”

Tsunade ignored the shocked, but approving looks her old teammate was getting. “Very well. I’d like to inform you of another break from tradition. My predecessor, the Sandaime, has petitioned to be allowed to take my place at the Kumo examinations. After due consideration of the security and political ramifications, I have decided to approve this petition.”

She was surprised to see Asuma look shocked. Evidently, Hiruzen hadn’t even discussed this with his son, which impressed her a bit.

Jiraiya was waiting for them as Gai-sensei was finishing his latest version of cool-down exercises. He strode up as their morning Taijutsu practice ended. “I need to see all three of you,” the older man rumbled, then turned and left the training ground – clearly expecting them to follow.

Naruto didn’t say a word. He knew Jiraiya was not a morning person, and when circumstances forced it, better to not give the Toad Hermit any arguments. He led them to a small tea shop that was just opening. Naruto didn’t know if the owner would have objected to his presence if he’d come alone. Fortunately, he wasn’t the only person smart enough to not argue with a grumpy Jiraiya.

The first cup of hot tea didn’t seem to improve the older man’s mood very much, but he started talking anyway. “There’s a mission. There is a chuunin examination coming up in Kumo in two weeks. The Hokage thinks you’re ready. I think you’re ready. If you think you’re ready, we’ll go there and you’ll kick the crap out of everyone in your way and come back with three flak vests.” He coughed and took another long sip of his tea. “Are you up for it? I have to ask.”

Naruto and Shino turned toward Hinata, who was already nodding. They turned back and nodded as well.

“If you keep doing that in unison, I’m going to hurt you,” Jiraiya groused.

After they were dismissed, Naruto walked with Hinata to the Hokage’s tower. She was just finishing her six months of “indentured servitude” to the Hokage, so this trip to Kumo had come just in time. Her break from living in the Hyuuga compound was nearing its end, but she welcomed any excuse to postpone returning.

She glanced over at her teammate. Naruto was unusually quiet today. In fact, after his first day back, he’d been… rather pensive that she could see. She wondered what was bothering him. He’d seemed pleased about the Naruto Protein Special named in his honor. Had she done something wrong?

So lost in thought was the Hyuuga that she almost flinched away when she felt warm fingers wrap around her hand, interlacing with hers. She turned her head toward Naruto, who was looking away and blushing in a manner that she found absolutely adorable. “N-Naruto-kun?” she asked, damning the quaver in her voice.

“I, uh, I missed you, a lot, you know, when I was away,” Naruto said, ducking his head and looking down.

Hinata felt her heart hammering in her chest. She was amazed it wasn’t drowning out her own voice. “I missed you too,” she managed to say.

“I’m not really sure how to say this,” Naruto admitted, “but I really like you.”

“I like you too, Naruto,” she replied without thinking. How had she done that so easily? Did he really mean it like it sounded?

Naruto swallowed. “Would you like to, you know, date, I guess? I mean to say, would you like to be my, er, girlfriend?” Naruto was obviously struggling with his words, and the last one came out as little more than a whisper.

Hinata felt her eyes bulge as her face heated. She’d wondered, dreamed, even, about this happening. But now that it was happening, she felt her doubts multiply. Could she be a good girlfriend? What if her father found out? What if Naruto grew tired of her? Would she drag him down to her level?

But as she hesitated, Naruto looked up, and she found herself lost in the blue of his eyes. She saw someone she knew was just as alone as she was, and she knew she could deny him nothing. “Yes, I would,” she said softly.

Naruto pulled her into a hug, softer than his previous, more exuberant ones, and time seemed to stop. His warmth seemed to melt all her doubts away, so why did she feel like crying?